<?xml version="1.0" ?><posts>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="41430" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;In science fiction there are a lot of spiders or spider-like creatures depicted in space. In real life there have also been a lot of studies done on spiders in space. Has science fiction been influenced by the real life studies of spiders in space, or have the real life studies been influenced by the popularity of spiders in science fiction? Or are humans simply so fascinated with spiders that they have become common in science fiction and in real space studies coincidentally?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://t2.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:ANd9GcS2rSCk-hWxUpA9Kqc8UUmknQ35kM9SZjEn5SXyrmnLGs8VsH5hAUcBala5&quot; alt=&quot;Spiders in Space&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If science fiction was influenced by real life studies, then we should see more spiders in space in science fiction after real life studies commenced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If real life studies were influenced by science fiction, then we should be able to find allusions to science fiction spiders in documentation of real life studies.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="9" CreationDate="2013-10-08T21:19:07.603" FavoriteCount="1" Id="41428" LastActivityDate="2013-10-09T16:03:50.180" LastEditDate="2017-03-10T09:42:39.887" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerDisplayName="called2voyage" OwnerUserId="15467" PostTypeId="1" Score="11" Tags="&lt;science-fiction-genre&gt;&lt;space&gt;" Title="Why are there so many spiders in space?" ViewCount="591"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I would say that the real and fictional occurrence of spiders in space are mostly independant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spiders are very common in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cultural_depictions_of_spiders&quot;&gt;all kinds of fiction&lt;/a&gt;, going back to ancient legendary figures like Arachne and Anansi. I think your reference to a general fascination with spiders is spot on - note also that no other animal is so commonly the subject of phobia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, real world &lt;a href=&quot;http://chemistry.about.com/od/chemistryinthenews/a/spiders-in-space-skylab.htm&quot;&gt;experiments&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://chemistry.about.com/od/chemistryinthenews/a/spider-in-space-sts-107.htm&quot;&gt;spiders in space&lt;/a&gt; seem to be focused on the question how microgravity affects web building:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In addition to looking at gravitational biology in spiders, the examination of a spider's solution for producing a web with minimal gravity could have practical applications. On Earth, spiders can use gravity (their body weight) and/or manipulation of their spinnerettes to extrude several different types of silk. Even when the chemical composition of the silk is unchanged, the rate and mechanism used to pull the silk determines its mechanical properties. Similarly, altering methods of producing manmade fibers can result in materials that are more elastic, stronger, etc. Understanding the way a spider builds its web in space may help engineers build web-like structures for space stations and other aerospace architecture. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There does, however, also seem to be a &quot;cool factor&quot; involved:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The project was also intended to foster interest in space exploration and scientific research for the Australian students. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2013-10-09T16:03:50.180" Id="41430" LastActivityDate="2013-10-09T16:03:50.180" OwnerUserId="6079" ParentId="41428" PostTypeId="2" Score="11"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="64040" AnswerCount="5" Body="&lt;p&gt;In 'Once upon a time' series there is the myth of true love. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rumplestiltskin declares himself really interested to it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I'm a fan of true love, dearie. And more importantly... what it creates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;since it is the strongest magic of all:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Love... is the most powerful magic of all - the only magic I haven't been able to bottle. If you can bottle love... you can do anything. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it is not so clear to me how you can state what is a true love &lt;strong&gt;in an imaginary world like the one described in this tv show&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One could say that the &quot;classical fairytales couples&quot; are all creating true love, e.g.:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Snow White and Prince Charming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aurora and Philip&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Others come with proof but are not clearly stated: for instance, Rumplestiltskin and Belle should be in true love, since they are just a transposition of another classical couple (i.e., Beauty and the Beast).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Others are not in clear position:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;is Hook Emma's true love just because they found out to love each other? Is it sufficient to state that if a couple is in love?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what about Robin Hood vs. Marian vs. Regina? The Green fairy states that Regina could find true love in Robin Hood, but Marian was Robin's first true love. Can one have multiple true loves?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="6" CreationDate="2014-07-25T09:44:12.153" FavoriteCount="4" Id="63997" LastActivityDate="2014-07-26T13:18:48.253" LastEditDate="2014-07-26T13:18:48.253" LastEditorUserId="30784" OwnerUserId="30784" PostTypeId="1" Score="16" Tags="&lt;once-upon-a-time&gt;&lt;fairy-tales&gt;&lt;love&gt;" Title="What is the definition of true love?" ViewCount="2486"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I'm a bit disappointed no one has answered this from the perspective of the &lt;em&gt;Once Upon a Time&lt;/em&gt; yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;True love&quot; in Once Upon a Time is a quality, not a person. When Tinkerbell shows Regina the man with the lion tattoo, she claims to have found her &lt;em&gt;soul mate&lt;/em&gt;, not her true love. She does claim that she and her soul mate would share love (presumably true love).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;True love is shown to be that quality which one holds toward another person that leads the subject to trust, hope, or protect that person unconditionally. It is not clearly defined because it is almost the entire point of the show: true love is this mysterious quality that some have and others seek to discover the secret. It is a quality one learns by giving of themselves, and it cannot be bought or coerced.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="5" CreationDate="2014-07-25T20:33:12.857" Id="64040" LastActivityDate="2014-07-25T20:33:12.857" OwnerUserId="15467" ParentId="63997" PostTypeId="2" Score="8"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="204604" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;I'm asking on behalf of my wife who has remembered seeing this movie for a long time. Here are the key details she remembers about the movie:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was seen on TV around 1997 or before.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It involves a boy, a girl, and a baby who are dropped off at an older male relative's house.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The setting looked to be about 90s based on cars.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The house seemed abandoned when the kids arrived.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weird things started happening when the kids got inside: trap doors, fake walls, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remembered scenes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At some point, the kids got separated and the boy was looking for the girl and the baby. He went into a room where he could see the girl in a rocking chair with the baby, but when he walked up to her she was holding a snake and she started laughing like an insane person. He ran out of the room.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Later, the kids had found each other and entered a room with a large cake. The boy went to eat the cake, and the girl slapped the spoon out of his hand. When the cake hit the floor it burnt a hole in the floor. Then, you could see the older relative coming up through the floor laughing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The kids tried to run outside, but the world had changed and everything had reverted to Western times with a ghost town and abandoned wagons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My wife is aware of the resemblance of the main characters to the characters from &lt;em&gt;A Series of Unfortunate Events&lt;/em&gt;, but she doesn't think it is connected. At the very least, she is certain it was a movie and she doesn't think her dates could be off by more than a few years--so it couldn't have been seen later than about 2001.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2018-11-21T15:23:30.180" FavoriteCount="0" Id="199051" LastActivityDate="2019-02-03T20:41:24.097" LastEditDate="2018-11-21T16:33:58.127" LastEditorUserId="58193" OwnerUserId="15467" PostTypeId="1" Score="10" Tags="&lt;story-identification&gt;&lt;movie&gt;" Title="Late 90s movie with kids in a strange house, cake burns hole in the floor, trap doors, fake walls, etc" ViewCount="235"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;This is actually &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0514450/&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;The Tale of the Whispering Walls&lt;/a&gt;, an episode of &lt;em&gt;Are You Afraid of the Dark?&lt;/em&gt; from 1993.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;After a day in the park, babysitter Louise and two pre-teenagers get lost in the highway and stop at a mansion where things aren't what they seem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's all there. The kids come across:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The young babysitter sitting in a rocking chair with a swaddled baby which turns out to be a huge snake;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A table with some desserts, and when the boy tries to eat the banana split, the sister knocks it over with a spoon and it burns a hole through the floor;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;And an inn from the past with people in old-timey clothes. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's currently on Yotube &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e1SWI7botOk&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2019-02-03T06:57:22.397" Id="204604" LastActivityDate="2019-02-03T06:57:22.397" OwnerUserId="41950" ParentId="199051" PostTypeId="2" Score="10"/>
</posts>