<?xml version="1.0" ?><posts>
  <row AnswerCount="4" Body="&lt;p&gt;I know normally we strive to have a lot of experts (in the professional sense) in a SE community. Is this something we should be actively trying to change? Or are we hoping the &quot;if we build it, they will come&quot; approach will work eventually?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm basing my assumption that we have relatively few professional historians on my personal experience, and the previous two posts related to this fact:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://history.meta.stackexchange.com/questions/152/poll-how-many-among-the-users-are-professional-historians&quot;&gt;Poll - how many among the users are “professional” historians?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://history.meta.stackexchange.com/questions/568/will-the-historians-please-stand-up&quot;&gt;Will the historians please stand up?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2013-08-28T15:19:42.487" Id="731" LastActivityDate="2013-09-02T06:39:07.653" LastEditDate="2017-03-16T15:49:21.130" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="2732" PostTypeId="1" Score="5" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;site-evaluation&gt;" Title="Should we be doing something about the fact that relatively few of our users are professional historians?" ViewCount="166"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;We can promote the site among communities that have &quot;professional historians,&quot; whatever that means. I think, unlike say Stackoverflow where there are tons of professionals from private industry, the only people that would be considered &quot;professional historians&quot; in a similar sense are probably university professors that study and teach history. I'm sure there are exceptions to this rule, but that is the snap judgment I would make. Now, if you want to lower the bar, then we do have a decent amount of people that have BAs, and a few MAs, in history. Additionally, many of our best users have no formal training in the study of history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that said, it would be nice if we had a few professors around here that could bring their expertise to the table. Maybe think tank employees that have a specialization in a particular region of the world? Basically anyone that gets paid to study history. That would be nice.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2013-08-29T04:09:58.473" Id="732" LastActivityDate="2013-08-29T04:09:58.473" OwnerUserId="579" ParentId="731" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;IMO, conceptually it might be a good idea to engage in a &quot;marketing blitz&quot; to bring in professionals, but it might not work out so well practically: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Stackoverflow for example, &quot;there are tons of professionals from private industry,&quot; and so some sort of parity is achieved among the group at large. But on this site there will likely be a small minority of professionals and a vast majority of &quot;amateurs&quot;. What will likely happen is that the professionals will dominate all the discussions and the amateurs won't be able to do much but listen and ask questions, as if they were in class. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the question becomes who is the audience for this site and what is its purpose? Is the goal to give regular people a chance to hone their skills and interests in History and try their best to come up with a good answer? Or is it supposed to be a symposium for professionals, with other people essentially just listening in?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="13" CreationDate="2013-08-29T06:28:10.963" Id="733" LastActivityDate="2013-08-29T07:25:58.737" LastEditDate="2013-08-29T07:25:58.737" LastEditorDisplayName="user2590" OwnerDisplayName="user2590" ParentId="731" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The day that there is wide spread private or public hiring of historians is the day you might get to float this community on the excess volunteer labour of people skiving off work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the moment the size of the professional historian community, and the nature of the one serious job they can get, means that they're not going to preference &quot;community outreach&quot; here when research publication volume and quality are intensely strong drivers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(This question might be better suited over at academic.se  &quot;Why don't academics have copious free time for sharing-based-online cultures?&quot;)&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="5" CreationDate="2013-09-01T22:27:54.143" Id="734" LastActivityDate="2013-09-01T22:27:54.143" OwnerUserId="876" ParentId="731" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;By now I am resigned to the expectation that it will never happen. The question-and-answer engine that powers SE should be good enough to attract communities of experts around any topic. Good enough so that the ease of use in getting answers (experts have questions, too!) should outweigh, as a plus, the minus of &quot;donating free labor&quot;. To make this happen, SE would have to partner with one of several major academic institution or professional association. That, however, would be a stretch too far for the good people at SE, who are software developers and comfortable only in their own environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;History.SE will either languish and wither on the vine or continue as an amateur community for history re-enactors, aspiring writers of historical fiction, crossword puzzle solvers looking for a change in pace, et cetera[1]. That is not the worst thing that could happen. At one time, this Stackexchange looked in danger of being infiltrated by holocaust revisionists trying a soft-shoe approach, asking &quot;harmless and innocent questions&quot;. It was one of the reasons why I joined, to put a stop to this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that not every amateur history enthusiast is a friendly hobbyist. Many are conspiracists, racists, whackos, creeps. Keeping them out is a thankless and never-ending task but it needs to be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;[1]Not to mention an easy way for people interested only in Stackoverflow to quickly reach 101 rep, collect the &quot;association bonus&quot;, and bypass the new-user restrictions on SO.&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2013-09-02T06:32:27.497" Id="735" LastActivityDate="2013-09-02T06:39:07.653" LastEditDate="2013-09-02T06:39:07.653" LastEditorUserId="825" OwnerUserId="825" ParentId="731" PostTypeId="2" Score="5"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="801" AnswerCount="5" Body="&lt;p&gt;I am concerned that this site is devolving into question after question of bickering over perspectives. I think that this endless bickering is distracting us from focusing on improving the quality of questions and answers. In the past when a case was made for the continued existence of this site, it was argued that this site was fun and educational--a good place to learn different historical theories. But it is hard to find that anymore beneath the endless dialogue of what constitutes good history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't get me wrong. I am all for ensuring good academic methods are followed, but if someone makes a cogent argument that is well-sourced maybe we should leave well enough alone in some cases. I think the &lt;strong&gt;upvotes&lt;/strong&gt; will help the best answers rise to the top, and I think we should quit downvoting answers because we disagree with them--as long as the answer is clear and makes an argument from sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you think?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2013-10-17T13:49:34.890" Id="799" LastActivityDate="2013-10-23T05:22:08.650" OwnerUserId="2732" PostTypeId="1" Score="8" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;site-evaluation&gt;" Title="Concerns about the future utility of this site" ViewCount="183"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I don't think downvoting answers that you find are incorrect or unhelpful even though they makes argument from sources is the problem. The problem is long discussions in the comments based on peoples prejudice and religion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was suggested by someone (though I forgot who) that we make tighter rules for questions about history of religion, which seems quite common, and tend to create a lot of bickering. Perhaps we should simply not allow them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know questions about history of religion &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; be answered in a factual, rational and non-religious manner, but not only does a lot of the people asking these question seem to have an agenda, a lot of the answers, and especially the comments, seem to have one as well.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2013-10-17T15:07:30.720" Id="800" LastActivityDate="2013-10-17T15:07:30.720" OwnerUserId="63" ParentId="799" PostTypeId="2" Score="6"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Excellent question. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the answer isn't upvotes or downvotes, but a collective agreement about what we want. 
I think you've offered an excellent summary of what I'm looking for, &quot;this site was fun and educational--a good place to learn different historical theories.&quot; - a fun place to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without specific examples, I'm not sure what you mean by the &lt;em&gt;endless dialogue about what constitutes good history&lt;/em&gt;, but I'm going to agree with @LennartRegebro that the bickering is what drives me away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm on record as what I perceive to be the critical features that support the kind of community I want to participate in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Questions that can be answered&lt;/strong&gt;, not questions that lead to discussion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Questions with enough preliminary research that I can learn something.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comments and answers that are civil and helpful.  Emphasis on civil.  Really strong emphasis on civil.  Did I say civil? Cause I think civility is important. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On another SE we refer to @CodeGnome's law; decide what you want to do before you devote attention to automating it.  I suspect (I may be wrong) that we spend too much time worrying about upvotes and downvotes and other technological artifacts and not enough time clearly expressing what kind of a community we want.  If we have a goal, clearly articulated on the help site, then we have a variety of mechanisms to cultivate that goal. (including upvotes, downvotes, close votes, flags, and the option of first recourse - point the OP at the help site and explain why the question is pushing the boundaries).&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2013-10-17T19:05:09.947" Id="801" LastActivityDate="2013-10-17T19:05:09.947" OwnerUserId="1401" ParentId="799" PostTypeId="2" Score="8"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;There is a terrible, absolutely terrible Answer to a Question with a religious background right now, but since the Mods have censored several of my comments pointing out the outright falsehoods and misrepresented sources (but not the disingenuous replies by the Answerer to my comments), History.SE users are getting a distorted idea of the quality of the Answer and currently it stands at +1 vote instead of -10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that downvoting cannot fulfill its role of quality control. An unfortunate situation.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2013-10-19T04:45:45.030" Id="802" LastActivityDate="2013-10-19T04:45:45.030" OwnerUserId="825" ParentId="799" PostTypeId="2" Score="-1"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I would like to point out that voting and comments are complimentary. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no reason why an answer shouldn't be commented on bit (or even a lot) before settling into a pile of up and down votes. Especially as votes can't be changed easily due to game-theory adjustments made in the early days of the &lt;em&gt;stackoverflow&lt;/em&gt; stack exchange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think we comment because we are courteous decent bunch of people; with not so much sniper down-voting. I've been to some stack exchanges* with lots of voting and few comments. I didn't like them very much - be that  correlation or causation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know that seeing how the sausage is made can be disconcerting but as long as the comments don't leak into the answer, they aren't supposed to be authoritative anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not too worried about the quality of questions we have; though we probably don't advertise ourselves very well on the wider internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt; * I won't mention which. No you can't make me. No. Nooo! Not the rats! Anything but the rats! I give in... the sites were &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;redaction by NSA&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2013-10-21T07:07:33.313" Id="803" LastActivityDate="2013-10-21T07:07:33.313" OwnerUserId="2830" ParentId="799" PostTypeId="2" Score="4"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;What you call bickering may to others be important points of contention, at least until something is thrashed out, and/or perhaps reflected in an edit. Not everyone has the same concerns or interests as you do. And if you see something you think is inappropriate in the comments, flag it. The moderators generally do a very good job of cleaning things up &quot;after the smoke has cleared&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As LF mentioned, better a site with comments where people sort things out, than a site that has lots of votes and few comments. This site is officially &quot;not for discussion,&quot; and if there was a large community of professional historians here, swapping expert answers, there might be far fewer comments. As it is, very few of us here, admittedly, are real &quot;historians&quot;, but dilettantes and dabblers of various degrees - so the discussion and debate in comments is important and helpful to many of us. And as I mentioned, when things are cleared up, obsolete and impertinent comments can be deleted (yours) or flagged.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-10-23T05:10:20.133" Id="808" LastActivityDate="2013-10-23T05:22:08.650" LastEditDate="2013-10-23T05:22:08.650" LastEditorDisplayName="user2590" OwnerDisplayName="user2590" ParentId="799" PostTypeId="2" Score="1"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="864" AnswerCount="4" Body="&lt;p&gt;We all love &lt;a href=&quot;http://history.stackexchange.com&quot;&gt;History Stack Exchange&lt;/a&gt;, but there is a whole world of people out there who need answers to their questions and don't even know that this site exists. When they arrive from Google, what will their first impression be? Let's try to look at this site through the eyes of someone who's never seen it before, and see how we stack up against the rest of the 'Net.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://history.stackexchange.com/review/site-eval&quot;&gt;Site Self-Evaluation review queue&lt;/a&gt; is open and populated with 10 questions that were asked and answered in the last quarter. 
Run a few Google searches to see how easy they are to find and compare the answers we have with the information available on other sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rating the questions is only a part of the puzzle, though. Do you see a pattern of questions that should have been closed but are not? Questions or answers that could use an edit? Anything that's going really well? &lt;strong&gt;Post an answer below to share your thoughts&lt;/strong&gt; and discuss these questions and the site's health with your fellow users!&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2014-01-14T03:00:59.280" Id="857" LastActivityDate="2014-01-21T03:01:04.827" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:47:51.347" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="-1" PostTypeId="1" Score="2" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;site-evaluation&gt;" Title="Let's get critical: Jan 2014 Site Self-Evaluation" ViewCount="110"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Around the time of the last site eval I posted this question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://history.meta.stackexchange.com/questions/799/concerns-about-the-future-utility-of-this-site&quot;&gt;Concerns about the future utility of this site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, the site has improved 1000% since then. Great job, History.SE!&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2014-01-14T19:17:55.287" Id="858" LastActivityDate="2014-01-14T19:17:55.287" LastEditDate="2017-03-16T15:49:21.130" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="2732" ParentId="857" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="863" AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;I understand how this question &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; fit in the topic of Sports.SE (obviously):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://history.stackexchange.com/questions/11434/any-historical-sports-with-instant-win-moves&quot;&gt;https://history.stackexchange.com/questions/11434/any-historical-sports-with-instant-win-moves&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I don't understand is why it &lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt; to be migrated to sports? Is there a particular reason why it wasn't wanted here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Admittedly, I'm a little disappointed that my rep from my last couple of answers here got migrated away, but I know those are just the facts of life sometimes. I do understand the rationale for migrating the question on accents to some degree (though my answer still ended up remaining the accepted and most upvoted one on English.SE), but I don't exactly understand why this one needed to be migrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm content with just an explanation; I just want to understand the reasoning a little better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, another thing that probably makes me slightly personally biased on this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question on accents got migrated to English.SE, which I also happen to participate in; so it helped me. Sports.SE, on the other hand, I really have no interest in, and before today I hadn't created an account there. So personally it feels a bit like wasted rep.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2014-01-17T14:44:11.657" FavoriteCount="1" Id="861" LastActivityDate="2014-01-20T02:05:08.030" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:47:51.627" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="2732" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;questions&gt;&lt;specific-question&gt;&lt;migration&gt;" Title="Rationale for migration of the historical sports question" ViewCount="72"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;My thinking is that while a few History enthusiasts will also be knowledgeable enough to tackle a History of Sports question, many Sports enthusiasts will be knowledgeable enough to tackle a History of Sports question. The rationale for migrating the question is then to locate it on the site where the &lt;strong&gt;most knowledgeable answers&lt;/strong&gt; are likely to be available, and where the &lt;strong&gt;most knowledgeable voters&lt;/strong&gt; will be available to assess those answers submitted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br&gt;
Additionally, when a &lt;em&gt;Moderator Flag&lt;/em&gt; is raised to migrate a question &lt;strong&gt;without voting to close&lt;/strong&gt;, that is simply a suggestion for the moderators of the two sites to decide where they believe a question can be addressed by the most knowledgeable audience.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2014-01-19T00:19:22.280" Id="862" LastActivityDate="2014-01-19T21:30:38.770" LastEditDate="2014-01-19T21:30:38.770" LastEditorUserId="2283" OwnerUserId="2283" ParentId="861" PostTypeId="2" Score="4"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;If we consider (2014-01-20) the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.journalofsporthistory.org/abstracts-of-articles-in-upcoming-issues.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Abstracts of forthcoming articles in &lt;em&gt;Journal of Sport History&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; we can appreciate the nature of Sports History as a sub-discipline.  For example, from 40(3) 2013:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Parting Ways, Testing Waters: Norway’s Early Olympic Ventures  By John F. L. Ross&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Fidelity to fair play informs a Norwegian national passion for OL, the Olympic Games, that embraces popular engagement, organizational skill and athletic prowess. Yet dominance in ice-and-snow sport has siphoned attention from Norway’s initial Olympic engagements that, up to 1924, were summer-only. These reflected an uneasy push-pull dynamic shaped by internal politics, socio-cultural traditions and regional tensions. The nascent Olympic stage gave Norway, which split acrimoniously from Sweden in 1905, needed visibility in an age of ascendant nationalism. However, the elitist early-modern Olympic world also clashed with egalitarian impulses and indigenous traditions that revered idræt, the vigorous but non-competitive pursuit of athletic endeavor. A wider values conflict was telescoped into the Norwegian debate during formative decades, while tensions with Sweden formed a little-known political backdrop to the 1912 Stockholm games. Only from the 1930s could Norway make peace with the Olympic project and forge its Hegelian-like postwar synthesis in which sporting professionalism has eclipsed yet not eradicated traditional idræt  elements. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicates that sports history is like any topically focused area of historiography.  We are unlikely to be able to answer details of historical trivia regarding sport.  We are highly likely to be able to answer contextualised issues around sports, gender, society, politics, nation, class, emotionality, &quot;the person,&quot; the history of ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question ported to the sports site seemed to be a matter of trivia, and close to a list request, rather than a historically contextualised question.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2014-01-20T02:05:08.030" Id="863" LastActivityDate="2014-01-20T02:05:08.030" OwnerUserId="876" ParentId="861" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row AnswerCount="5" Body="&lt;p&gt;It seems that daily we receive several &quot;Where can I find references on ABC?&quot; questions. It seems that there is an unmet need amongst candidates for members of this community/stack for reading lists on broad general topics in history. SO, along the lines of various early **list* questions on Stack Overflow. I am wondering if it might be worthwhile to authorize, as a community, and as a community service, a small number of questions listing some well-founded history approachable by the general public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If so, I see a few issues that would have to be addressed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How to determine the number of such questions, while still ensuring that this category does not overwhelm the site. One suggestion might be to allow one such question each month/week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How to determine which question to open each  as above? And who gets the final call.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any thoughts on the merits of the idea, and on how it could be monitored and (if necessary) policed are welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="10" CreationDate="2016-06-08T02:32:20.583" Id="3342" LastActivityDate="2016-06-15T21:08:38.467" LastEditDate="2016-06-08T20:44:45.887" LastEditorUserId="2283" OwnerUserId="2283" PostTypeId="1" Score="4" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;" Title="Should we authorize a select list of &quot;Reference&quot; questions" ViewCount="175"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Building on Mark C. Wallace's answer, maybe we should have questions for some overarching categories that we decide in advance. The canonical answer can then be further subdivided as necessary. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Question 1:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Resources for Time Periods&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Note: Answer categories can be further subdivided by region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Answer:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neolithic
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neolithic Ireland&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bronze Age&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Medieval
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Early Middle Ages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Renaissance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Question 2:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Resources for Specific Individuals&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Answer:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Philosophers
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plato&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scientists
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Einstein&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generals
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patton&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Question 3:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Resources for Specific Institutions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Answer:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;States
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;United Kingdom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Companies
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;East India Company&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Question 4:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Resources for Specific Events&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Answer:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Black Death&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Question 5:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Resources for Historiography&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Answer:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comparative history&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Question 6:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Resources for Archaeology&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Answer:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remote sensing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The subdivisions aren't really important--they can be edited over time and refined since they will be in the community wiki answer. What is important is defining the overarching categories (the bold examples) in advance.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2016-06-14T18:20:59.557" Id="3345" LastActivityDate="2016-06-14T18:20:59.557" OwnerUserId="2732" ParentId="3342" PostTypeId="2" Score="1"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="3363" AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;I had recently noticed that this SE site have a tag 'script'. I had proposed a SE site in area 51 named &lt;a href=&quot;http://area51.stackexchange.com/proposals/101170/s-for-script&quot;&gt;'S' for script'&lt;/a&gt;. Do this tag and and proposal match? please help if you know something.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2016-07-14T13:25:42.170" Id="3361" LastActivityDate="2016-07-15T14:11:45.443" OwnerUserId="19363" PostTypeId="1" Score="0" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;tags&gt;" Title="Do this tag and proposal match?" ViewCount="63"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;No, I don't believe that is a match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://history.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/script&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;script&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;script&lt;/a&gt; refers to, as T.E.D. said, &quot;the actual set of glyphs a language's writing system uses&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The phrase &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=%22ancient+scripts+and+scrolls+%22&amp;amp;ie=utf-8&amp;amp;oe=utf-8&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&quot;ancient scripts and scrolls&quot;&lt;/a&gt;, as you can see in the linked google results, is most often used to refer to script in the sense of an ancient manuscript, or document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't believe there is a match here. Now, T.E.D. is being cautious because we don't have a lot of information on the proposal, and there is a possibility I am wrong. I'm just telling you what I believe given the current information.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2016-07-15T14:11:45.443" Id="3363" LastActivityDate="2016-07-15T14:11:45.443" OwnerUserId="2732" ParentId="3361" PostTypeId="2" Score="0"/>
  <row AnswerCount="4" Body="&lt;p&gt;H:SE currently has a list of on topic/off topic advice in &lt;a href=&quot;https://history.stackexchange.com/help/on-topic&quot;&gt;ask&lt;/a&gt;. (Curiously the &quot;what not to ask here&quot; is under the heading &quot;What topics can I ask about?&quot; rather than the &quot;What topics should I not ask about?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current list is:
    It is not about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    Genealogy
    Asking for reference material
    Questions answered by a simple Google search or to be found in a Wikipedia page
    Predicting the future based on historical trends
    Mythology
    General (non-human) Prehistory
    Conspiracy Theories or Pseudo-science
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd like to add one more item&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Denialism&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Denialism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically of course I'm referring to Holocaust Denialism.  Wikipedia defines Holocaust Denalism as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Scholars use the term &quot;denial&quot; to describe the views and methodology of Holocaust deniers in order to distinguish them from legitimate historical revisionists, who challenge orthodox interpretations of history using established historical methodologies.[5] Holocaust deniers generally do not accept the term denial as an appropriate description of their activities, and use the term revisionism instead.[6] The methodologies of Holocaust deniers are often based on a predetermined conclusion that ignores overwhelming historical evidence to the contrary.[7] &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Holocaust_denial&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That pretty well summarizes the distinction I'm trying to make.  I'm happy to discuss challenges to historical orthodoxies &lt;em&gt;based on historical methodologies&lt;/em&gt;, but I don't want to engage in discussion/debate with those who are arguing from a predetermined conclusion.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that community moderation is sufficient to resolve any ambiguity.  I'm more comfortable with a downvote/closevote if I can point to a clearly documented community standard that we don't want to engage denialists.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="8" CreationDate="2016-07-26T19:22:17.153" FavoriteCount="1" Id="3364" LastActivityDate="2016-09-21T15:00:42.450" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:47:51.603" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="1401" PostTypeId="1" Score="14" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;" Title="Can we add &quot;Denialism&quot; to the list of discouraged topics?" ViewCount="314"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Following up my comment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Ultimately what I guess I'm trying to say is &lt;strong&gt;no&lt;/strong&gt;. We shouldn't add it to the list of discouraged topics. If it is primarily opinion based or too broad or a duplicate, we should close it as such, otherwise if it is answerable we should allow it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Specifically of course I'm referring to Holocaust Denialism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see nothing about the Holocaust in particular that is a problem aside from the fact that it is a sensitive topic. Yes, we should make sure the topic is handled sensitively, and we should close poor questions, but good questions about the Holocaust should be on topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say (quoting Wikipedia):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The methodologies of Holocaust deniers are often based on a predetermined conclusion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such methodologies should not be accepted in the body of a question, but fortunately questions can be edited if there is anything salvageable. It may mean that no answer gets accepted, but that is a common problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I don't want to engage in discussion/debate with those who are arguing from a predetermined conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, discussion/debate is already not the proper form for this site anyway. Questions that encourage such should be edited to be less discussion-inciting. If the comments end up that way anyway, moderators can step in, as they should.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I'm more comfortable with a downvote/closevote if I can point to a clearly documented community standard that we don't want to engage denialists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Downvotes do not have to be based on standards, and questions should not necessarily be closed because of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Closevotes are a little different, but they are still ultimately based on one person's interpretation of the rules. I don't think we should set denialism in stone as a discouraged topic. If an otherwise good question gets closed just because of the point of view of the asker, then hopefully others will reopen.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="5" CreationDate="2016-07-27T12:46:10.700" Id="3365" LastActivityDate="2016-07-27T12:46:10.700" OwnerUserId="2732" ParentId="3364" PostTypeId="2" Score="8"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="3404" AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;NB: This is not referring to simply correcting misquoted text or typos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://history.stackexchange.com/questions/23436/are-there-any-battles-that-have-been-extensively-studied-across-the-world&quot;&gt;this question&lt;/a&gt; contains a paragraph quoted from &quot;The Classical Tradition&quot; (by Grafton, Anthony, Glenn W. Most, and Salvatore Settis) that listed a number of military academies including the École Polytechnique in Paris. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was recently edited because the editor believed that &quot;The Ecole Polytechnique does not aim anymore to train officers. The Ecole Spéciale Militaire de Saint Cyr is the one responsible for it.&quot; and the original text was replaced with the new institution. While this edit may genuinely be correcting a factual error in the quote, I don't believe that a quoted text should be edited in this manner as it means the quote is no longer a true representation of the source material. I rejected the edit for this reason but others accepted it and the edit went ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surely there is a better way to highlight/correct factual errors in quoted material than editing the quote itself?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2016-11-08T14:07:56.737" Id="3402" LastActivityDate="2016-11-08T16:22:16.077" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:47:51.627" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="6489" PostTypeId="1" Score="2" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;" Title="What's the correct way to handle factual errors in quotes?" ViewCount="64"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;You are correct. It is inappropriate to modify the quote in this case, especially without any note that the quote has been altered. I have restored the quote and inserted [&lt;em&gt;sic&lt;/em&gt;] after the name of the old academy (using the function of &lt;em&gt;sic&lt;/em&gt; to indicate a surprising assertion), and I added the editor's note on the current academy in small text after the quote.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2016-11-08T14:36:29.617" Id="3403" LastActivityDate="2016-11-08T14:36:29.617" OwnerUserId="2732" ParentId="3402" PostTypeId="2" Score="5"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="3449" AnswerCount="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;Currently we have two tags:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://history.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/byzantine-empire&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;byzantine-empire&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;byzantine-empire&lt;/a&gt; (52 questions tagged)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://history.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/eastern-roman-empire&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;eastern-roman-empire&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;eastern-roman-empire&lt;/a&gt; (3 questions tagged)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we know, Eastern Roman Empire and Byzantine Empire both refer to the same political entity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it doesn't make sense to keep them as distinct tags (Which is also annoying to ERE lovers like me who want to scream it's the Eastern Roman Empire, not the Byzantine Empire as Western Europe used to call them). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I propose that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We should keep Byzantine Empire tag as the main tag due to its more universal usage and popularity (As sad as it is). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We should map Eastern Roman Empire tag to Byzantine Empire tag as a synonym. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We should remove ERE tag from the existing three questions (If we have to, I don't know if synonymization will remove it automatically or not). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have created a synonym suggestion for the tag &lt;a href=&quot;https://history.stackexchange.com/tags/byzantine-empire/synonyms&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Please vote to have it approved. Thanks. &lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="7" CreationDate="2017-02-15T09:07:39.153" FavoriteCount="1" Id="3448" LastActivityDate="2017-02-16T19:26:30.057" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:47:51.627" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="15625" PostTypeId="1" Score="0" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;tags&gt;&lt;tag-synonyms&gt;" Title="Make Byzantium, Eastern Roman Empire again!" ViewCount="174"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I am of the opinion that we should generally not imply a particular interpretation of history through our tags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://history.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/eastern-roman-empire&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;eastern-roman-empire&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;eastern-roman-empire&lt;/a&gt; to refer to the Byzantine Empire after ca. 376 implies that it was the continuation of the Roman Empire. This is a matter of interpretation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, &lt;a href=&quot;https://history.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/empire-of-the-greeks&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;empire-of-the-greeks&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;empire-of-the-greeks&lt;/a&gt;, if it were a tag, would imply the interpretation that it was not a continuation of the Roman Empire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, &lt;a href=&quot;https://history.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/byzantine-empire&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;byzantine-empire&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;byzantine-empire&lt;/a&gt; does not imply either direction. It is a neutral tag that is well understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would say to merge &lt;a href=&quot;https://history.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/eastern-roman-empire&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;eastern-roman-empire&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;eastern-roman-empire&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&quot;https://history.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/byzantine-empire&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;byzantine-empire&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;byzantine-empire&lt;/a&gt;, except as T.E.D. pointed out there is a valid use case for the former, to indicate the Eastern portion prior to the diminution of the West.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2017-02-16T19:26:30.057" Id="3451" LastActivityDate="2017-02-16T19:26:30.057" OwnerUserId="2732" ParentId="3448" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row AnswerCount="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;There is currently a question on the front page that is on hold; it is explicitly an off-topic question according to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://history.stackexchange.com/help/on-topic&quot;&gt;What topics can I ask about here?&lt;/a&gt; page. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, before the question was put on hold, another user added an answer. It was a fairly good answer, and satisfied the original question. &lt;em&gt;On its merits as an answer alone&lt;/em&gt; I would have upvoted it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it's an answer to a question that should not have been asked. If the question were to be edited to be on-topic, the answer would no longer be a suitable answer for the question, and would not deserve an upvote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the right course of action?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2017-11-15T22:41:35.943" Id="3571" LastActivityDate="2017-11-17T16:14:44.657" OwnerUserId="17772" PostTypeId="1" Score="2" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;" Title="Should I upvote a good answer to an off-topic question?" ViewCount="72"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Scores carry over to other sites when questions and their associated answers are migrated. This suggests that it is perfectly acceptable to upvote an answer in the general case you outline.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2017-11-16T15:39:27.477" Id="3572" LastActivityDate="2017-11-16T15:39:27.477" OwnerUserId="2732" ParentId="3571" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
</posts>