<?xml version="1.0" ?><posts>
  <row AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;This site, as an education site with educators, is likely to end up soliciting many questions that come down to simple advice. (namely &lt;a href=&quot;https://cseducators.stackexchange.com/questions/1/what-language-should-be-first-used-to-introduce-coding&quot;&gt;What language should be first used to introduce coding?&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does this site plan to respond to these questions? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;edit&lt;/strong&gt;: Here is a link to the example questions: &lt;a href=&quot;https://area51.stackexchange.com/proposals/92460?phase=definition&quot;&gt;area51 definition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2017-05-23T14:25:22.687" Id="1" LastActivityDate="2017-05-23T19:22:47.250" OwnerUserId="12" PostTypeId="1" Score="7" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;" Title="Objectivity and this site" ViewCount="91"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Generally, yes, a lot of sites have to allow some subjectivity. However, you want the Q&amp;amp;A to be constructive and you want lists to be manageable. In your example, as Robert Cartaino pointed out, there are a lot of strongly held opinions and few means to limit the number of options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if you ask instead &quot;What factors of a language make it an ideal first language to introduce coding?&quot; that would be more objective and meaningful. It would empower the reader to figure out for themselves which language works best.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2017-05-23T14:44:15.830" Id="2" LastActivityDate="2017-05-23T14:44:15.830" OwnerUserId="7" ParentId="1" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row AnswerCount="8" Body="&lt;p&gt;When our site was created, we were given a &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.stackexchange.com/rooms/59174&quot;&gt;main chat room&lt;/a&gt;. Just like all the other sites, we were given the default name, which is the same name as our site name: &quot;Computer Science Educators&quot;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On many other sites, they get creative and think up a better name for their room, and we should do the same. Do you have any good ideas for room names? Suggest them here! The best one, as determined by voting, will be chosen when the activity on this question quiets down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was already discussed and a few suggested accumulated &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.stackexchange.com/rooms/59174/conversation/room-naming&quot;&gt;in chat&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2017-06-25T15:05:28.760" FavoriteCount="0" Id="173" LastActivityDate="2017-06-30T02:54:30.877" LastEditDate="2017-06-30T02:54:30.877" LastEditorUserId="58" OwnerUserId="58" PostTypeId="1" Score="10" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;status-completed&gt;&lt;chat&gt;" Title="Let's name our main room!" ViewCount="154"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I propose &quot;Hello, World!&quot; as it references the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/%22Hello,_World!%22_program&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;basic first program&lt;/a&gt; of many students and it sounds welcoming.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2017-06-28T13:29:04.323" Id="182" LastActivityDate="2017-06-28T13:29:04.323" OwnerUserId="7" ParentId="173" PostTypeId="2" Score="0"/>
</posts>