<?xml version="1.0" ?><posts>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="26585" AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;Next year for our high school reunion, my wife and I are considering the possibility of doing an apocalyptic-themed survivalist LARP at a camp in the middle of nowhere Colorado. This is something that all attendees would be interested in. Some of them have no RP experience whatsoever, some of them have RP experience but no LARP experience, and some of them may be experienced. What set ups would work with our group size (20-50) and the mixed level of experience? It doesn't have to be a formal system; it can even be something that you made up on the spot, but I don't have a lot of experience organizing LARP so I'm looking for advice.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2013-06-21T21:52:09.017" FavoriteCount="1" Id="26572" LastActivityDate="2013-06-25T16:28:23.750" OwnerUserId="7890" PostTypeId="1" Score="9" Tags="&lt;larp&gt;&lt;post-apocalyptic&gt;" Title="For a group of 20-50 people, what would be some apocalyptic survivalist LARP set ups that would work with the group size and skill level?" ViewCount="367"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;One idea that may fit your theme would be Humans Vs Zombies. It has a simple learning curve and is geared for mid sized groups like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing to consider with HvZ is each player is going to need either a Nerf gun or pairs of socks that they are willing to damage/lose. The game can be run without Nerf Guns with very little change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short and simple: The game revolves around group of Human Survivors trying to survive in a location. This becomes a challenge when Zombies start to overrun the surrounding areas. The game starts as Zombies start to attack the group(1 - 5 Zombies at start).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zombies can turn Humans into more Zombies, Guns and Socks/Marshmallows can stun Zombies, and the aim is to survive a period of time. Humans win if they last till the end, Zombies win by converting all Humans. Zombies can also die by starving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rules and concepts of the game are easily flexible to accommodate level and length of game play. Some games can be resolved in a day or two, while others last for weeks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More on the game can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;http://humansvszombies.org/&quot;&gt;http://humansvszombies.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also missions and other RP elements can be added to enhance the game. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want you could limit how much the guests know before arrival(just that the LARP in question involves Nerf guns and the rest will be explained). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then hold a meeting when they have all arrived. In this meeting start with a back story on how Zombies have overrun civilization, they are a group of survivors. During this have the seed Zombies brush close to create atmosphere. Following this have the leaders explain what is known about the Zombies and start the game. &lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2013-06-22T10:24:28.380" Id="26585" LastActivityDate="2013-06-22T11:15:31.207" LastEditDate="2013-06-22T11:15:31.207" LastEditorUserId="7701" OwnerUserId="7701" ParentId="26572" PostTypeId="2" Score="6"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;To add to RMDan's post, you can mix it up with a scavenger hunt as well. We played a game called 'Tribes' where there were four teams (red, blue, green, yellow) each with a base, a flag, team members... and a laundry list of BS they had to go get. There was no real attacking as no one had weapons, but the point of the scavenger hunt was to collect items for the tribes to use in order to capture the flag, in which they would get that tribe's items... as well as their flag. Some of the items were rope (to lasso an enemy), a lighter (for light), a key (to enter someone else's base), a map (obvious), a pen, water bottles, food, shield, foam floaty tubes, etc. It was like survivor, except without the voting and the 'me!me!me!' aspect. It lasted about two days and was a lot of fun. It was like trying to play paintball in a national forest without the paintball guns, and having to use your brains. Terrain permitting, this could be quite fun for large groups, as I did this with about 20 people.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2013-06-25T16:28:23.750" Id="26662" LastActivityDate="2013-06-25T16:28:23.750" OwnerUserId="8410" ParentId="26572" PostTypeId="2" Score="1"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="26699" AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;I understand that in terms of the core rules to run games&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;D&amp;amp;D 3.5 has: Dungeon Master's Guide + Player's Handbook + Bestiary(s)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pathfinder has: Core Rulebook + Bestiary(s).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pathfinder has a Game Mastery Guide, but I understand this contains extra information for writing/planning campaigns rather than running games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I run Pathfinder games and I'm considering buying a 3.5 DMG. With the equivalent of the Pathfinder DMG combined into the CR, do I already have all of that information? Is there much practical advice for GMs from the 3.5 material that would apply to GMing Pathfinder that would make it worth buying?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there any non-rule content (like practical advice for running games) in the DMG, that is missing from the Core Rulebook and GMG?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2013-06-26T11:46:44.787" Id="26685" LastActivityDate="2015-03-02T07:04:35.027" LastEditDate="2015-03-02T07:04:35.027" LastEditorUserId="1204" OwnerUserId="3819" PostTypeId="1" Score="7" Tags="&lt;pathfinder-1e&gt;&lt;dnd-3.5e&gt;&lt;books&gt;" Title="Does D&amp;D 3.5 DM material contain information applicable for Pathfinder GMs?" ViewCount="439"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;It's been a while since I've read the 3.5 material, but if I remember correctly it depends on how much you want to deviate from or experiment with the Pathfinder system. If you'll be doing a lot of custom/homebrew stuff with your adventures, then the D&amp;amp;D 3.5 material has some extra stuff that can help you add in extra rules and classes, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also depends on how much external structure you need when you're doing your own thing. Many people are happy modding the Pathfinder rules alone, or winging it, but if that is outside of your comfort zone the 3.5 material could help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit to elaborate on specifics:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as practical advice for GMs...I would say not really. GMing advice in manuals all tends to be about the same for me. I find you really learn more by running a few games and developing your own style. If you have any specific GMing questions, you can ask them on here and we'll give you our two cents from our experience. That is all we can give though; ultimately it is between you and your players to work out a style that suits your gameplay.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-06-26T12:26:47.660" Id="26687" LastActivityDate="2013-06-26T13:07:15.223" LastEditDate="2013-06-26T13:07:15.223" LastEditorUserId="7890" OwnerUserId="7890" ParentId="26685" PostTypeId="2" Score="6"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="26812" AnswerCount="8" Body="&lt;p&gt;This question has a specific and a general sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, if your game runs long enough, a party will be pretty much maxed out - reaching level caps, wielding top-level powers and abilities, dispatching the most fearsome enemies. There are monsters and encounters that can challenge even the toughest parties, mechanically speaking, but in terms of narrative, there's only so far you can go. Speaking D&amp;amp;D-specific for a moment, I've seen monster specs for some of the 4e gods. Once your party has killed a god (or several), there's not much to go &quot;up&quot; to from there. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, even if you can think up a tale that justifies a string of high-level encounters of that sort, with no more skills or abilities to gain the players will no longer be able to develop their characters beyond free-form RP, so gameplay might get a bit repetitive (my players love gaining and trying out new skills... with nothing new to gain, I fear they'll get bored).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the general question is: how do DMs deal with this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a more specific sense, I had an idea a little while ago for an encounter (D&amp;amp;D 4e) that basically ends with the party being &quot;retired&quot;. The basic gist is that the campaign ends with a choice: leave yourselves an exit, and know that this also leaves the chance for your foe to return someday, or make the ultimate sacrifice to defeat them permanently. It wouldn't be a death as such; the characters would still exist but would be trapped beyond the mortal realms. (If anyone's familiar with the Thomas Covenant books, think of the bit where he gets trapped inside the Arch of Time). As a DM, I'd love to have the characters show up as NPC demigod/guardian angel/Ghost Of Encounters Past thing, and I think my party know that I'm the sort to do something like that. Do you think a party is likely to take the latter option and end their characters' stories? &lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-07-02T13:13:11.367" FavoriteCount="3" Id="26809" LastActivityDate="2014-05-15T16:25:31.880" OwnerUserId="8599" PostTypeId="1" Score="20" Tags="&lt;gm-techniques&gt;&lt;system-agnostic&gt;&lt;campaign-development&gt;&lt;character-levels&gt;&lt;character-death&gt;" Title="&quot;Retiring&quot; a maxed-out party" ViewCount="1917"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;There is one question you have asked (though it is not your titular question) that I haven't seen addressed yet:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;how do DMs deal with [not being able to &quot;go up&quot; anymore]?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While, as others have pointed out, you don't have to continue on (and the retirement suggestions sound great), there are ways you &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; continue if you and your players wanted to. For example, you don't have to continue to &quot;work up&quot;. Now that your players are &quot;at the top&quot; they are (as you have pointed out) essentially gods or demigods themselves. Being in such a position is a tremendous responsibility. Now instead of &quot;working up&quot; you can have them &quot;work down&quot; into more responsibilities. As new powers in the land, there will be complex issues for them to deal with. This &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; slant your roleplay to being a little more political, but it could be fun and interesting depending on your group's preferences.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2013-07-02T15:49:40.077" Id="26819" LastActivityDate="2013-07-02T15:49:40.077" OwnerUserId="7890" ParentId="26809" PostTypeId="2" Score="8"/>
  <row Body="For questions about adapting games and/or play to be available to as many people as possible, especially for players or GMs with disabilities or special needs." CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-08-05T17:09:24.377" Id="27727" LastActivityDate="2019-04-18T21:49:22.280" LastEditDate="2019-04-18T21:49:22.280" LastEditorUserId="33569" OwnerUserId="7890" PostTypeId="4" Score="0"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="35865" AnswerCount="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;I noticed in &lt;em&gt;The Inner Sea World Guide&lt;/em&gt; that most core deities seem to have 5 domains associated with them, and every other deity has 4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm trying to make a few additions to the list for my campaign but didn't want to disrupt the balance too much.  My guess would be that I can just make one and give it the appropriate number of domains?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2014-04-04T11:49:21.103" Id="35859" LastActivityDate="2014-04-05T17:44:30.110" OwnerUserId="11514" PostTypeId="1" Score="4" Tags="&lt;pathfinder-1e&gt;" Title="Are there mechanics to make your own deities?" ViewCount="7150"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;If your goal is to make your created deities fit in with the existing deity mechanics and/or the existing Pathfinder deity style as much as possible, then I would highly recommend getting the &lt;a href=&quot;http://paizo.com/products/btpy85eh?Pathfinder-Chronicles-Gods-Magic&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gods and Magic&lt;/em&gt; book by Sean Reynolds&lt;/a&gt;. This is a Paizo campaign setting guide for the official Pathfinder setting, but the PDF is only $13 USD and contains a ton of detail on the existing deities in Pathfinder:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Creators of life, forgers of worlds, and rulers of reality—these are the gods and goddesses of the world. They have existed for eons. The countless worlds of the Great Beyond are their playgrounds and battlefields. Yet for all their vast power, it is not the gods of Golarion who shape nations and write history—this task falls instead to their greatest creations: the mortal races of the world. It is through their priests and paladins, their clerics and cultists that the gods make their will known in this world, be it for good or ill.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In Gods and Magic, you will learn not only of the core twenty deities of the Pathfinder Chronicles campaign setting, but of a multitude of other deities whose flocks, while smaller and more isolated, have just as much potential for greatness. Yet this book isn’t just for clerics—religion and faith are important factors in the lives of many, be they stalwart paladins, brave rangers, mysterious druids, or dedicated monks. Even those whose talents lie beyond the divine, such as the scholarly wizard or the god-fearing barbarian, find that faith has its advantages.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Within this 64-page book you will find:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Detailed descriptions of the core twenty deities of the Pathfinder Chronicles campaign setting, complete with symbols and full illustrations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Details on over 40 additional deities, including the gods of dwarves and elves, gnomes and halflings, giants and dragons, and more&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over 20 new spells associated with the most powerful religions, yet usable by both arcane and divine spellcasters&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dozens of new magic items keyed to the world’s religions, ranging from minor trinkets to powerful artifacts&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By comparison you should be able to construct your own with as much or as little detail necessary for your campaign.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2014-04-04T16:31:27.867" Id="35865" LastActivityDate="2014-04-04T16:31:27.867" OwnerUserId="7890" ParentId="35859" PostTypeId="2" Score="7"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="149640" AnswerCount="9" Body="&lt;p&gt;I'm a fairly new D&amp;amp;D player and as you can see from &lt;a href=&quot;https://rpg.stackexchange.com/questions/138230/how-can-i-develop-my-characters-background-when-i-know-nothing-of-the-games-lo&quot;&gt;one of my other questions&lt;/a&gt; I'm attempting to play as spoiler free a game as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this in mind I try and keep my reading about D&amp;amp;D to a minimum and tend to ask my DM (either 'in-game' or 'out-of-game') about things I'm not sure about, some of which would likely be well known by seasoned players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My concern is that by doing so I may be inadvertently meta-influencing* the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the example that I've been playing with in my mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;My level 5 Ranger wants to cast Locate Plant or Animal fairly
  regularly. For it she needs Bloodhound Fur which is a bit tricky to
  come by. I know, by reading the PHB, that a Component Pouch could work
  in the place of the Bloodhound Fur and also be useful for any other
  spells with a material component.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, given that I now want a Component Pouch, I set about in-game to find one. However, as a player, I'm not really sure where to start and this is where my problem lies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I imagine it's going to be a shop of some sort and I imagine, uninfluenced, 'Ye Old Magic Shop' as having a set inventory of items, let's say: Magic Hat, Magic Dice and Magic Shoes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If I ask my DM, out-of-game, where to get a Component Pouch I may now find that 'Ye Old Magic Shop' suddenly has one!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If I ask at 'The Blacksmiths', in-game, he may direct me to 'Ye Old Magic Shop' which suddenly has one!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If I let the DM know, either in-game or out-of-game, that my character seeks a given item I may suddenly find the Big Boss drops that very item instead of what he would have dropped had I not mentioned it!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my question is, how can I find out about the game world, such as situations like this, without meta-influencing it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;* I use the term meta-influencing to distinguish it from my character's in-game influence. I wouldn't be concerned, for example, with 'Ye Old Magic Shop' ordering in / making a Component Pouch for me as a result of my charactering showing an interest in it.&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="5" CreationDate="2019-06-10T13:23:00.813" FavoriteCount="3" Id="149629" LastActivityDate="2019-06-12T20:51:03.067" LastEditDate="2019-06-11T16:03:57.123" LastEditorUserId="42805" OwnerUserId="49360" PostTypeId="1" Score="32" Tags="&lt;dungeons-and-dragons&gt;&lt;metagaming&gt;" Title="How can I find out about the game world without meta-influencing it?" ViewCount="7817"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;For the example you give of securing items, the listed price for an item in the game materials gives you an idea of its relative abundance, unless the DM says otherwise. In the case of 5e, the &quot;Item Rarity&quot; is actually listed. So, until your DM says anything about it, you as the player should know that a Component Pouch is &quot;Standard&quot;, and thus you should not be surprised if your character finds it with ease. Just because your DM never mentioned them before doesn't mean they weren't there, your character just wasn't looking for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, if the DM is presenting you with exhaustive stock catalogs for each vendor, then I would suggest they are shooting themselves in the foot and doing too much work. You could talk to them about giving less specific detail so that it is less jarring when they have omitted some things that should be relatively abundant.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2019-06-11T17:32:11.497" Id="149733" LastActivityDate="2019-06-11T17:32:11.497" OwnerUserId="7890" ParentId="149629" PostTypeId="2" Score="4"/>
  <row AnswerCount="5" Body="&lt;p&gt;What are the advantages of using the Intimidate skill over using the Diplomacy skill for the same purpose?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some pretty obvious downsides to intimidation. The primary one is if it fails you may end up with a bunch of city guards on your tail. What about the advantages? Because from what I, in my limited knowledge, understand, intimidation is just the worse option, due to the potential repercussions being notably higher. Odds are I'm very wrong about that, which is why I asked.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="8" CreationDate="2019-08-18T00:48:53.937" Id="153738" LastActivityDate="2019-08-20T03:49:38.513" LastEditDate="2019-08-18T21:09:35.113" LastEditorUserId="33569" OwnerUserId="49714" PostTypeId="1" Score="4" Tags="&lt;pathfinder-1e&gt;&lt;skills&gt;&lt;social-stats&gt;" Title="What are the advantages of using the Intimidate skill over using the Diplomacy skill for the same purpose?" ViewCount="290"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Obviously this will vary from GM to GM, but as Diplomacy is supposed to represent negotiation using suitable etiquette and manners, a GM could decide that even a successful check involves some manner of compromise. You get what you want per RAW, but maybe in exchange for that you have to give something up. A good GM will tell you this before you make the check. When my players want to do a Diplomacy check I ask them how they plan to convince the NPC. That plan &lt;em&gt;may&lt;/em&gt; be purely verbal persuasion, but it could also involve promising to do something for the NPC or offering them a gift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, with a successful Intimidate check the only thing you give up is the attitude of the NPC. To be fair, there can be consequences to this, like getting reported to the authorities, as the rules say, but perhaps the reward of not having to give anything up to the NPC outweighs the risk.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2019-08-19T17:56:54.490" Id="153788" LastActivityDate="2019-08-19T17:56:54.490" OwnerUserId="7890" ParentId="153738" PostTypeId="2" Score="1"/>
</posts>