<?xml version="1.0" ?><posts>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="8124" AnswerCount="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;My 18ish month old baby loves to throw. She has several balls that she likes to toss around with me and her coordination with throwing is getting quite good. The problem is that she likes to throw other things too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I have gotten her to stop all out chucking things across the room, she still tosses them down onto the floor. She never does it out of anger. It's usually when she has completed a task with something for example, when she is done drinking her water, she tosses the mug onto the ground rather nonchalantly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same thing occurs with toys, when she has completed playing with a toy, she tosses it away. I have zero problem with her placing anything on the ground. She's rather good at helping mama and I clean up before she goes to bed, however I do mind the tossing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Has anyone had any success or does anyone know a method to  practice that will teach her to place things rather than throw? And also, does anyone know anyway that this could carry over between things she shouldn't throw (i.e. her mug) and things that are intended to be thrown (i.e. a ball)?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-05-29T00:33:00.820" FavoriteCount="2" Id="8117" LastActivityDate="2013-06-27T16:18:14.427" LastEditDate="2013-05-29T04:55:28.003" LastEditorUserId="2221" OwnerUserId="4348" PostTypeId="1" Score="5" Tags="&lt;toddler&gt;&lt;teaching&gt;&lt;habits&gt;" Title="How to deal with a toddler who has formed a habit of throwing things including food?" ViewCount="604"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;My son is almost 17 months old, and he is at the same stage. As others are saying this is something that, at least in my experience, just has to be learned with time and gentle encouragement. My son has gotten a lot better about throwing his cup when he's done drinking. Now he tries putting it down on the table or on his tray or in a cup holder.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-06-27T16:18:14.427" Id="8338" LastActivityDate="2013-06-27T16:18:14.427" OwnerUserId="4481" ParentId="8117" PostTypeId="2" Score="0"/>
  <row AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;My kid refuses to do his homework and is failing freshman biology, literature, US History and Art in high school.  I grounded him and he still won't do the work.  I've taken away as many privileges as I can.  What now?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-11-20T13:47:02.667" Id="10492" LastActivityDate="2013-11-20T20:58:19.597" LastEditDate="2013-11-20T20:58:19.597" LastEditorUserId="2058" OwnerUserId="2876" PostTypeId="1" Score="5" Tags="&lt;discipline&gt;&lt;teen&gt;&lt;motivation&gt;" Title="My teenager doesn't care about being grounded - what now?" ViewCount="3076"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;If your son is already failing all those courses and not doing homework, then it is probably too late for grounding to be effective. Sometimes I question the effectivity of grounding at all in teenagers, but that is beside the point here. Your son is becoming independent, and he has reasons (however ill-founded) for deciding to not do the work. Negative motivation is not going to overcome his reasons. Without more details it is difficult to determine what might be going on, but this is definitely something that you should sit down and have an open discussion about with him. You should let him know that he is free to express his thoughts and opinions on the matter, and that you are primarily interested in knowing why &lt;em&gt;he&lt;/em&gt; feels his school work has fallen by the wayside. Now that your son is getting older it is time to start treating him like an adult. He may not always be prepared to make the right decisions, but he needs to learn how to make decisions on his own and face the consequences when they arise. You can still provide him guidance at this stage, but you should always keep your communication with him open and calm. Speak to him like an adult.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2013-11-20T15:47:41.783" Id="10496" LastActivityDate="2013-11-20T15:47:41.783" OwnerUserId="4481" ParentId="10492" PostTypeId="2" Score="5"/>
  <row AnswerCount="6" Body="&lt;p&gt;We have a 4yo and a 1yo. The 4yo has been playing with Lego Duplo for a long time and it's safe for our 1yo because Duplo blocks are specifically made to be &quot;too large to eat.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's clear that the 4yo is ready to move on to &quot;real&quot; Lego. These pieces are smaller, and that's a problem because suddenly it's no longer safe to have Lego lying around in the home. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't think it's realistic to tell a 4yo to keep his Lego only on the dining table where the baby can't reach it. Lego is meant to be played on the floor, and no room is safe from both kids. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don't want to keep the baby out of the 4yo's room just because of the Lego (which would then only be allowed in that room). We feel it would be unreasonable to the 4yo to forbid Lego in the rest of the house, and unreasonable to the baby to forbid access to his brother's room. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there a better solution that I am not seeing?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-11-27T20:30:50.977" Id="10584" LastActivityDate="2014-01-17T09:33:55.837" OwnerUserId="109" PostTypeId="1" Score="6" Tags="&lt;infant&gt;&lt;pre-schooler&gt;&lt;safety&gt;&lt;toys&gt;" Title="How can we keep our infant safe from small Lego pieces?" ViewCount="4388"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Another possibility is building a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=lego+table&amp;amp;espv=210&amp;amp;es_sm=122&amp;amp;tbm=isch&amp;amp;tbo=u&amp;amp;source=univ&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ei=oeOdUpy2M6a2sAT_4IDYAg&amp;amp;ved=0CHgQsAQ&amp;amp;biw=1416&amp;amp;bih=865&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;lego table&lt;/a&gt;. They do sell these commercially, but if you are up to the task it wouldn't be that difficult to build your own to your specifications. This way you could make sure it was baby proof, and your four-year-old will most likely think it is awesome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would sand down a sheet of plywood and add four legs (to be sturdy enough that it won't topple easily) and make sure the legs are tall enough that the baby can't reach the edge of the table. Then I would buy some large, flat lego baseplates and glue these to the plywood with super glue. From there it is really an open concept that you can do whatever you want with. There are lots of neat ideas online. &lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2013-12-03T14:08:40.097" Id="10630" LastActivityDate="2013-12-03T14:08:40.097" OwnerUserId="4481" ParentId="10584" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;It's clear that children growing up with the internet the same way that my generation grew up with television: it's ubiquitous. Just like my parents worried that too much TV would harm me, it's not difficult to worry about my children being harmed by the 'net. This last week, dana boyd wrote a thoughtful &lt;a href=&quot;http://time.com/23031/danah-boyd-let-kids-run-wild-online/&quot;&gt;opinion piece&lt;/a&gt; for Time Magazine:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What makes the digital street safe is when teens and adults collectively agree to open their eyes and pay attention, communicate and collaboratively negotiate difficult situations. Teens need the freedom to wander the digital street, but they also need to know that caring adults are behind them and supporting them wherever they go. The first step is to turn off the tracking software. Then ask your kids what they're doing when they're online&amp;mdash;and why it’s so important to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is great advice and I wholeheartedly intend to follow it. My 10-year-old son certainly is growing up with the internet and we talk a lot about the things he does online. (Mostly he plays Minecraft and watches instructional videos...about Minecraft.) Checking in on his activities (by asking, not snooping) has been reassuring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, he managed to install a ton of adware on our family computer. (I suspect he followed some link claiming to make our computer run faster.) Thankfully, I caught the problem early. When I asked him about it the next day, he was evasive. He seemed relieved, actually, when I mentioned that I had turned on password protection for administrator tasks to prevent problems in the future. I suspect he knew he'd screwed up and was worried about how I'd react.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd like to believe that communication between children and parents will make his online interactions safer, but what can be done when communication breaks down? When shame prevents a child from coming to the parent for help, doesn't that make boyd's advice somewhat risky?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="6" CreationDate="2014-03-18T23:59:25.103" FavoriteCount="1" Id="11835" LastActivityDate="2016-03-23T15:38:18.017" LastEditDate="2014-03-19T19:37:09.690" LastEditorUserId="4521" OwnerUserId="4521" PostTypeId="1" Score="10" Tags="&lt;middle-childhood&gt;&lt;internet&gt;" Title="How can we help children learn to handle online freedom?" ViewCount="531"/>
  <row Body="&lt;h2&gt;How can we help children learn to handle free access to media?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing to realize is that this is not a new problem. The ubiquity of the Internet, its breadth of information, and its connectivity to such a vast userbase is new, but the base problem is not new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the earliest media of communication is storytelling. Still today we find ourselves questioning the best way to handle our child's access to stories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://parenting.stackexchange.com/questions/10493/the-school-has-assigned-reading-i-feel-is-inappropriate-for-my-son-to-read-how&quot;&gt;The school has assigned reading I feel is inappropriate for my son to read. How do I approach this problem with the school and with my son?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The invention of writing brought information out of the oral realm into something that could be preserved across time and space without having to be transmitted directly from the source of the information. As more people gained access to writing, our ancestors had to ask themselves&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How can we help children learn to handle access to reading and writing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today there are various approaches to this problem. We naturally teach our children to take care in what, how, and to whom they write. We concern ourselves with what our children read and have open discussions with them about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The invention of printing didn't really change any of this. All it did was increase the access to information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Television did seem to bring a new set of problems: it presented information in audio/visual form, it broadcast it over large distances, and it didn't immediately open up access for everyone to broadcast. The latter two are really nothing new. Access to information increased again, and like most new things the more powerful had greater control initially. Today we are still dealing with the repercussions of the audio/visual format:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://parenting.stackexchange.com/questions/3/at-what-age-should-a-child-be-introduced-to-the-television&quot;&gt;At what age should a child be introduced to the Television?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How is the Internet different?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet is everywhere and it is for everybody, but how is it &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; different? It is &lt;strong&gt;instantaneous&lt;/strong&gt;. Once given access to an unrestricted device connected to the Internet, our children can immediately gain access to whatever they want &lt;em&gt;and more&lt;/em&gt;. Even &lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; you restricted your home devices, Internet-connected devices are practically ubiquitous today. It is not difficult for your child to visit the neighbors and be on the Internet before you even know they've left the house (depending on their age).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What's the point?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't think the instantaneous nature of the Internet changes much except that it makes it all the more important that we establish open communication with our kids. If we form the habit of sharing what &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt; (parents and children) experience early on, then we will be prepared (with an understanding of our child's experience) to handle their issues and they will be prepared to share their issues when they occur because they will know we're ready to listen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Case 1: Gory Flash Game&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Open Communication Outcome 1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Child: I want to play some flash games.&lt;br&gt;
Parent: All right, what were you thinking of playing?&lt;br&gt;
Child: Oh, I was going to try out this fighting game on Freshdirt.&lt;br&gt;
Parent: I think that game's pretty gory.&lt;br&gt;
Child: Hm, I didn't know that. Maybe I'll try something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alternate ending:&lt;/em&gt;
Child: I saw that it might be a little gory, but I think it's just comic violence.&lt;br&gt;
Parent: Well, if you're sure it won't bother you, why don't we check it out together and see why it's so gory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If the game covers mature themes like &quot;Kill Your Boss&quot;, it might be a good time for a discussion about how that kind of thinking isn't healthy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Open Communication Outcome 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Child: I just clicked on a flash game, and it was pretty scary.&lt;br&gt;
Parent: Well, what happened?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Parent and Child can discuss what was disturbing. Parent will probably look at the game too to know more specifically what occurred.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Open Communication Outcome 3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parent: What did you do for fun today?&lt;br&gt;
Child: I played some Internet games.&lt;br&gt;
Parent: Did you find anything interesting?&lt;br&gt;
Child: Well, I did play this one game. It was kind of gory though.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Further discussion, as above.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on age, this much freedom does not have to be given. As this may be particularly relevant to the title question, see &quot;Easing in access&quot; section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Case 2: Pornography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parent: I've noticed you've been spending a lot of time in your room on the computer lately.&lt;br&gt;
Child: Well, I'm just surfing the web.&lt;br&gt;
Parent: With your door closed?&lt;br&gt;
Child: To be honest, I'm exploring a little bit of those things we talked about.&lt;br&gt;
Parent: There's a lot of scams and malware out there, and sometimes you may stumble into more than you bargained for. Can I give you some advice?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Parent explains to their satisfaction what the best practices regarding Internet porn are.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Case 3: Talking with Strangers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Child: I met somebody cool on the Internet.&lt;br&gt;
Parent: What do you talk about?&lt;br&gt;
...
Parent: Don't forget to be careful with how much information you give out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alternate ending:&lt;/em&gt;
Child: They want to meet me.
Parent: Well, I think we need to get to know them a little better first, and we should probably meet them together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Easing in access&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As your child gets older, there will naturally be less direct supervision of their online activity, but how exactly should this happen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In regards to mature content like violence, sex, and drugs, it is probably a good idea to have a safe list of sites to visit with your children. As they get older, you give them more freedom to visit the safe list with less direct supervision. For things not on the safe list, you may view them with them the first time or preview them in advance. By making the safe list a social device that you both refer to rather than a technical restriction, this shows that you trust them to make decisions about their own safety as they learn from you how to manage it. You may start out using the Internet with them at all times at a young age, then when they are older they may use it solo in the same room as you. Eventually, they graduate to using it on their own terms but with time restrictions, and then finally they start to learn how to make their own time management decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In regards to communication with strangers, you should be clear with your children early on about what kind of information is dangerous to share with people--and who you can share what with. When they start talking with people online, you should probably be with them at first. As they get older, you may ask to be introduced to their online friends but not have to be present for the whole conversation. If they ever want to meet someone in person, you should be clear that you want to go with them--at least at first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is this my opinion?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, but I tried to make it as grounded in the prevailing views of experts as I could, as far as I see it, and also open to many different applications. I am open to criticism and may choose to adopt views of others into my post as I see fit. Leave a comment if something sticks out to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I think by the age of 15 (at the latest) you should have your child ready for unlimited access to the Internet alone whether you like it or not, because they most likely will find their ways to get it no matter what the consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My answer assumes a knowledgeable parent--that is, a parent who knows about the Internet themselves and its risks and how to protect yourself. I don't think that is a problem with my post. A parent should become knowledgeable about anything before they set themselves as the point of contact for that issue with their child.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2014-03-24T20:54:47.020" Id="11908" LastActivityDate="2014-03-24T21:08:05.137" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:41:13.330" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="4481" ParentId="11835" PostTypeId="2" Score="1"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="22844" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;Our first child had no problems speaking quite clearly.
However, our second child who is 2 years old
has trouble pronouncing sounds like &quot;vee&quot; and &quot;fee&quot;.
For example, &quot;vessel&quot; becomes &quot;bessel&quot; and &quot;Sophia&quot; becomes &quot;So-bee-ia&quot;.
Will this problem naturally correct itself as she grows older?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know a friend who had a 4-year old who needed speech therapy,
though I do not know why he needed it and whether it was helpful.
How do we know if speech therapy is helpful or necessary?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2015-11-03T05:43:55.877" Id="22842" LastActivityDate="2016-02-11T09:16:31.700" LastEditDate="2015-11-03T14:25:58.733" LastEditorUserId="11210" OwnerUserId="4718" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;toddler&gt;&lt;language-development&gt;&lt;speech&gt;" Title="Should I be concerned that my 2 year-old cannot pronounce sounds like &quot;vee&quot; and &quot;fee&quot;?" ViewCount="325"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;This behavior is a normal part of development for a two-year-old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At 24 months a child should have about 70% accuracy of consonants, and by 36 months about 87% accuracy. Producing &quot;b&quot; instead of &quot;f&quot; is one example of a very common mistake a child of this age might make. Of course, if it seems like the accuracy is worse than 70%, or if the child does not seem to be improving in a few months, you may want to ask your pediatrician if speech therapy would be helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Details:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In technical terms, this kind of mistake is called producing a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stop_consonant&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;stop&lt;/a&gt; instead of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fricative_consonant&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;fricative&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the source paper, this is the top listed error for a 24 month old:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Target fricatives/affricates are produced as stops&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/pdf/10.3109/02699206.2013.766764&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Early phonological development: Creating an
assessment test - Carol Stoel-Gammon &amp;amp; A. Lynn Williams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2015-11-03T14:30:29.603" Id="22844" LastActivityDate="2015-11-03T14:45:44.510" LastEditDate="2015-11-03T14:45:44.510" LastEditorUserId="4481" OwnerUserId="4481" ParentId="22842" PostTypeId="2" Score="4"/>
  <row AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;I'm having a 4th birthday party for my daughter, and invited about 8 girls out of 40 or so kids from her Kindergarden class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I received a text from a girl's mum, saying that they lost the invitation and can she &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSVP&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;RSVP&lt;/a&gt; with me.  Problem is that her daughter was not invited in the first place, and they must have found out from someone else, and think that it's a 'whole class party'. My daughter doesn't want her daughter to be there as they do not really play together.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do we just invite them to make this whole thing go away, or stand our ground and let them know that they were not invited? If so, how to put it gently? &lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2016-08-11T14:16:45.987" FavoriteCount="1" Id="26792" LastActivityDate="2019-07-30T12:14:13.717" LastEditDate="2019-07-30T12:14:13.717" LastEditorUserId="30519" OwnerUserId="24045" PostTypeId="1" Score="4" Tags="&lt;pre-schooler&gt;&lt;communication&gt;&lt;birthday&gt;&lt;party&gt;&lt;etiquette&gt;" Title="How to react to a girl's mum inviting themselves to my daughter's party?" ViewCount="1231"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Just tell her simply:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We have planned to have a small party with my daughter's close friends, and so we did not invite the whole class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where to take it from there is up to you. If this girl and your daughter truly don't play together, the other mother should be reasonable enough to understand that her daughter is not a close friend. There may also be a cultural element here. Is it common for parents to bring treats to class for their child's birthday? If you plan to do so, you can add:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Your daughter is of course welcome to join the rest of the class in celebrating my daughter's birthday at school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That together with the above should make it clear that they are not invited to your daughter's personal birthday party, but if you don't have the second bit then you may wish to add one more statement to make it perfectly clear:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Your daughter was not invited because of the limited number of guests we're comfortable accommodating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should feel no obligation to invite anyone to a party which you host.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="10" CreationDate="2016-08-11T14:41:32.743" Id="26793" LastActivityDate="2016-08-11T14:41:32.743" OwnerUserId="4481" ParentId="26792" PostTypeId="2" Score="11"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="29358" AnswerCount="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;My 20 months old daughter is in very good shape and is growing very well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She has discovered how to play the music sound system and we are listening to the same record over and over again. In the course of these moments, sometimes she starts enjoying it very much to the point of laughing, running around the living room and, eventually, spinning around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This last thing is the one that impresses me the most: how come spinning around is this enjoyable for her? I have talked with other fellow parents and they also recognize this behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make my point clear, by spinning around I mean her rotating around her axis many, many times (say ten or so). Then, she tries to walk normally and the effect of the rotation makes her wobble, walk strangely and sometimes even fall down. To her fun, of course, because she laughs while doing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her spinning also includes us, the parents, from time to time: she will grab our hand and start running around us, so we also do rotate. To me this is hard because I get sick after the second turn, so I just stop myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I assume this is not dangerous, so my concern is: what is the reason for her spinning around? Is there any kind of feeling they get at this age that I cannot perceive as an adult?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2017-03-15T11:28:22.833" Id="29356" LastActivityDate="2019-03-07T16:51:13.057" OwnerUserId="14546" PostTypeId="1" Score="2" Tags="&lt;toddler&gt;&lt;behavior&gt;" Title="Why does my daughter spin around for fun?" ViewCount="9013"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Spinning actually produces a state of ecstasy. Dancing, in general, releases endorphins and serotonin, but spinning is particularly effective at this. Kids are not inhibited by social norms that might make them feel they look silly, so they have no restraints to prevent them from enjoying this form of mood-elevation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spinning also helps kids train their balance system, which is still developing until around fifteen years of age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing that prevents many adults from enjoying this is nausea. The precise causes are not known, but it is thought that nausea develops because the brain thinks that the blur of information means you ate something toxic. The inner ear (which aids in sensing balance) deteriorates with age, making adults more susceptible to these effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.york-biofeedback.co.uk/articles/sufi-meditation-and-positive-mental-health&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Sufi Meditation and Positive Mental Health - York Biofeedback&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://braindecoder.com/post/why-kids-love-getting-dizzy-1251740214&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Why Kids Love Getting Dizzy - Brain Decoder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2017-03-15T13:13:19.997" Id="29358" LastActivityDate="2017-03-15T13:13:19.997" OwnerUserId="4481" ParentId="29356" PostTypeId="2" Score="8"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="32204" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;My son's elementary school is doing a week with a different costume theme each day. I doubt that the theme is mandatory, as I can't imagine them requiring low income families to participate. That said, we would like to allow my son to dress up for each day's theme, but we have already spent a lot of money this month in preparation for Halloween. Unfortunately, the themes are specific enough that reusing our son's Halloween costume won't be an option. In fact, none of the days are &quot;spooky&quot;-themed or would allow for dressing up as a fictional character, so that makes it even harder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an example, one of the days is dress up as a historical person and another is dress up as a famous composer, but I would like the answers to be general and not focused on a particular theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I admit, I'm having a hard time imagining how I can avoid spending at least $20 on each day! What are some techniques that I can use to do costumes on a budget? The more I could do with things around the house, the better!&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2017-10-26T19:57:54.270" Id="32203" LastActivityDate="2017-10-26T20:42:05.267" OwnerUserId="4481" PostTypeId="1" Score="6" Tags="&lt;primary-schooler&gt;&lt;school&gt;&lt;money&gt;&lt;halloween&gt;&lt;usa&gt;" Title="How can I help my kindergartener dress up for costume week on a budget?" ViewCount="387"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The main thing is to be creative and 'declare it to be perfect'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example i dressed up my son around that age as a dinosaur. I took some old green sweatpants, filled 1 leg with paper, the other leg around his waist and that was his tail&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the same thing with a famous composer or a historical person. You could make the 'perfect Mozart wig' by just taking a few toilet paper rolls and glue them on a paper hat. (and you can go crazy here, put a piece of white paper on a box and draw piano keys )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As long as you can convince your son that he is then a perfect Mozart then he'll have fun and is far less bothered by the fact that you didn't pay x for the costume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main point is to find something that your kid can identify with that makes his costume his costume. For example a dinosaur needs a tail, Mozard needs a wig and maybe a piano, Benjamin franklin needs a kite. As long as your costume has that 1 key element, and you are actually having fun making it together with your kid, then i think the rest doesn't matter.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2017-10-26T20:36:54.167" Id="32204" LastActivityDate="2017-10-26T20:42:05.267" LastEditDate="2017-10-26T20:42:05.267" LastEditorUserId="14522" OwnerUserId="14522" ParentId="32203" PostTypeId="2" Score="14"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="32598" AnswerCount="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;Here is the dilemma. My wife, my brother, my five-year-old son, and I live about five hours from my parents, about four hours from my father-in-law and his SO, and about an hour from my mother-in-law. My sister-in-law lives close to us. My brother lives about eight hours away (six hours from my parents). My brother-in-law lives about four hours away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every Christmas and Thanksgiving, no matter what we tell our parents, they somehow expect all their kids, everyone's significant others, and grandson to all be present for one day within a week of the holiday. A further complication: my wife's grandparents are living. We like to see her dad's mother for Thanksgiving and Christmas, and her mom's parents for Christmas. We do see my wife's parents at those events--however, they still expect a separate day to themselves. I forgot to mention that my father-in-law lives in the exact opposite direction of my parents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though we've discussed it at previous holidays, we had to discuss again as this holiday season approached that all the driving is just too much. We have extended an open invitation to our whole family to be at our house for Thanksgiving Day, Christmas Eve, and Christmas Day. We said we will do no traveling Thanksgiving, except to my father-in-law's mother who cannot travel herself. We said for Christmas that we would not be traveling the 24-26, but that the other days of the break would be open to &lt;em&gt;requests&lt;/em&gt; and we would accommodate the requests that we were able to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone reluctantly agreed to the conditions for Thanksgiving, though my parents complained at length about the whole thing. My mother-in-law came to our house, my father-in-law saw us at his mother's house, and my parents opted to wait until Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that Christmas is approaching, however, all of our parents are suddenly insisting that it should be no trouble to us to see them on dates within one week of the holiday. My father-in-law is requesting the day that we informed him in advance we had already committed to my parents. He is trying to find a way for my sister-in-law to be present, but we have already discussed plans with her in advance and know that the only time our schedules match is the 24th. My father-in-law has thus far not accepted the invitation to come to our house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do we get across to our parents that it is simply unreasonable to expect everyone of their family members to be present at once for every holiday?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2017-12-05T15:29:39.433" Id="32576" LastActivityDate="2017-12-06T19:28:28.100" LastEditDate="2017-12-05T15:34:42.013" LastEditorUserId="4481" OwnerUserId="4481" PostTypeId="1" Score="14" Tags="&lt;travel&gt;&lt;grandparents&gt;&lt;arguments&gt;&lt;holidays&gt;&lt;christmas&gt;" Title="How do we convince parents that we can't all be there within one week of the holiday every year?" ViewCount="3020"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I don't fault your parents for wanting everyone to come visit.  Once kids get older and move out it becomes harder and harder to get everyone together, to have one more moment together as a family.  That desire to have some more of something that made them happy isn't wrong.  And the holidays are usually a good time for such things because many people get/take time off of work and it's expected that people will be gone.  So keep that in mind when talking about this with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To your point though, it becomes a huge burden on families to do so much travelling, especially in such a short time frame and in many different directions.  Growing up, both of my sets of grandparents lived on the opposite side of the country (USA, so it was about 2000 miles or a 2 day all-day drive to get there).  So we never got to see them terribly often, very rarely for holidays.  We just couldn't make it work with school and work schedules to find enough time to make it out and back around most major holidays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that my siblings and I are out of the house we are running into the same kinds of problems you describe.  We've all solved it in different ways (largely because of where we all live relative to my parents).  My sister had a schedule with my parents and her in-laws that they would spend Christmas alternating who they visited (something like my parents on odd numbered years, in-laws on even numbered years).  For me and my wife, her family will celebrate holidays a week or two early.  Then we get together with them for that and then we and her siblings can all spend the actual holiday either at in-laws or however we want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the way we make this all work is that we all (parents and siblings, or in the case of growing up, my parents and their siblings/parents) got together and talked it over to coordinate.  We brought up the fact that we just couldn't make travelling thousands of miles all the time feasible, economically, time-wise, etc.  Then we proposed a solution and coordinated.  Rather than having to have the conversation every year about if we were all going to be able to get together, etc. we established a schedule.  It was known that for any given year if we were going to all meet at mom and dad's for Christmas.  And, while I'm sure it wasn't the ideal my parents/grandparents wanted, it did set some expectations and assured them that they would get the together time they wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest key here was establishing expectations.  There was a lot less debate over &quot;I came for this holiday so you owe me this one&quot; or having to have the same conversation about when we were coming ad nauseam when everyone already knew what to expect.  No one was wondering about when the next time we would see each other would be.  We had already figured it out and it didn't need to be hashed out again and again.  (Occasionally plans would change for one reason or another and we would all get on Skype and figure it out.  But that was very rare, so it didn't break the trust that the general plan would hold.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So sit down with your spouse and come up with a tentative plan on how to coordinate this.  Once you are both on the same page, bring it to your respective families and make sure everyone has a clear expectation of when the next family holiday will be.  If you can make a recurring plan, great.  If you can only plan out the next 2 years (one with your family, the next with the in-laws, whatever makes sense for your family), great.  Discuss it once, make the plans and when someone brings up the topic, point back to the plan you already made.  Don't open it for debate again (unless absolutely necessary).  After a little while of going through this, your parents and in-laws will get used to it and should be able to handle it just fine.  Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2017-12-05T17:07:50.013" Id="32577" LastActivityDate="2017-12-05T17:07:50.013" OwnerUserId="4087" ParentId="32576" PostTypeId="2" Score="10"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;We create new dates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;We refuse to travel for Christmas, but are open to people visiting us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;We accept invitations for New Years, but warn people to not expect us to stay up past 10 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;We accept invitations for Ukranian Christmas (January 7)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;We accept invitations for St. Nicklaus's day (December 8)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Canada our Thanksgiving is in line with our climate:  we celebrate it on the 2nd Monday in October.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remberance Day, Nov 11, is a legal holiday here.  If it makes a long weekend, then it's open for visits too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One year we rented a house at a distance more or less equally inconvenient for everyone.  No one was happy with this.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2017-12-06T18:54:16.027" Id="32593" LastActivityDate="2017-12-06T18:54:16.027" OwnerUserId="30736" ParentId="32576" PostTypeId="2" Score="1"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;You don't convince them of anything.  You can't.  If they aren't being reasonable, you can't reason with them.  Stop trying, it clearly is not working.  You simply tell them what your plans are, and say that your travel plans are not up for discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2017-12-06T19:28:28.100" Id="32598" LastActivityDate="2017-12-06T19:28:28.100" OwnerUserId="9368" ParentId="32576" PostTypeId="2" Score="1"/>
  <row AnswerCount="10" Body="&lt;p&gt;My daughter, 13, has said she wants to be a boy. A little background: we moved to a new state a year and a half ago. In her new school, she felt isolated among her peers until she met a girl in art, and became good friends. She joined the drama club, and made  friends with some 8th graders. They joined “the diversity club”. This club is a LGBT club. The kids put on a play they wrote and starred in, which had homosexual connotations. “Romeo and Juliet”, but script  rewritten to include  2 females as the couple, for instance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My daughter got so wrapped up in it, that her life was as if she was copying the play. She’s no longer friends with the friend from art, but remains close with the 8th grade crowd. They all labeled themselves. One week, my daughter said she was gay, then, changed to bi, then onto pan. (I had to google that one). Now she is emphatic about being disgusted with her body and wants to be a boy. She wants to donate all the “girly” clothes she picked out last year, and tossed out all the makeup she bought a few months ago. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All her life, she was the classic girly girl. She had crushes on boys, and she and this boy were inseparable since first grade. She was sad when it came time to move away. When we settled here, she became sullen and angry, putting herself down. She now sees a therapist who she really likes. We’ve been working on her self esteem issues. She’s wanting us to call her “he” and by a male name. I can’t do that. She’s my daughter. She is female. Had we seen this coming, maybe I could come to accepting. But it happened out of the blue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the old her comes back-I got a makeup sample and she was interested in trying it, looked at me, then quickly put it down and said “ewww, makeup”—just a few months ago, she bought a bunch. She’s now wanting to wear boys clothes and talks of wearing a suit to her prom. She is very impressionable, and seems affected by viral YouTube videos about kids coming coming out to their mothers, and the mothers gleefully embrace with happy tears. She has told me when she’s 18, she’s having her breasts removed.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing seems normal to me anymore-in terms of how she always was-this new situation just doesn’t fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My gut tells me this is a phase.  I’m hoping it’s a phase. But with all I’m seeing in the media about this, I’m not sure. I love her; this is too much for me to process. I’m a stay at home mom; we were inseparable. I knew her. Until now.:(  She cut off all her beautiful hair, and wears boys shorts, baggy tee shirts, and bought this awful men’s deodorant spray. Please help me sort this out. I’m at my wits end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you think this is a phase? Is this common?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="5" CreationDate="2018-05-22T16:48:55.097" FavoriteCount="6" Id="34033" LastActivityDate="2019-08-28T02:56:47.650" LastEditDate="2018-06-05T20:59:39.297" LastEditorUserId="14742" OwnerUserId="32229" PostTypeId="1" Score="22" Tags="&lt;teen&gt;&lt;lgbtq&gt;" Title="My 13 year old daughter says she wants to be a boy. This is out of character for her. Is this a phase?" ViewCount="9322"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I'm appalled at the disconnect here from what the actual research says in regards to this issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a systematic literature review on the elevated risk of health issues among transgender and gender variant youth (&lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007%2Fs10935-018-0508-9&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Protective Factors Among Transgender and Gender Variant Youth: A Systematic Review by Socioecological Level&lt;/a&gt;), there were found some consistent protective factors. First of all, let me make clear that questioning one's gender, even if it doesn't result in a permanent identification as transgender, is a form of &lt;a href=&quot;https://ok2bme.ca/wp-content/uploads/Parenting_a_Gender_Variant_Child.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;gender variance&lt;/a&gt;. This means that the findings discussed in this literature review represent a form of consensus of research on how to handle youth like your teenager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This review covered articles spanning 1999 to 2014. The data analyzed pertains to youth aged 10 to 24 years. The paper notes first:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Transgender and gender variant (GV) youth experience elevated risk for poor health and academic outcomes &lt;strong&gt;due mainly to social experiences of stigma and discrimination&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;emphasis added&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, here are the protective factors uncovered by this study that mitigate the risks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Within these articles, 27 unique protective factors across four levels of the ecological model were identified as related to positive health and well-being. &lt;strong&gt;Self-esteem at the individual level, healthy relationships with parents and peers at the relationship-level, and gay-straight alliances at the community level emerged as protective factors across multiple studies&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;emphasis added&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The
  availability of transgender health and social services in schools and neighborhoods
  was cited as important for ﬁnding emotional support for and tangible assistance with
  legal and medical transitions &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I will note that medical transition is not something to undertake lightly. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nhs.uk/conditions/gender-dysphoria/treatment/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;NHS&lt;/a&gt; states:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Most treatments offered at this stage [children under 18 referred to specialists for gender dysphoria] are psychological, rather than medical or surgical. This is because the majority of children with suspected gender dysphoria don't have the condition once they reach puberty. Psychological support offers young people and their families a chance to discuss their thoughts and receive support to help them cope with the emotional distress of the condition, without rushing into more drastic treatments.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If your child has gender dysphoria and they've reached puberty, they could be treated with gonadotrophin-releasing hormone (GnRH) analogues. These are synthetic (man-made) hormones that suppress the hormones naturally produced by the body.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The effects of treatment with GnRH analogues are considered to be fully reversible, so treatment can usually be stopped at any time after a discussion between you, your child and your MDT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, there is a lot of misinformation out there. Here are the findings of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://whatweknow.inequality.cornell.edu/topics/lgbt-equality/what-does-the-scholarly-research-say-about-the-well-being-of-transgender-people/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Cornell University review&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The scholarly literature makes clear that gender transition is effective in treating gender dysphoria and can significantly improve the well-being of transgender individuals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Among the positive outcomes of gender transition and related medical treatments for transgender individuals are improved quality of life, greater relationship satisfaction, higher self-esteem and confidence, and reductions in anxiety, depression, suicidality, and substance use.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The positive impact of gender transition on transgender well-being has grown considerably in recent years, as both surgical techniques and social support have improved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regrets following gender transition are extremely rare and have become even rarer as both surgical techniques and social support have improved. Pooling data from numerous studies demonstrates a regret rate ranging from .3 percent to 3.8 percent. Regrets are most likely to result from a lack of social support after transition or poor surgical outcomes using older techniques.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Factors that are predictive of success in the treatment of gender dysphoria include adequate preparation and mental health support prior to treatment, proper follow-up care from knowledgeable providers, consistent family and social support, and high-quality surgical outcomes (when surgery is involved).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Transgender individuals, particularly those who cannot access treatment for gender dysphoria or who encounter unsupportive social environments, are more likely than the general population to experience health challenges such as depression, anxiety, suicidality and minority stress. While gender transition can mitigate these challenges, the health and well-being of transgender people can be harmed by stigmatizing and discriminatory treatment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;An inherent limitation in the field of transgender health research is that it is difficult to conduct prospective studies or randomized control trials of treatments for gender dysphoria because of the individualized nature of treatment, the varying and unequal circumstances of population members, the small size of the known transgender population, and the ethical issues involved in withholding an effective treatment from those who need it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Transgender outcomes research is still evolving and has been limited by the historical stigma against conducting research in this field. More research is needed to adequately characterize and address the needs of the transgender population.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, your goal right now should be to &lt;strong&gt;create a supportive environment for your teenager&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;help build their self-esteem&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;allow them to continue to engage with the LGBT community&lt;/strong&gt; while &lt;strong&gt;continuing to seek therapy with professionals who understand transgender and gender variance issues&lt;/strong&gt;. Anything less is a risk to your teenager's health.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2018-10-03T21:02:03.283" Id="34973" LastActivityDate="2018-10-03T21:02:03.283" OwnerUserId="4481" ParentId="34033" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="37448" AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;My oldest child (17) told us that he has been struggling with finding his &quot;presentation&quot; and he &quot;thinks&quot; the answer is that she's a woman. Oldest is searching for the right female name and wants to change her name in time for senior year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are lucky to have a children's hospital close by that has a specialty gender clinic and I called the next morning and got the ball rolling there. Oldest will have access to expert counseling as well as medical treatment should that be the route of the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, despite trying to be supportive of his/her gender dysphoria, I may have put a foot wrong. While doing more research, I found that there are more flavors of gender and queerness than I ever thought possible. Because I don't want the full gender change (feels like a rejection of the past 17 years of our family life), I suggested that s/he look into being genderqueer or transfeminine. It's the odd wording that s/he used that makes me think these are valid possibilities. S/he's more concerned with &quot;presentation&quot; and didn't at all mention being uncomfortable without breasts or uncomfortable with his current private parts. I keep rationalizing, but I wonder if I accidentally hurt his/her feelings and shouldn't throw out these ideas again just because they suit &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt; better and s/he may not have considered them before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;S/he seems okay this morning. We had a positive exchange and late last night, s/he even cleaned and left the coffee press and coffee cups out for his/her father and me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question:&lt;/strong&gt; Is it okay to bring up the alternatives of genderqueer and transfeminine in slightly greater depth and discuss them as real alternatives or should I just keep avoiding names and pronouns and leave the fine-grained gendering discussion to the experts at the hospital?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ETA:&lt;/strong&gt; We're a few weeks out now and it's still hard for us in some ways, but it's getting better faster than I imagined it would. Every time I take a step toward getting her name used and officially changed and setting appointments with doctors and counselors, the genuine sincerity of her thanks and appreciation have helped reaffirm for me that she's doing the right thing for herself. &lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="5" CreationDate="2019-06-28T21:56:40.133" Id="37439" LastActivityDate="2019-07-10T16:07:23.030" LastEditDate="2019-07-10T16:07:23.030" LastEditorUserId="27044" OwnerUserId="27044" PostTypeId="1" Score="8" Tags="&lt;teen&gt;&lt;communication&gt;&lt;lgbtq&gt;" Title="Is it okay to encourage a transgender teen to consider genderqueer and transfeminine as alternatives to transgender?" ViewCount="943"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I am an adult trans woman and a mom. I love Chrys's answer and your supportiveness, but I just wanted to provide a little more insight here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Is it okay to encourage [...] genderqueer and transfeminine as alternatives to transgender?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transgender identity is inclusive of genderqueer and transfeminine individuals, so it is important not to contrast these  with each other. Perhaps you meant as alternatives to identifying as a binary trans woman? In any case, the difference between these identities should not be defined by what physical changes a person chooses for themselves, but by how they feel internally. It is certainly great for your teen to be aware of all the different possibilities, but I want you to understand that at the end of the day if your teen identifies as a woman but doesn't want to change some physical features that is ok.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;My oldest child (17) told us that he has been struggling with finding his &quot;presentation&quot; and he &quot;thinks&quot; the answer is that she's a woman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there is likely lots of questioning going on, I would discourage placing too much weight on your child's choice of the word &quot;thinks&quot;. Your child may have trouble expressing certainty because of the fear of what kind of responses she may receive (i.e. &quot;Are you sure you're a woman? You don't do X.&quot;). One of my biggest fears when I first started trying to express my gender identity was that cis women (even liberal, accepting ones) would feel I was claiming an identity that I didn't really represent. For now, from what I gather, it seems your child has chosen she/her pronouns. That could change, and that's ok, but you should use what your child currently feels like. For that reason, I'm going to refer to her that way through the rest of my answer. In case it's not clear, this is why I'm gathering she's currently chosen she/her: &quot;the answer is that she's a woman&quot; and &quot;Oldest is searching for the right female name and wants to change her name in time for senior year&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We are lucky to have a children's hospital close by that has a specialty gender clinic and I called the next morning and got the ball rolling there. Oldest will have access to expert counseling as well as medical treatment should that be the route of the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's fantastic! And your daughter is so blessed to have a mother willing to do this for her. I would also encourage you to get counseling as well, if you haven't already, because it can help you process some of these worries openly before you decide whether/how to approach your daughter about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Because I don't want the full gender change (feels like a rejection of the past 17 years of our family life), I suggested that s/he look into being genderqueer or transfeminine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the area of biggest concern to me, and why I would strongly urge you to consider counseling as well. While it is perfectly normal for you to experience feelings of fear/rejection/loss over these types of changes, the way you respond to your daughter will have a &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; impact on her well-being. If your daughter &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; feel the need for hormones/surgeries (there are many options and whether they are needed depends entirely on how your daughter feels), then your expressed reluctance may make it harder for her to accept or communicate to you. She may not know or want them right now, and that is fine, but you should be careful about discouraging her from them. If there are concerns about timing, that is something you should definitely bring up with the therapist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;should I just keep avoiding names and pronouns&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chrys already covered this pretty well, but you should use whatever name and pronouns your daughter is comfortable with in the moment. You don't have to wait for a legal name change to start using the new name. However, if there are people she is not out to, you should have a discussion with her about how to handle referring to her around them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bottom-line: Chrys is absolutely right that no matter what bumps in the road there are, you are on the right path! I just love the way she finished her answer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Your child is lucky to have supportive parents, and if the worst experience ever is that on Day 1 someone said &quot;are you sure you need to go 100% all the way, you might just be genderqueer?&quot; then that is going to be a pretty great transition. Smile, be glad you're someone who is trusted to be along on the journey, and gather your strength for protecting your child from a world that won't all be as nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reaching out for help! I love that you care so much about your daughter to consider all these factors!&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2019-07-03T21:05:46.927" Id="37457" LastActivityDate="2019-07-03T21:13:04.243" LastEditDate="2019-07-03T21:13:04.243" LastEditorUserId="4481" OwnerUserId="4481" ParentId="37439" PostTypeId="2" Score="13"/>
</posts>