<?xml version="1.0" ?><posts>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="19139" AnswerCount="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;This morning at 8:30 AM on the Power 96.1 radio station in Atlanta, Georgia, I heard a radio ad for M&amp;amp;M in which it was claimed that one out of every one hundred (1/100) peanuts ends up in Peanut M&amp;amp;Ms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there any data behind this assertion or was it just made up for marketing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/mms-peanut-chocolate-candies-thrill-fans-at-25th-annual-peach-drop-in-atlanta-with-all-star-performances-and-one-sweet-surprise-238335271.html&quot;&gt;an article on PR Newswire&lt;/a&gt; which also mentions the statement touted by Mars:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;in fact only 1 in 100 peanuts is lucky enough to find its way into a bag of M&amp;amp;M'S Peanut&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;I tagged this with the nutrition tag because &quot;food&quot; is a synonym.&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2014-01-14T14:52:17.780" FavoriteCount="2" Id="19138" LastActivityDate="2017-10-25T11:08:02.440" LastEditDate="2014-01-17T19:18:22.937" LastEditorUserId="43" OwnerUserId="14622" PostTypeId="1" Score="21" Tags="&lt;nutrition&gt;&lt;marketing&gt;" Title="Does one out of every hundred peanuts produced end up in Peanut M&amp;Ms?" ViewCount="4915"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.fas.usda.gov/psdonline/psdreport.aspx?hidReportRetrievalName=BVS&amp;amp;hidReportRetrievalID=918&amp;amp;hidReportRetrievalTemplateID=1#ancor&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;preliminary projection for world peanut production in 2012/2013&lt;/a&gt; is 39.93 million metric tons. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.crbtrader.com/fund/articles/peanuts.asp&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;In 2006&lt;/a&gt;, it was 32.30 million metric tons. That is in-shell weight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The global shelling percentage (how much peanut is left after shelling, by mass) is about 70% (El Bassam. &lt;em&gt;Handbook of Bioenergy Crops: A Complete Reference to Species, Development and Applications&lt;/em&gt;. 2010. At p. 200).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That results in about 28 million metric tons of shelled peanut in 2013, or 23 million metric tons of shelled peanut in 2006.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=28+million+metric+tons+%2F+100&amp;amp;oq=28+million+metric+tons+%2F+100&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;For 1/100 of that&lt;/a&gt; to find its way into Peanut M&amp;amp;Ms would mean that at least 0.28 million metric tons of peanuts are used in Peanut M&amp;amp;Ms per year (or 0.23 million metric tons at 2006 levels of production).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://stat.pugetsound.edu/hoard/datasetDetails.aspx?id=1&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;average mass of a Peanut M&amp;amp;M&lt;/a&gt; is 2.59 grams (with a standard error of 0.03 grams). (The average mass of Peanut M&amp;amp;Ms is an upper bound on the average mass of peanut in them. There are other ingredients.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=0.23+million+metric+tons+%2F+2.59+grams&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;0.23 million metric tons (the 2006 number) of 2.59 gram units is 88,803,088,803 units&lt;/a&gt;. At least 88 billion Peanut M&amp;amp;Ms would be needed to be produced. (For 2013, the requisite number is 108 billion Peanut M&amp;amp;Ms.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are about 146 billion M&amp;amp;M candies produced per year. (Sutton and Klein. &lt;em&gt;Enterprise Marketing Management: The New Science of Marketing&lt;/em&gt;. 2006. At p. 139). This estimate is still current. I confirmed this by a phone call to Mars. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/hm1a4ugxykgy650/400million.mp3&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;They said&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We make about 400 million M&amp;amp;M pieces every day; that's for all types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically the question comes down to whether it's plausible (or even better, whether there's evidence) that at least 60% (for 2006) or at least 74% (for 2013) of M&amp;amp;Ms are peanut M&amp;amp;Ms.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="21" CreationDate="2014-01-14T17:33:15.397" Id="19139" LastActivityDate="2017-10-25T11:08:02.440" LastEditDate="2017-10-25T11:08:02.440" LastEditorDisplayName="user5582" LastEditorUserId="37939" OwnerDisplayName="user5582" ParentId="19138" PostTypeId="2" Score="41"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The &quot;1/100&quot; claim appears to have originated directly from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mars.com/global/press-center/press-list/news-releases.aspx?SiteId=94&amp;amp;Id=5415&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;this press release from Mars&lt;/a&gt;, the manufacturer of M&amp;amp;Ms, which itself directly quotes Roy Benin, Chief Consumer Officer of Mars Chocolate North America:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“This event perfectly captured our passion for peanuts – in fact only 1 in 100 peanuts is lucky enough to find its way into a bag of M&amp;amp;M’S Peanut.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This claim appears to be the cornerstone of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/mms&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;an ongoing marketing campaign for M&amp;amp;M&lt;/a&gt;.  The exact wording used in that press release, though, is a bit ambiguous.  It could very well mean that only 1 in 100 of the peanuts &lt;em&gt;delivered&lt;/em&gt; to Mars makes it into an M&amp;amp;M.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://skeptics.stackexchange.com/a/19139/1337&quot;&gt;Articuno's answer&lt;/a&gt; provides a thorough analysis of the numbers, which I see no need to reproduce.  With that said I disagree with the conclusion that the numbers are insufficient to conclude that the 1/100 claim is &lt;em&gt;plausible&lt;/em&gt;, because, like most agricultural products, worldwide peanut production varies quite dramatically year over year.  For example, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.peanutsusa.com/component/phocadownload/category/20-2011.html?download=82:Peanut%20Crop%20Production%20-%202011%20Annual%20Summary&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;the USDA reported almost a 13% increase in peanut production in the US from 2009 to 2010&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.fas.usda.gov/psdonline/psdreport.aspx?hidReportRetrievalName=BVS&amp;amp;hidReportRetrievalID=918&amp;amp;hidReportRetrievalTemplateID=1#ancor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;The data to which Articuno linked&lt;/a&gt; predicted over a 5% increase in worldwide production in 2012/2013.  Global peanut production in 2006—the year from which the M&amp;amp;M candy production statistic was reported—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.crbtrader.com/fund/articles/peanuts.asp&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;was 32.303 million metric tons&lt;/a&gt;, which is about 20% lower than the cited projections for 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the new numbers for 2006, the requisite number of peanut M&amp;amp;Ms produced would be about 124.7 billion units, which is below the total number of M&amp;amp;M sales reported in that year.  Therefore, there is a chance that the interpretation that &quot;1/100&quot; means &quot;one out of every hundred peanuts produced &lt;em&gt;in the world&lt;/em&gt;&quot; could potentially be plausible, but it is impossible to evaluate the statement's validity because its original wording is ambiguous.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2014-01-14T18:29:37.710" Id="19140" LastActivityDate="2014-01-14T18:29:37.710" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:46:38.070" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="1337" ParentId="19138" PostTypeId="2" Score="16"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="28548" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://pubs.niaaa.nih.gov/publications/AA67/AA67.htm&quot;&gt;National Institute for Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism&lt;/a&gt; strongly implies that consuming &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; alcohol at all while under the age of 18 is excessively detrimental to one's health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While never stated outright, this implication is visible in places such as this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Whatever it is that leads adolescents to begin drinking, once they start they face a number of potential health risks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For adults, most studies indicate that a regular diet of one or two drinks a day is healthy--and in fact may have health benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would drinking one or two drinks a day (or less) do more physiological harm to a 13 to 18 year old than an adult?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="15" CreationDate="2014-01-22T15:34:59.543" FavoriteCount="3" Id="19249" LastActivityDate="2015-08-20T04:22:32.760" LastEditDate="2014-04-01T14:00:35.750" LastEditorUserId="14622" OwnerUserId="14622" PostTypeId="1" Score="13" Tags="&lt;medical-science&gt;&lt;alcohol&gt;" Title="Does drinking recommended amounts of alcohol do more harm to children aged 13 to 18 than it does to adults?" ViewCount="1453"/>
  <row Body="&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&quot;It's about time we remind the world how irresistible M&amp;amp;M's Peanut really is,&quot; Seth Klugherz, senior director of M&amp;amp;M's Chocolate Candies, said in a statement. &quot;Each M&amp;amp;M's Peanut is literally 1 in 100 — meaning we have to sort through 100 different peanuts, just to find one that's lucky enough to make its way into a bag of M&amp;amp;M's Peanut.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mars.com/france/fr/press-center/press-list/news-releases.aspx?SiteId=94&amp;amp;Id=5446&quot;&gt;http://www.mars.com/france/fr/press-center/press-list/news-releases.aspx?SiteId=94&amp;amp;Id=5446&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;so, NOT 1% of all peanuts in the world... but that raises a new question of what happens to the 99% of peanuts they don't use?  and why are they so bad/what's wrong with all those peanuts?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2014-03-04T03:23:18.193" Id="19768" LastActivityDate="2014-03-04T11:05:32.287" LastEditDate="2014-03-04T11:05:32.287" LastEditorDisplayName="user16186" OwnerUserId="17937" ParentId="19138" PostTypeId="2" Score="10"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drinking one or two drinks shows higher estimated BACs (which might relate to more harm due to impairment in reasoning, depth perception, peripheral vision and glare recovery) in a 13 to 18 year old than an adult with relation to body weight.&lt;/strong&gt; Research shows that at one standard drink, peak BACs ranges from 62.0 mg/dL for 9-year-old boys to 27.4 mg/dL for 17-year-old boys, and from 61.9 mg/dL for 9-year-old girls to 38.2 mg/dL for 17-year-old girls. At two drinks, the estimated peak BAC for girls aged 9-13 exceeded 80 mg/dL (81.8 to 123.9 mg/dL), while only those for boys aged 9-12 reached this level (84.6 to 124.0 mg/dL).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Children and adolescents exhibited higher estimated BACs than adults at each level of alcohol intake since &quot;Both children and early adolescents weigh substantially less than adults and would likely achieve considerably higher BAC levels after five drinks within a 2-hour period or would reach a BAC ≥ 80 mg/dL after significantly fewer drinks&quot;&lt;/strong&gt; per study by Donovan JE in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2690712/&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;2009&lt;/a&gt;.  A BAC level of 20 mg/dl or higher is considered indicative of alcohol use and BAC levels greater than 80 mg/dL (&gt;17.4 mmol/L) is considered positive for driving under the influence in most states in USA. Per the study, at three drinks, the estimated peak BAC for all children aged 9-17 were 2.3 times greater than the NIAAA binge drinking level for the youngest children (i.e., 186.0 and 185.8 mg/dL for 9-year-old boys and girls, respectively)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;At one standard drink, boys and girls could theoretically achieve peak BACs ranging from 62.0 mg/dL for 9-year-old boys to 27.4 mg/dL for 17-year-old boys, and from 61.9 mg/dL for 9-year-old girls to 38.2 mg/dL for 17-year-old girls. At two drinks, the estimated peak BAC for girls aged 9-13 exceeded 80 mg/dL (81.8 to 123.9 mg/dL), while only those for boys aged 9-12 reached this level (84.6 to 124.0 mg/dL). At three drinks, the estimated peak BAC for all children aged 9-17 exceeded the 80 mg/dL NIAAA criterion, and were 2.3 times this level for the youngest children (i.e., 186.0 and 185.8 mg/dL for 9-year-old boys and girls, respectively). At five standard drinks, estimated peak BACs ranged from 137.1 to 309.9 mg/dL for boys and from 191.1 to 309.7 mg/dL for girls, levels that can result in coma and respiratory problems in children and early adolescents.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The more standard drinks consumed at each age, the higher the estimated BAC. Also, the younger the child, the higher the estimated post-peak BAC at each intake level. For ages 9-13, the mean estimated BACs for boys and girls were comparable at each level: mean BACs for girls fell within the 95% CI for boys the same age. For ages 14 through 17, girls had higher estimated BACs than boys at each intake level, with no overlap in their 95% CIs.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RESULTS:&lt;/strong&gt; The estimated BAC for children after consuming just three standard drinks within a 2-hour period was between 80 and 139 mg/dL for boys aged 9-13 and for girls aged 9-17, indicating substantial potential alcohol impairment. At five drinks within 2 hours, the level used to define binge drinking among college students, children aged 9-13 were estimated to have BACs two to three times the adult legal limit for intoxication of 80 mg/dL.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CONCLUSIONS:&lt;/strong&gt; Binge drinking assessment in children and adolescents requires substantially lower cut-points than those used for college students. Binge drinking should be defined as 3 or more drinks for 9-13 year olds, as 4 or more drinks for boys and 3 or more drinks for girls aged 14 or 15, and as 5 or more drinks for boys and 3 or more drinks for girls aged 16 or 17.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism (NIAAA) redefined binge drinking as a drinking pattern that brings a person’s blood alcohol concentration (BAC) to 80 mg/dL or above, a level accompanied by significant physical and mental impairment. For the typical adult, this pattern corresponds to five drinks by a man or four drinks by a woman within a 2-hour period.&quot; and definition of standard drink can be found &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.camy.org/factsheets/sheets/alcohol_advertising_promotion/Call_To_Action.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First use of alcohol at ages 11-14 greatly heightens the risk of progression to the development of alcohol disorders per study by DeWit DJ et.al. in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/10784467&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;2000&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Body of evidence, however, does suggest that early exposure to alcohol may set adolescents up for problem drinking later on, and that delaying the first drink for as long as possible may help to foster more responsible alcohol &lt;a href=&quot;http://healthland.time.com/2013/05/24/if-drinking-starts-at-puberty-its-more-likely-to-lead-to-alcohol-problems/&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;habits&lt;/a&gt;.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The health risks of youth drinking per &lt;a href=&quot;http://pubs.niaaa.nih.gov/publications/AA67/AA67.htm&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;NIAAA&lt;/a&gt; are &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brain Effects by animal studies&lt;/strong&gt; — &quot;It’s simply not known how alcohol will affect the long-term memory and learning skills of people who began drinking heavily as adolescents. Scientists currently are examining just how alcohol affects the developing brain, and research has shown that animals fed alcohol during this critical developmental stage continue to show long-lasting impairment from alcohol as they age&quot;. Alcohol use during DSM-IV alcohol dependent adolescence is associated with prefrontal volume abnormalities, including white matter &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2825148/&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;differences&lt;/a&gt;. Additional research is necessary to know the exact effects of alcohol on the adolescent hippocampus and other brain structures and to better understand the long-term implications of adolescent alcohol &lt;a href=&quot;http://pubs.niaaa.nih.gov/publications/arh284/213-221.htm&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;exposure&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Liver Effects&lt;/strong&gt; — &quot;Elevated liver enzymes, indicating some degree of liver damage, have been found in some adolescents who drink alcohol. Young drinkers who are overweight or obese showed elevated liver enzymes even with only moderate levels of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/11584156&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;drinking&lt;/a&gt;&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Growth and Endocrine Effects by animal studies&lt;/strong&gt;— &quot;In both males and females, puberty is a period associated with marked hormonal changes, including increases in the sex hormones, estrogen and testosterone. These hormones, in turn, increase production of other hormones and growth factors which are vital for normal organ development. Drinking alcohol during this period of rapid growth and development (i.e., prior to or during puberty) may upset the critical hormonal balance necessary for normal development of organs, muscles, and bones. Studies in animals also show that consuming alcohol during puberty adversely affects the maturation of the reproductive system&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2015-07-24T07:24:49.197" Id="28548" LastActivityDate="2015-08-18T08:48:48.467" LastEditDate="2015-08-18T08:48:48.467" LastEditorUserId="26648" OwnerUserId="26648" ParentId="19249" PostTypeId="2" Score="5"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="30587" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;It is often claimed that yellow (or a particular hue of yellow or yellow-green) is the most conspicuous color. This supposed fact is used in many industries from safety to advertising. This reasoning is used as justification for the yellow coloration of everything from safety vests to school buses to hard hats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/b6Bp6.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/b6Bp6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Yellow safety vest&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see this claim made &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.visualexpert.com/Resources/colorfunctionality.html&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Recent research in commercial and safety fields has converged on the same conclusion: the most conspicuous colors are yellow and yellow-green, sometimes called &quot;lime yellow.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.colormatters.com/color-matters-for-kids/why-are-school-buses-yellow&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Lateral peripheral vision for detecting yellows is 1.24 times greater than for red.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Many experts also point out that colors such as yellow or greenish-yellow are more visible to the human eye under dimmer conditions compared to red.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While both sites mention &quot;science&quot;, &quot;experts&quot;, or &quot;studies&quot;, there are no &lt;em&gt;direct&lt;/em&gt; references or links provided. The first site has references, but they are to secondary works and not the studies themselves--with the exception of a 1931 study for which that site is the only reference in Google search results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conversely, I have seen some claims that other colors such as red, orange, or pink are more conspicuous than yellow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One argument is that during the daytime yellow is more likely to blend into background colors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So be careful to take into account not only colors' &quot;raw&quot; visibility but also the ability to discern them from background.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="6" CreationDate="2015-10-26T16:26:29.473" FavoriteCount="1" Id="30579" LastActivityDate="2015-12-16T15:50:54.783" OwnerUserId="14622" PostTypeId="1" Score="11" Tags="&lt;safety&gt;&lt;colors&gt;" Title="Is yellow the most conspicuous color?" ViewCount="891"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I recalled hearing that the U.S. Coast Guard had studied this, in an effort to determine the best colors for life rafts, to make them more likely to be seen by the spotters aboard SAR aircraft.  I could not find that study, but I did find a similar, older one by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.uscg.mil/hq/cg5/cg534/manuals/Study%20of%20Detectability%20of%20Colored%20Targets.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;U.S. Navy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did not feel like reading the whole thing, so I skipped to the conclusion on page 57:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fluorescent paints, particularly the yellow-orange and red orange, are superior in detectability to ordinary paints.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of the ordinary paints tested, the most conspicuous colors were those of high saturation and/or brightness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper does mention a color called &quot;Saturn Yellow&quot; elsewhere as having superior detection.  It also indicates brightness (florescence) may be more important than hue, as the observers were often unable to correctly report the color of an object from a great distance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conclusion seems to favor orange, and the fact that PFDs (life jackets) and life rafts today are often orange is also compelling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EDIT:  As a counter point, I have discovered that the International Tennis Federation had done its own study in the 1970s, with emphasis on television viewers.  I couldn't confirm it, but it appears they did not release the full study publicly, only the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.itftennis.com/technical/balls/other/history.aspx&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;conclusion&lt;/a&gt;.  They were even asked &quot;Why not pink or orange?&quot; and only said the study indicated yellow was best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My original intent was that the answer to the stated question is &quot;no.&quot;  But when we put the Navy and ITF data together with the ideas discussed in the comments, perhaps the best answer one can give is just &quot;Maybe, it depends.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="7" CreationDate="2015-10-27T18:04:09.790" Id="30587" LastActivityDate="2015-11-16T15:19:59.623" LastEditDate="2015-11-16T15:19:59.623" LastEditorUserId="29604" OwnerUserId="29604" ParentId="30579" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="32990" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia writes in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lateralization_of_brain_function&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Lateralization of brain function&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Significant differences between male and female hemispheric rivalry and dominance have been established. Male brains have significantly better global and rivalry efficiency between the hemispheres. Whereas female brains possess considerably better local efficiency within the RHS &lt;em&gt;[right brain hemisphere]&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is that claim well-supported by evidence?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2016-05-19T15:02:21.030" Id="32989" LastActivityDate="2016-05-21T11:08:02.840" LastEditDate="2016-05-21T11:08:02.840" LastEditorUserId="3943" OwnerUserId="196" PostTypeId="1" Score="1" Tags="&lt;physiology&gt;&lt;neurology&gt;&lt;gender&gt;" Title="Do male human brains have better global efficiency than female human brains and female brains have better local efficiency in the right hemisphere?" ViewCount="548"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;It is not quite that clean cut. Here is what a 2013 study found:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the cerebrum, males tend to have greater &lt;em&gt;within&lt;/em&gt;-hemisphere connectivity, and females tend to have greater inter-hemisphere connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this effect is reversed in the cerebellum: males tend to have greater inter-hemisphere connectivity, and females tend to have greater within-hemisphere connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study used the following method:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In this work, we modeled the structural connectome using diffusion tensor imaging in a sample of 949 youths (aged 8–22 y, 428 males and 521 females)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ref: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/111/2/823&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Sex differences in the structural connectome of the human brain - Ingalhalikar, et al.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 2012 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jneurosci.org/content/32/7/2241.short&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Journal of Neuroscience paper&lt;/a&gt; concluded that there are significant differences between males and females in brain structure and:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The number of published studies limited to males remains stunningly and stubbornly high (Zucker and Beery, 2010). Scientific conclusions based on the study of one sex could have limited value in understanding some phenomena in the other sex. Thus, females deserve more study. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This says nothing specifically regarding hemispheres, but does show that there are notable differences yet the field is still evolving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting even more specific, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0149763413003011&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;2014 meta-analysis&lt;/a&gt; on sex differences in brain volumes and densities notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;At a regional level, males on average have larger volumes and higher tissue densities in the left amygdala, hippocampus, insular cortex, putamen; higher densities in the right VI lobe of the cerebellum and in the left claustrum; and larger volumes in the bilateral anterior parahippocampal gyri, posterior cingulate gyri, precuneus, temporal poles, and cerebellum, areas in the left posterior and anterior cingulate gyri, and in right amygdala, hippocampus, and putamen. Females have on average higher density in the left frontal pole, and larger volumes in the right frontal pole, inferior and middle frontal gyri, pars triangularis, planum temporale/parietal operculum, anterior cingulate gyrus, insular cortex, and Heschl's gyrus; bilateral thalami and precuneus; the left parahippocampal gyrus and lateral occipital cortex (superior division).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2016-05-19T15:15:38.907" Id="32990" LastActivityDate="2016-05-19T16:48:47.207" LastEditDate="2016-05-19T16:48:47.207" LastEditorUserId="14622" OwnerUserId="14622" ParentId="32989" PostTypeId="2" Score="1"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="35293" AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;As claimed on page 33 of &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.archive.org/web/20171118103754/http://www.mms-supplement.com:80/master_mineral_of_the_third_millennium-partial_free-2011.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;this MMS book&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;All pathogens (poison producers) have a negative ORP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;All beneficial bacteria have a positive ORP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The beneficial bacteria are positively charged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Human tissue cells also have a weak positive charge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are these valid claims?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional clarification of the terminology:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;ORP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;All  organisms  and  body  cells  and  even  liquids  have  an  ORP  (Oxidation  Reduction  Potential)  that  can  be  either  positive  or negative. The ORP is the electrical charge that cells exert on other things in their immediate environment. Oxidizers also have an ORP, mostly called Oxidation Potential, and all oxidizers have a positive potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pathogens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Pathogens  create  a  waste  material  that  is  poisonous  to  the  body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beneficial bacteria&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Beneficial bacteria do   not   generate any poisonous material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="11" CreationDate="2016-09-26T20:24:57.367" Id="35277" LastActivityDate="2018-11-28T14:38:01.720" LastEditDate="2018-11-28T14:38:01.720" LastEditorUserId="8014" OwnerUserId="8014" PostTypeId="1" Score="2" Tags="&lt;biology&gt;&lt;hygiene&gt;" Title="Do pathogens have a negative ORP and beneficial bacteria a positive?" ViewCount="1023"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The beneficial strain of &lt;em&gt;E. coli&lt;/em&gt; K-12 has a negative ORP. Therefore, the original claim cannot be universally true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, &lt;em&gt;E. coli&lt;/em&gt; is a facultative anaerobe, which means it can survive in both oxygenated and oxygen-free environments. Since some strains of &lt;em&gt;E. coli&lt;/em&gt; are pathogens, this means that the claims elsewhere in that document that oxygen kills pathogens but preserves beneficial organisms are also false.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jb.asm.org/content/182/3/620.short&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Extracellular Oxidoreduction Potential Modifies Carbon and Electron Flow in Escherichia coli - Riondet, et al.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2016-09-27T21:15:12.900" Id="35293" LastActivityDate="2016-09-28T13:49:37.880" LastEditDate="2016-09-28T13:49:37.880" LastEditorUserId="14622" OwnerUserId="14622" ParentId="35277" PostTypeId="2" Score="19"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="35741" AnswerCount="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Swastika&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Wikipedia entry on the swastika&lt;/a&gt; says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It is considered to be a sacred and auspicious symbol in Hinduism,
  Buddhism, and Jainism and &lt;strong&gt;dates back at least 11,000 years.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source cited for the claim is &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com.bd/books?redir_esc=y&amp;amp;id=-3804Ud9-4IC&amp;amp;q=+11%2C000+years.#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=11000&amp;amp;f=false&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Handbook of Tibetan Buddhist Symbols&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. I searched for &quot;11000&quot; and &quot;11000 years&quot; in it, but this didn't yield any results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found &lt;a href=&quot;https://zeenews.india.com/news/india/indian-researchers-solve-centuries-old-puzzle-claim-swastika-is-11000-years-old_1904477.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;a Zeenews article&lt;/a&gt; that says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;According to a 'Times of India' report, it has now come to light that
  'Swastika' is much older than the Aryans and even the Indus Valley
  Civilization.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A team of top-notch researchers from several prestigious institutions
  from across the country have found that the 'Swastika' dates back at
  least 11,000 years and have traced its spread to western and
  Middle-Eastern civilizations.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In fact, one of their key findings is that a Ukranian 'Swastika',
  believed to date back 12,000 years to the Paleolithic Age, may not be
  this old, said the report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it doesn't give any links to the original &lt;em&gt;Times of India&lt;/em&gt; article or the report it talks about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My question is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is the claim that the swastika is over 11000 years old backed by scientific evidence?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2016-11-03T20:47:02.550" Id="35739" LastActivityDate="2016-11-04T20:06:43.033" LastEditDate="2016-11-04T05:13:15.840" LastEditorUserId="6523" OwnerUserId="32459" PostTypeId="1" Score="7" Tags="&lt;religion&gt;" Title="Is the swastika over 11000 years old?" ViewCount="672"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Essentially yes&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The earliest figure recognized as a swastika was found on a bird figurine in Mezin, Ukraine and was dated to about 12,000 years ago:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;From Figure 2 we observe that the original &lt;strong&gt;swastika&lt;/strong&gt; was an elaborate form with spiral arms, whereas the more modern symbol is like the gammadion (geometrical) form with short arms.&lt;sup&gt;14b&lt;/sup&gt; Truncation to the gammadion form does not change the meaning of this symbol in connection with the Earth Mother or Goddess culture, but it lessens the chance of interpretive insight. The crux of the matter is this: the swastika is a double-symbol for a fertility religion having two gods, the Earth Mother and the Earth Father. To get to this point, you must study the symbols of ancient art until you conclude that the principal meaning of the equal-arm cross is reference to the Earth Mother. In addition to these context-related sources, numerous examples&lt;sup&gt;14a,c&lt;/sup&gt; of ancient minimal art of human females and birds make the same suggestion about the cross. The point then is that the ancient swastika was an equal-arm cross with a serpent-symbol spiral attached to the tip of each arm. &lt;strong&gt;You can see this in Figure 2, and it is over 12,000 years old.&lt;/strong&gt; Further to this point, we have published&lt;sup&gt;14d,e&lt;/sup&gt; sacred bird images from ancient Australia and Shang China with inscribed snakes. Serious confirmation indeed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;emphasis added&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recommend checking the link because there is an illustration of the artifact and the inscribed swastika.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This discovery was originally noted by Joseph Campbell:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The oldest example of a &quot;Swastika&quot; symbol, as I interpret it, was discovered in the book Flight of the Wild Gander by Joseph Campbell&lt;sup&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt; circa 1998. It took some time to locate an older source of his figures that could be republished in this Journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20120216232228/http://midwesternepigraphic.org/swastika01.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;ICE AGE SWASTIKA FROM MEZIN IN UKRAINE : INTERPRETATION OF A BASIC SYMBOL OF MANKIND - John J White , III&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2016-11-03T21:18:58.853" Id="35740" LastActivityDate="2016-11-03T21:18:58.853" OwnerUserId="14622" ParentId="35739" PostTypeId="2" Score="5"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="36084" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rudolf_Otto&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Rudolf Otto&lt;/a&gt; claimed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;That Krishna himself was a historical figure is indeed quite indubitable. [&lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=WuVG8PxKq_0C&amp;amp;lpg=PA127&amp;amp;ots=lUQANx1t-6&amp;amp;dq=%22That%20Krishna%20himself%20was%20a%20historical%20figure%20is%20indeed%20quite%20indubitable.%22%20-%20Rudolf%20Otto&amp;amp;pg=PA127#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=%22That%20Krishna%20himself%20was%20a%20historical%20figure%20is%20indeed%20quite%20indubitable.%22%20-%20Rudolf%20Otto&amp;amp;f=false&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this, much of modern Western discourse ignores (or displays skepticism towards) a historical Krishna, while Indian discourse maintains that he is in fact historical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have read a few of the arguments for a historical Krishna, and we have only dealt with one here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://skeptics.stackexchange.com/q/28415/14622&quot;&gt;Has the legendary city of Dwarka been found under water?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I consider this to be a weak support, even if the underwater ruins do turn out to date older.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is difficult to find much modern scholarship addressing this topic, so I decided if we could tackle Jesus and Moses here, perhaps we could tackle Krishna as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there a case in modern scholarship for a historical Krishna? If so, what is the evidence?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://skeptics.stackexchange.com/q/1624/14622&quot;&gt;Did Jesus live?&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://skeptics.stackexchange.com/q/3529/14622&quot;&gt;Did Moses live?&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://skeptics.stackexchange.com/q/10966/14622&quot;&gt;Did the Prophet Muhammad exist?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2016-11-22T15:00:22.613" FavoriteCount="2" Id="36029" LastActivityDate="2016-11-29T06:13:38.820" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:46:38.493" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="14622" PostTypeId="1" Score="15" Tags="&lt;history&gt;&lt;religion&gt;&lt;india&gt;" Title="Did Krishna live?" ViewCount="957"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;This is unlikely to be a satisfying answer but I don't anticipate a better one coming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In another answer I have addressed the historicity of the &lt;em&gt;Mahābhārata&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://skeptics.stackexchange.com/questions/19157/can-the-events-of-the-ramayana-and-mahabharata-be-astronomically-dated-to-around&quot;&gt;Can the events of the Ramayana and Mahabharata be astronomically dated to around 7300 BCE and 5561 BCE respectively?&lt;/a&gt; There, I explored some of the problems of the &lt;em&gt;Mahābhārata&lt;/em&gt; as oral literature. Namely, it is presumed that it was passed down for many generations as an oral epic before it was re-edited and written down. Anthropologists have observed that contrary to popular belief, oral cultures actually tend to preserve stories better and have longer, more unchanging memories than literary cultures. (The main academic source for this is Walter Ong, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rads.stackoverflow.com/amzn/click/0415281296&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Orality and Literacy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. There is also a more poetic, shorter, and freely available essay by Ananda Coomaraswamy: &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.worldwisdom.com/public/viewpdf/default.aspx?article-title=The_Bugbear_of_Literacy_by_Ananda_Coomaraswamy.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;The Bugbear of Literacy&lt;/a&gt;&quot;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this tells us absolutely nothing about whether the characters in the &lt;em&gt;Mahābhārata&lt;/em&gt;, including Krishna, actually lived. The traditional assumption in India has been basically ahistoric: that Krishna was a real person, but that he lives primarily through the telling of his story (i.e., what the ancient Greeks would have called ἱστορία &lt;em&gt;historía&lt;/em&gt;) and in his mystical apparition to Hindu believers. The Western conception of &quot;scientifically verifiable&quot; history has come into conflict with the assumptions of many cultures, including Japan and India. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do not have any archaeological evidence for Krishna himself, since India did not have a native tradition of sculpture; this was brought by the Greeks in the final centuries BC. We do have &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mahabharataonline.com/articles/mahabharata_article.php?id=32&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;disputed ruins of the city of Dwarka&lt;/a&gt;. As you note in the question, these have been supposedly dated to 3000 BC. but many academics disagree with this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Dwarka, the oldest evidence of the name &quot;Krishna&quot; is in the &lt;em&gt;Rig Veda&lt;/em&gt;, a more rigorously preserved set of oral prayers which has been dated to roughly 1500 BC based on linguistic evidence. This is merely used as a name and we cannot confirm who it is referring to. The oldest reliably dated references to parts of the Krishna story are the &lt;em&gt;Chandogya Upanishad&lt;/em&gt; (500s BC) and Panini's famous Sanskrit grammar (300s BC). There is also a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Megasthenes&amp;#39;_Herakles&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;disputed reference to Krishna&lt;/a&gt; by a Greek author writing in 300 BC. (source: Edwin Francis Bryant's introduction to &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=0z02cZe8PU8C&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Krishna: A Sourcebook&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Oxford University Press)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we see two things: (1) there is a 3000-year gap between Krishna's supposed birthdate and the earliest archaeologically verifiable references to him, but (2) before &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brahmic_scripts#History&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;500 BC&lt;/a&gt;, India was an oral culture without a sculptural tradition, so we cannot expect any much archaeological evidence for specific historical figures from that era anyway. For comparison, there is a 400-year gap between the earliest Buddhist scriptures and the historical dates for the Buddha, who most scholars believe existed, and a 80-year gap between outsider references to Jesus and his historical dates-- again, most scholars believe he existed, although some people try to put this in dispute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, there is unlikely to ever be as definite a proof for Krishna as there is for Jesus (or, say, Socrates or Caesar), but this simply reflects the respective times and cultures in which these people are said to have lived, and doesn't meet the generally high requirements for an &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Argument_from_silence&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;argument from silence&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2016-11-29T06:13:38.820" Id="36084" LastActivityDate="2016-11-29T06:13:38.820" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:46:38.487" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="22367" ParentId="36029" PostTypeId="2" Score="8"/>
  <row AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;It's a wide spread belief in India (Ayurveda) that drinking water stored in copper ware (like copper jugs and pots) is better for health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's even a website about it: &lt;a href=&quot;http://drcopper.in/scientifically-ayurveda-recommendations.php&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Dr. Copper's &quot;Scientifically &amp;amp; Ayurveda Recommendations&quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sanskriti Magazine in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sanskritimagazine.com/ayurveda/why-copper-was-used-by-our-ancestors/&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Why copper was used by our ancestors&lt;/a&gt; relates it to immunity and fertility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the Minnesota Department of Health article &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.health.state.mn.us/divs/eh/water/factsheet/com/copper.html&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Copper in Drinking Water
Health Effects and How to Reduce Exposure&lt;/a&gt; says that water from copper pipes leads to copper poisoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is drinking water from copper ware good for your health or does it make itworse?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="5" CreationDate="2016-11-30T14:36:51.557" Id="36099" LastActivityDate="2016-11-30T20:48:08.787" LastEditDate="2016-11-30T15:37:34.513" LastEditorDisplayName="user22865" OwnerUserId="29000" PostTypeId="1" Score="6" Tags="&lt;environmental-health&gt;&lt;natural-remedies&gt;&lt;toxicology&gt;&lt;india&gt;" Title="Is drinking water stored in copper vessels (copperware) good for your health?" ViewCount="673"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Copper in the water is not a problem. In fact, in moderation it is necessary for your health. In the United States, a lot of homes use copper plumbing. &lt;strong&gt;However, the concentration of copper can be an issue&lt;/strong&gt;, and letting water sit in copper containers is, in fact, a risk. The average concentration of copper in tap water in the US is between 20 to 75 parts per billion. It can even range up to over 1000 parts per billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To avoid copper toxicity, the concentration of copper in drinking water should be kept below 1300 parts per billion. Tap water can get a high concentration of copper from the water sitting in the pipes overnight. This is what leads me to believe that storing water in copper vessels could be a bad idea. Children under one year old and people with Wilson's disease are even more sensitive to the effects of copper, and keeping the copper concentration below 1300 parts per billion &lt;strong&gt;is not enough&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Water stored in a copper container reaches 180 parts per billion in about 16 hours. This amount will vary depending on conditions and the amount of copper already present in the water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corrosive water and hot water can also lead to higher concentrations of the copper being absorbed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over time copper does form a natural coating that prevents as much leaching into the water, but this does not prevent it completely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION:&lt;/strong&gt; Based on this information, I would advise against storing water in copper containers at all. If an older container that has had time to develop a coating is used, and the water is not left to sit in it overnight, there may be less risk for the average person--but I would definitely not use this with children under one year of age or those who have Wilson's disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ideal solution would be to test your water for the level of copper and ensure that it is safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.atsdr.cdc.gov/toxprofiles/tp132-c1.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Copper Public Health Statement - CDC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/wilsons-disease/basics/definition/con-20043499&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Wilson's disease - Mayo Clinic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/10665/37931/2/9241561734_eng.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Trace Elements in Human Nutrition and Health - World Health Organization&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/Does-drinking-water-kept-overnight-or-for-a-long-interval-in-a-copper-utensil-has-any-medical-benefit/answer/Ankit-Malhotra-3?srid=kKeL&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Does drinking water kept overnight (or for a long interval) in a copper utensil has any medical benefit? - Quora&lt;/a&gt; (with references)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2016-11-30T20:04:50.877" Id="36102" LastActivityDate="2016-11-30T20:48:08.787" LastEditDate="2016-11-30T20:48:08.787" LastEditorUserId="14622" OwnerUserId="14622" ParentId="36099" PostTypeId="2" Score="4"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="36908" AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;According to the Independent article &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.independent.co.uk/life-style/gadgets-and-tech/news/donald-trump-environmental-protection-agency-website-climate-change-global-warming-a7544621.html&quot;&gt;Donald Trump orders Environmental Protection Agency to delete all climate change information from its website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Trump administration is forcing the Environmental Protection Agency to delete all of its pages on climate change.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The move comes as part of a much broader crackdown on postings by all agencies who track the effects of global warming on the environment. All of those organisations – as well as others, like the National Parks Service – have been banned from talking to the public by the US government.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Now scientists are scrambling to save some of the most important parts of the EPA's website before they are deleted off the internet entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am really struggling to believe this is an accurate report. After all, it doesn't seem to me that the US President has ever had full editorial control on any US agency site. Is this a correct representation of what is happening?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is Donald Trump forcing the EPA to take down all climate change information?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2017-01-25T20:50:13.777" FavoriteCount="3" Id="36897" LastActivityDate="2017-06-08T11:36:20.773" LastEditDate="2017-01-25T21:38:12.093" LastEditorUserId="96" OwnerUserId="96" PostTypeId="1" Score="31" Tags="&lt;united-states&gt;&lt;climate-change&gt;&lt;donald-trump&gt;" Title="Is Donald Trump forcing the EPA to take down all climate change information?" ViewCount="2069"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Regarding, your comment that &quot;After all, it doesn't seem to me that the US President has ever had full editorial control on any US agency site&quot;, this is actually an unsettled issue:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Most regulatory statutes specify that agency heads rather than the
  President shall make regulatory decisions. Yet for more than four decades
  every President has established some program to require pre-decisional
  review and clearance of agency regulatory decisions, usually conducted by
  the Office of Management and Budget (OMB). On January 18, 2011,
  President Barack Obama joined his seven predecessors in expressly
  endorsing regulatory review when he signed Executive Order 13,563.
  President Obama’s regulatory review program generally emulates those
  of his two most recent predecessors, relying on OMB’s Office of
  Information and Regulatory Affairs (OIRA) to review only the most
  significant agency rulemaking actions. &lt;strong&gt;Although this form of presidential
  oversight of rulemaking is now well established, an important, unresolved
  question is whether the President has the authority to dictate the substance
  of regulatory decisions entrusted by statute to agency heads. While
  proponents of a unitary executive argue in favor of presidential directive
  authority, this article demonstrates that each President’s regulatory review
  program has disclaimed such authority, even though OIRA at times has
  tried to displace agency decisionmaking.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;Robert V. Percival, &lt;a href=&quot;http://ir.lawnet.fordham.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=4716&amp;amp;context=flr&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Who's In Charge? Does the President Have Directive Authority Over Agency Regulatory Decisions?&lt;/a&gt; , 79 Fordham L. Rev.
2487 (2011).
Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;http://ir.lawnet.fordham.edu/flr/vol79/iss6/2&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;http://ir.lawnet.fordham.edu/flr/vol79/iss6/2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;(emphasis added)&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2017-01-26T19:00:00.660" Id="36910" LastActivityDate="2017-01-26T19:00:00.660" OwnerUserId="14622" ParentId="36897" PostTypeId="2" Score="5"/>
  <row AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://politics.stackexchange.com/a/44415/18373&quot;&gt;an answer on politics.SE&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2395697&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;a Northwestern University study&lt;/a&gt; was highlighted, whose main findings included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;more Democrats than Republicans think astrology is scientific&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Using Fisher’s Exact Test, conservative Republicans are significantly more likely than other groups combined to reject astrology as not scientific (p&amp;lt;.0005). The same is true of conservatives compared to non-conservatives (p&amp;lt;.0005) and Republicans compared to non-Republicans (p&amp;lt;.0005). Likewise, Democrats are less likely to reject astrology as unscientific than others (p&amp;lt;.0005). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;fewer Democrats than Republicans think the earth revolves around the sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;...in 2012 a majority of Democrats (51.4%) could not
  correctly answer both that the earth revolves around the Sun and that this takes a year. Republicans fare a bit better, with only 37.9% failing to get both correct. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that does look a little dubious is that that this study was penned by a law professor. I'm also unsure if it has been published in a peer-review venue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are the results of this study consistent with other similar studies on such matters?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2019-09-09T13:56:25.130" FavoriteCount="5" Id="44941" LastActivityDate="2019-09-12T13:32:51.380" LastEditDate="2019-09-10T01:25:21.367" LastEditorUserId="39645" OwnerUserId="29579" PostTypeId="1" Score="63" Tags="&lt;united-states&gt;&lt;politics&gt;&lt;education&gt;&lt;astrology&gt;" Title="Are Democrats more likely to believe Astrology is a science?" ViewCount="14564"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Independently, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pewforum.org/2009/12/09/many-americans-mix-multiple-faiths/&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Pew&lt;/a&gt; has discovered that a greater percentage of Democrats believe in astrology than Republicans:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.pewresearch.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/11/2012/07/image009.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Pew results: 31% of Democrats, 26% of Independents, and 14% of Republicans believe in astrology&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They include details on their survey methods. They did provide a definition of astrology in the survey: &quot;that the position of the stars and planets can affect people’s lives&quot;. This may rule out people confusing astronomy and astrology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To summarize, this chart depicts that their findings were that 31% of Democrats and 14% of Republicans believe in astrology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There may be good reason to question the significance of these findings, though. In Europe, as in the US, there is considerable belief in astrology. In a multivariate analysis, it was found that people do vary considerably in their answers based on what definition they are given, and that people are likely to confuse astrology and astronomy and likely to rank astrology as more scientific than horoscopes. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://poseidon01.ssrn.com/delivery.php?ID=303127090027116066027123065104122109055040034038059056067025101025116088121078111077124122059008021029045112083094097028001094061060042093055125122091014080003127091019028063006006068086001124079077082127010119126003080067120112028068094066080076077030&amp;amp;EXT=pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;What Makes Some People Think Astrology Is Scientific? - Nick Allum&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the bit about heliocentrism seems at odds with what I have seen before. This is just one study, but it concludes that political conservatism is a predictor of disbelief in Earth Science: &lt;a href=&quot;https://evolution-outreach.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1007/s12052-010-0239-8&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Do Americans Believe Modern Earth Science? - Allan Mazur&lt;/a&gt;. In the table on predicting factors, it notes a small predictive effect (may not be statistically significant) from political conservatism for disbelief in heliocentrism.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2019-09-09T16:18:52.320" Id="44942" LastActivityDate="2019-09-12T13:32:51.380" LastEditDate="2019-09-12T13:32:51.380" LastEditorUserId="14622" OwnerUserId="14622" ParentId="44941" PostTypeId="2" Score="84"/>
</posts>