<?xml version="1.0" ?><posts>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="973" AnswerCount="30" Body="&lt;p&gt;The question is fairly simple. Could a civilization progress so far as to have spaceships while still using swords, spears, and bows as their most advanced weaponry? (what those weapons are made of could, of course, have improved with better material science)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question is one of interdependent technology and culture, I suppose. Is it even possible to find a way into space without hitting the obvious alternative applications of rocket technology? Could you even get to rockets without first developing something like gunpowder?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are there ways of achieving orbit that do not have obvious weapon applications? Something like scramjet engines might allow you to get to orbit with sufficiently low gravity, for instance.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="10" CreationDate="2014-10-03T15:03:18.113" FavoriteCount="6" Id="966" LastActivityDate="2016-07-29T21:01:59.323" LastEditDate="2016-03-04T21:22:11.707" LastEditorUserId="49" OwnerUserId="539" PostTypeId="1" Score="22" Tags="&lt;technology&gt;&lt;culture&gt;&lt;weapons&gt;&lt;space-travel&gt;&lt;civilization&gt;" Title="Could a civilization achieve spaceflight without inventing advanced weaponry along the way?" ViewCount="5924"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="48626" AnswerCount="17" Body="&lt;p&gt;I'm writing a traditional fantasy novel (minus the cliches). I have a land that the novel takes place in. The land does have a name, which sometimes sounds all right, but most of the time sounds kind of stupid. Being the author, it might just be me, but I was wondering if there was some way I could ensure the name of my land would reflect the style and theme (in this case, noble and majestic) like I want it to. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not talking about names like 'Middle Earth' which simply use English words. I'm talking about a completely made up name, like Paolini's 'Alagaësia,' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here's the question: is there some formula or rule I can follow to make geographical names sound similar and unique?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;POST-ANSWER EDIT: I've marked the reply by James as the answer. I think for those simply looking for a good name, this is a great way to go. However, the answer by Durakken is also a great method, and will hold up in the event that your novel is the next Harry Potter or Lord of the Rings. It takes more time, but it is a lot more thorough. And if you get stuck, you can always uses James' method for inspiration. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the answer supplied by Bookeater is a great method to test the names once you have them. After going over names in your head for so long, it can be helpful to write them down and have someone else read them to you. Remember, if they pronounce them wrong, just alter the spelling. The real name likely isn't written in English, so all you're doing is translating it. You just need to make sure it is pronounced correctly. &lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="7" CreationDate="2016-07-26T17:53:04.413" FavoriteCount="36" Id="48622" LastActivityDate="2019-01-08T07:28:29.373" LastEditDate="2019-01-08T07:28:29.373" LastEditorUserId="2113" OwnerUserId="6620" PostTypeId="1" Score="75" Tags="&lt;language&gt;&lt;worldbuilding-process&gt;&lt;names&gt;" Title="How can I develop names for my fantasy land?" ViewCount="22261"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The reason fantasy names often sound weird is that they violate the way we normally handle names.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Romans didn't call Ireland &lt;em&gt;Éirinn&lt;/em&gt;; they called it Hibernia. We don't refer to the Irish name &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aengus&quot;&gt;Aengus&lt;/a&gt; as Oíngus but as Angus. Human cultures adapt names from other languages into names that sound more comfortable to their ears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless your entire work is written in a fantasy language, you are probably going to be writing in an existing language, so your names need to sound comfortable to the language you are writing in--this means they need to be composed of parts often used in that language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exception is if you want to give the impression that the names are foreign to the central character. For example, the hobbits and humans are the central characters of the Lord of the Rings, and so their names sound familiar, if a bit archaic, to English speakers: Aragorn, Bilbo, the Shire, Gondor. Elven and dwarven names sound more distant: Thranduil, Galadriel, Lothlorien, Gloin, Khazad-dum. This is because they are supposed to feel foreign from the perspective of the main characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example of constructing a name comfortable to English speakers:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hell -&gt; Hel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dim -&gt; Dem&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hel + Dem = Heldem&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You construct the name out of sounds of existing words, and now you may even have an idea of what the name means in your world.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2016-07-26T20:43:45.387" Id="48645" LastActivityDate="2016-07-26T20:43:45.387" OwnerUserId="13391" ParentId="48622" PostTypeId="2" Score="28"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I'm going to take a completely different approach on this one, arguing for &lt;strong&gt;Yes&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off, it's probably going to take a &lt;em&gt;long time&lt;/em&gt;, and it will require your civilization to start out pacifist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a world populated only by plants, and one species of plant has sentience as described here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://worldbuilding.stackexchange.com/a/10761/13391&quot;&gt;How could a sentient plant evolve and what conditions would be required for this evolution?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That answer mentions weapons, but I see no reason why that would necessarily be the case. If this plant civilization had no predators and their internal competition was strictly peaceful because of their strong psychological connection with one another, then they could likely maintain no need for weapons &lt;em&gt;per se&lt;/em&gt; for a long time (they might have tools to destroy other plants, but we don't really see those as weapons). Their science would develop to solve other problems besides military ones, for example disease and longevity, greater access to resources for the species as a whole, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would likely, as I said, take quite some time, but eventually this civilization will look to the cosmos for resources. They might have already noticed by this point that &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rocket-powered_aircraft&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;rockets are useful for intercontinental transportation&lt;/a&gt;. Eventually their space program will develop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, why would they develop swords, spears, and bows? Here's the fun part:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After they start exploring other worlds, they notice that some have animals, a rather unusual creature. They frequently capture small specimens for study in their own environment. Eventually, one of these specimens is actually able to take advantage of the plants for its diet. This creature reproduces quickly and becomes a pest--kind of like how rats are a pest that stowaway on ships on Earth. Having never needed weapons before, and given that the creature is a small, dumb rat, the plant civilization may well be able to develop bombs or pesticide, or engineer a contagion, but that's overkill for a small pest problem. Instead, it is easy to turn cutting edges into swords, or mount them on poles to make spears and arrows.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2016-07-29T21:01:59.323" Id="49039" LastActivityDate="2016-07-29T21:01:59.323" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:52:29.510" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="13391" ParentId="966" PostTypeId="2" Score="1"/>
  <row AnswerCount="17" Body="&lt;p&gt;The planet Earth is made up of one giant supercontinent that all of humanity live on. The landmasses are separated by jungles, deserts, mountain ranges, large rivers, and other geographical barriers. However, They are all connected through portals called Realm Gates, which are scattered thoughout the supercontinent. The portals vary in size, from those which could only transport several people at once, to larger ones that can move hundreds or even thousands. These gates exist across different different countires. Their people have their own cultures, traditions, and celebrations, but all follow one organized faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Realm Gates are controlled by the organized religion, which exists in some form across these countries on the continent. Priests are the only ones who can activate or de-activate the portals. Churches spring up around these gates, and control access to them. They are considered sacred gifts from the gods, and destroying one is considered sacrilege. The knowledge of these portals are known to the public. These gates connect to each other as well as to the Main realmgates at the country's capital. This gate controls all the other gates in the country, and connects to the realmgates of the capitals of other nations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world exists alongside a parallel reality that is equivalent to hell. This realm is filled with creatures called daemons that cross over into the world. The only thing keeping the daemons out is a thin barrier that exists between realms. This barrier is powered by human worship. Because of this, The religion wants to maintain a unified church without splitting into different factions like the monotheistic faiths of today, such as christianity and its many denominations. Since there are numerous countries on the landmass, each with its own people and cultures, it would be difficult to keep the faith consistent without causing misinterpretations and unwanted additions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can I credibly describe how this church maintains its unity across a supercontinent without splintering?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="18" CreationDate="2017-10-10T12:57:35.117" FavoriteCount="5" Id="94506" LastActivityDate="2019-02-07T02:17:26.800" LastEditDate="2018-01-17T19:39:39.573" LastEditorDisplayName="user32862" OwnerDisplayName="user32862" PostTypeId="1" Score="19" Tags="&lt;magic&gt;&lt;religion&gt;" Title="How can a religion that exists across a supercontinent maintain its unity?" ViewCount="3707"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Portals grant their operators the ability to instill the full trust of the people in anything stated &lt;em&gt;ex cathedra&lt;/em&gt;. One of the portals is the &quot;Master Portal&quot; which grants its operator the ability to instill the full trust of the other portal operators in anything stated &lt;em&gt;ex cathedra&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optionally, the &quot;Master Portal&quot; may have some built-in ability to prevent its operator from abusing its power to violate the established order. For example, if the religion is based on the portal operators electing the &quot;Master Portal&quot; operator, it may prevent the &quot;Master Portal&quot; operator from using his ability to influence elections.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2017-10-10T19:27:52.353" Id="94557" LastActivityDate="2017-10-10T19:27:52.353" OwnerUserId="13391" ParentId="94506" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="150025" AnswerCount="48" Body="&lt;p&gt;Note: this is an in-universe explanation, not media in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Media in general tends to have magic written in archaic, usually dead, languages. In my world, magic is best described as fickle; most known spells are &quot;iffy&quot; with many having unintended consequences. For example, a spell to cure a lame limb might also turn it ghostly pale or a spell to cure one's cow might cause it to also grow another tail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spells themselves are written on tablets, scrolls, etc., passed down from generation to generation within the 'Mage Families'- people who bought spells in the market, happened upon an ancient library or wizard's tower, or accumulated them over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While new copies of spells can be made, only a few select spells are seen as worth copying due to them having been used enough times to have a clear outcome and side effects. However, the spells can only work if they are transcribed exactly as written, which means writing in the ancient &quot;Magic Languages&quot;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What would be a good in-universe justification for the &quot;Magic Languages&quot; to be a series of dead languages while contemporary languages are unable to have any ability to make spells work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: by dead language I mean no one speaks it as their native language, and the Mages themselves have a very minimal understanding of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this world dreaming is a very important part of the Theology so tying in dreaming would be nice, but isn't necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brand new spells are very, very, very hard to create with only a few being made every hundred years or so. However, finding new spells is rather common.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="11" CreationDate="2019-07-01T22:53:50.643" FavoriteCount="17" Id="150022" LastActivityDate="2019-07-08T19:56:44.063" LastEditDate="2019-07-02T04:48:28.983" LastEditorUserId="62803" OwnerUserId="51720" PostTypeId="1" Score="80" Tags="&lt;magic&gt;&lt;language&gt;" Title="Why would &quot;dead languages&quot; be the only languages that spells could be written in?" ViewCount="14143"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Magic words gain their power by becoming &quot;dead&quot; words.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Magic is fueled by the psychic energy of people. When people make &quot;damn it&quot; taboo and replace it with &quot;darn it&quot;, then &quot;damn&quot; gains magical power through the psychic energy it triggers when spoken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The words don't have to be taboo, however. For example, &quot;grog&quot; gains magical power as well, because its disuse means that it evokes deep feelings when invoked, triggering the same psychic energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A dead language is thus an &lt;em&gt;entire language&lt;/em&gt; of words with magical power, and thus the optimal way to craft spells, which are more complex concepts built out of magical words.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2019-07-02T16:26:58.013" Id="150093" LastActivityDate="2019-07-02T16:26:58.013" OwnerUserId="13391" ParentId="150022" PostTypeId="2" Score="0"/>
</posts>