<?xml version="1.0" ?><posts>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="8" AnswerCount="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;Exoplanet questions and other planetary science questions seem to be valid here, on Space Exploration, and on Physics. Where do we draw the line on what is valid where?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/exoplanet&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;exoplanet&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;exoplanet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2013-09-24T19:04:06.940" Id="1" LastActivityDate="2013-09-29T22:11:17.050" LastEditDate="2013-09-29T22:11:17.050" LastEditorUserId="19" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="7" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;physics.se&gt;" Title="Where do we draw the line concerning planetary science questions?" ViewCount="109"/>
  <row AnswerCount="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;There are two major measurement units: Fahrenheit and Celsius. Us crazy American enthusiasts often use the Fahrenheit system, while the rest of the world uses primarily the Celsius (metric) system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which should we use? Should we just specify both? Or does it matter?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-09-24T19:05:22.893" FavoriteCount="1" Id="2" LastActivityDate="2013-09-29T22:08:31.457" LastEditDate="2013-09-29T22:08:31.457" LastEditorUserId="19" OwnerUserId="19" PostTypeId="1" Score="7" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;" Title="Should we use fahrenheit or celsius? Does it matter?" ViewCount="83"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I suggest we use Celsius in general, but if we are quoting or borrowing numbers from a source we should maintain their unit of choice (providing Celsius in parentheses). Fahrenheit can always be provided in parentheses for convenience.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-09-24T19:13:39.430" Id="3" LastActivityDate="2013-09-24T19:13:39.430" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="2" PostTypeId="2" Score="1"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Okay, here is my rationale, using the question that I posted &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/2/how-are-the-compositional-components-of-exoplanet-atmospheres-differentiated&quot;&gt;&quot;How are the compositional components of exoplanet atmospheres differentiated?&quot;&lt;/a&gt; s an example, which started this discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This question is asking about the scientific basis for differentiating the atmospheric spectra from the parent star, planetary surface etc.  It is an example of a question pertaining to the detection of and nature of the compositions of components of exoplanets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reasons I believe that this and similar exoplanet based questions should stay here are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The question is asking about an astronomical technique (detection of the compositions), so not necessarily Space Exploration based, as it is not about travelling there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The fact that it I asking about the atmospheric composition techniques, means that it would be bordering on off-topic for Physics&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also as a side note, some members here are not members of Space Exploration (such as myself) and some are not members of Physics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edited to add: there is another question posted about exoplanet weather &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/15/what-is-the-most-extreme-weather-found-on-another-planet&quot;&gt;&quot;What is the most extreme weather found on another planet?&quot;&lt;/a&gt; - which I believe would not match the other 2 sites at all.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2013-09-24T19:33:50.260" Id="4" LastActivityDate="2013-09-24T19:40:53.670" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:06.230" LastEditorDisplayName="user8" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerDisplayName="user8" ParentId="1" PostTypeId="2" Score="5"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;We need to be careful to avoid the English Language &amp;amp; Usage / English Language Learners problem over here. Planetary sciences is one area that is particularly fuzzy when it comes to determining what is space exploration and what is astronomy. I suggest that we need to draw a line somewhere in the middle, and we need to draw it early and stick to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions of astronomical technique in planetary sciences should belong here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions regarding rovers, satellites, etc. involved in planetary sciences should belong at SpaceEx.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I imagine there will be other things that don't clearly fall into the above two categories, and we need to figure out how to handle them.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2013-09-24T19:42:23.223" Id="5" LastActivityDate="2013-09-24T19:42:23.223" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="1" PostTypeId="2" Score="5"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;We don't need to. It's perfectly OK for sites to have an overlap. Migrations should only be done if:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The question is &lt;em&gt;off topic&lt;/em&gt; on the source site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If not, it still may be migrated on OPs request&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If it is borderline on topic on the source site and doesn't get answers, again it can be migrated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No need to draw a line. It's fine if more than one site gets a piece of the pie.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2013-09-24T19:53:29.070" Id="8" LastActivityDate="2013-09-24T19:53:29.070" OwnerUserId="28" ParentId="1" PostTypeId="2" Score="10"/>
  <row AnswerCount="7" Body="&lt;p&gt;Currently, our chatroom has the (rather unexciting) name 'Colloquium'. In my opinion, we should not be using a common ancient Roman phrase for this modern site. What should our chatroom be named?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Format:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;Foo Bar&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Because we all like to foo bars!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-09-24T20:22:11.240" FavoriteCount="2" Id="13" LastActivityDate="2013-09-29T18:13:27.700" OwnerUserId="19" PostTypeId="1" Score="10" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;chat&gt;" Title="What should our chatroom be named?" ViewCount="121"/>
  <row Body="&lt;h1&gt;The Observatory&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe too obvious, but I like it.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2013-09-24T20:24:21.413" Id="14" LastActivityDate="2013-09-24T20:24:21.413" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="13" PostTypeId="2" Score="15"/>
  <row AnswerCount="8" Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our moderators pro tempore have already been selected.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/questions/118/moderator-pro-tem-announcement&quot;&gt;Moderator Pro Tem Announcement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Original Post:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If your meta site does not have a post to nominate Moderators, start one now! Pro Tem appointments will begin about two weeks after the site is created. The more guidance we receive, the more informed our choice. &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.stackoverflow.com/2010/07/moderator-pro-tempore/&quot;&gt;Moderator Pro Tempore&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Each nomination should be a separate answer&lt;/strong&gt;. Link the name to the user’s profile (parent and meta) so we can see their activity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The nominee should indicate their acceptance by editing the answer, adding that they accept the nomination. Optionally they can write something about themselves.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self nominations are okay, and even encouraged. Most sites have not had sufficient time for many users to stand out. Self nomination is simply a way to say, “I’m interested. Let my record speak for itself.” Links to other activities may be helpful: Area 51 participation, participation in other sites, blog posts reviewing or announcing the site, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're looking for members of this site who:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a reasonably high reputation score to indicate active, consistent participation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show an interest in their meta’s community-building activities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lead by example, showing patience and respect for their fellow community members in everything they write.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exhibit those intangible traits discussed in &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.stackoverflow.com/2010/07/2009/05/a-theory-of-moderation/&quot;&gt;A Theory of Moderation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's also good if the moderators:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are members with participation in both the meta and main site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Participated in Area 51, generate social network referrals, or blog about the site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are members who have already shown an interest or ability to promote their community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;Lifted from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://space.meta.stackexchange.com/questions/60/moderator-nominations&quot;&gt;meta.space&lt;/a&gt; nomination thread.&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CommunityOwnedDate="2013-09-26T20:35:26.640" CreationDate="2013-09-26T14:32:31.297" FavoriteCount="3" Id="48" LastActivityDate="2018-12-28T23:17:09.777" LastEditDate="2017-03-16T15:52:10.620" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="19" PostTypeId="1" Score="13" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;moderators&gt;" Title="Who should our moderators be?" ViewCount="519"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I'm going to nominate &lt;strong&gt;astromax&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/users/45/astromax&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/users/flair/45.png&quot; width=&quot;208&quot; height=&quot;58&quot; alt=&quot;profile for astromax at Astronomy Stack Exchange, Q&amp;amp;A for astronomers and astrophysicists&quot; title=&quot;profile for astromax at Astronomy Stack Exchange, Q&amp;amp;A for astronomers and astrophysicists&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://stackexchange.com/users/1423264&quot;&gt;
profile for astromax on Stack Exchange, a network of free, community-driven Q&amp;amp;A sites http://stackexchange.com/users/flair/1423264.png
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meta: &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/users/45/astromax&quot;&gt;Meta Account&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Field knowledge (PhD candidate in Physics)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delivers excellent answers and knowledge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CommunityOwnedDate="2013-09-26T14:37:54.100" CreationDate="2013-09-26T14:37:54.100" Id="50" LastActivityDate="2013-09-29T00:52:37.057" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:06.230" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="48" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I want to remind everyone to be comfortable enough to stick out your own neck here. Moderating isn't really a position of self-promotion, but a position of self-dedication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, if you feel you have something to offer the community, go for it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I'm going to nominate myself, &lt;strong&gt;called2voyage&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/users/6/called2voyage&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/users/flair/6.png&quot; width=&quot;208&quot; height=&quot;58&quot; alt=&quot;profile for called2voyage at Astronomy Stack Exchange, Q&amp;amp;A for astronomers and astrophysicists&quot; title=&quot;profile for called2voyage at Astronomy Stack Exchange, Q&amp;amp;A for astronomers and astrophysicists&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://stackexchange.com/users/2359501&quot;&gt;
profile for called2voyage on Stack Exchange, a network of free, community-driven Q&amp;amp;A sites http://stackexchange.com/users/flair/2359501.png
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been a committed user over at Space Exploration for a while now, and Astronomy has always been an interest of mine.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CommunityOwnedDate="2013-09-26T15:34:09.727" CreationDate="2013-09-26T15:34:09.727" Id="53" LastActivityDate="2013-09-26T15:34:09.727" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:06.230" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="48" PostTypeId="2" Score="7"/>
  <row AnswerCount="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;We've decided to keep Astronomy Stack Exchange in PRIVATE beta for one more week.  The &lt;a href=&quot;https://meta.stackexchange.com/a/99341/1438&quot;&gt;Community Manager team&lt;/a&gt; reviewed the site so far and, while we love the enthusiasm here, we are deeply concerned that &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/questions/59/lets-ask-more-meaty-questions&quot;&gt;many of the questions&lt;/a&gt; and answers are poor or literal copies of material available elsewhere on the internet.  &lt;strong&gt;We want to make sure this is a site for people &quot;doing&quot; astronomy&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;mdash;whether you're a PhD or into backyard astronomy.  We don't want to create a site where folks are simply repeating content they heard elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me paraphrase something Joel Spolsky (Stack Exchange co-founder) &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joelonsoftware.com/items/2010/04/19.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There are only 200 easy [astronomy] questions, and they've all been asked 100 times on every other site on the subject. But there are 20,000,000 detailed, difficult, long-tail questions that only an expert can answer, and we'd be doing a REAL service to the Internet by creating a place where you can find answers to the 20,000,000 hard questions, not the 200 easy ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current list of questions comes close to being a complete set of the 200 easy questions with pitifully few of the hard ones.  Let me call out one counter-example: &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/150/how-can-i-collimate-a-dobsonian-telescope-with-a-laser-collimator&quot;&gt;How can I collimate a dobsonian telescope with a laser collimator?&lt;/a&gt;  What I love about this question is that Wipqozn clearly was trying to &lt;strong&gt;do some astronomy&lt;/strong&gt;, ran into a problem, and chose to ask here.  Then TildalWave answered the question by pulling out some equipment and taking pictures of the process to &lt;strong&gt;show how it's done&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is an odd disconnect between the questions being asked and the folks we see on the site. Many of you are working on (or actually hold) advanced degrees... or work in academia, engineering, or astronomy. If there's some misunderstanding about why we're all here during the private beta, it's time to hear from you... right now. If you're holding back waiting for the site to get better, now is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; the time to wait. Whether it's a question from your studies, or a particularly intriguing problem you might have once encountered in work... &lt;em&gt;the time to ask your question is right now&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2013-09-30T22:17:07.010" FavoriteCount="1" Id="93" LastActivityDate="2013-10-08T15:29:08.343" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:06.230" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="48" PostTypeId="1" Score="16" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;" Title="NOT READY FOR PUBLIC BETA — What function should this site serve?" ViewCount="332"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;In the words of &lt;a href=&quot;http://chat.stackexchange.com/transcript/message/11495535#11495535&quot;&gt;TildalWave&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;here, we should focus on observational science more, not so much on actually interpreting data... how to gather data, where to look for them, with what equipment, who has done what, how do we define / catalogue something, also discussing other astro societies, events, e.t.c.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think some of our highest voted questions show that we know that we need that focus:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/24/how-are-black-holes-found&quot;&gt;How are black holes found?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/94/what-is-a-parsec-and-how-is-it-measured&quot;&gt;What is a parsec and how is it measured?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/1/how-do-i-calculate-the-inclination-of-an-object-with-an-amateur-telescope&quot;&gt;How do I calculate the inclination of an object with an amateur telescope?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/16/why-is-only-one-side-of-the-moon-visible-from-earth&quot;&gt;Why is only one side of the Moon visible from Earth?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/331/how-could-a-hobbyist-astronomer-determine-apparent-magnitude-of-a-star&quot;&gt;How could a hobbyist astronomer determine apparent magnitude of a star?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/3/amateur-observing-targets-for-binary-star-systems&quot;&gt;Amateur observing targets for binary star systems?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/9/could-someone-explain-ra-dec-in-simple-terms&quot;&gt;Could someone explain RA/dec in simple terms?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/273/why-is-the-hubble-telescope-in-space&quot;&gt;Why is the Hubble Telescope in space?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/443/i-live-in-an-area-with-a-lot-of-light-pollution-how-can-i-view-the-stars-withou&quot;&gt;I live in an area with a lot of light pollution, how can I view the stars without building an observatory?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/2/how-are-the-compositional-components-of-exoplanet-atmospheres-differentiated&quot;&gt;How are the compositional components of exoplanet atmospheres differentiated?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem isn't that we don't know what we need; it's that we seem not to know how to generate a large enough volume of these types of questions. I suspect that will improve if we promote the site well enough, but that won't likely happen unless we go public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, from &lt;a href=&quot;http://chat.stackexchange.com/transcript/message/11495448#11495448&quot;&gt;TildalWave&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So if Astro is to make it, I guess we need folks that will make it what it will be. And in private beta, that might be impossible to achieve anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2013-10-02T20:57:17.650" Id="98" LastActivityDate="2013-10-02T20:57:17.650" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:06.230" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="93" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;I am just curious about why it is the case. It seems to me that it is even true when compared with Cosmology, which studies similar things. I feel that the people just want to look at stars, and I have ever met people that know what Astronomy is but not Physics. This give me an impression that Astronomy is more like an amateur field. I know it is not, and the real research often involves huge amount of data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone can give explanation to me?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2013-10-06T20:43:05.663" Id="102" LastActivityDate="2013-10-10T17:03:44.767" LastEditDate="2013-10-10T13:48:12.913" LastEditorUserId="19" OwnerUserId="172" PostTypeId="1" Score="4" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;" Title="Why is the general public more interested in Astronomy than other branches of Physics and Cosmology?" ViewCount="74"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="137" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;I went over to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackexchange.com/newsletters&quot;&gt;newsletter list&lt;/a&gt; to subscribe to our newsletter - a weekly email SE sends you containing recent popular questions, a nice way to keep up on the overall taste of the site:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/i0xQNm.png&quot; alt=&quot;enter image description here&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't know if I'm looking too soon, but a search for astronomy yields...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/sQ6i9.png&quot; alt=&quot;enter image description here&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are we going to have one? Am I jumping the gun in looking for it just a few hours after public beta opened?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2013-10-08T23:26:36.963" Id="112" LastActivityDate="2013-10-22T13:38:24.980" LastEditDate="2013-10-22T13:38:24.980" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="19" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;bug&gt;&lt;status-bydesign&gt;&lt;status-completed&gt;" Title="Do we have a newsletter?" ViewCount="64"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Cosmology is a little abstruse for some people, even astrophysics in general can often seem daunting to the general public. Atomic/molecular/optical physics, particle physics, and condensed matter physics are similarly obscure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applied physics is interesting to some people, but it is heavily dependant on what their other interests are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Astronomy on the other hand has a very old tradition, and in its simplest form just involves looking up at the night sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Space has the added benefit of being &quot;the final frontier&quot; to many, because we see Earth everyday but space is far removed from us. This makes it wondrous and mysterious.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-10-10T17:03:44.767" Id="113" LastActivityDate="2013-10-10T17:03:44.767" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="102" PostTypeId="2" Score="5"/>
  <row AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;Now that you've got moderators, you can edit &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/help/on-topic&quot;&gt;the on-topic page in your help center&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;! Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now what do you put there? Post your points in the answers below, and vote for them. &lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CommunityOwnedDate="2013-10-11T18:56:42.547" CreationDate="2013-10-11T18:54:50.127" Id="119" LastActivityDate="2014-04-11T14:39:48.123" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:06.230" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="223" PostTypeId="1" Score="4" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;on-topic&gt;" Title="What's on topic on this site?" ViewCount="183"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;This site is for the observational science of Astronomy: how to gather data, where to look for it, with what equipment, who has done what, how we define / catalogue something, also discussing other astro societies, events, e.t.c.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;I'm paraphrasing TildalWave. Feel free to edit this into a better format for the help center.&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CommunityOwnedDate="2013-10-11T19:08:40.880" CreationDate="2013-10-11T19:08:40.880" Id="120" LastActivityDate="2013-10-11T19:08:40.880" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="119" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row AnswerCount="4" Body="&lt;p&gt;Topic of the week is a week where we make an effort to ask and answer more questions around a specific tag, this brings more attention to the topic which in turn should bring us more views and users who are interested in those areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topic of the week helps us flesh out topics that look like they could use a bit more attention. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to post an answer, suggesting a tag each, maybe with some reasoning to get voted on so we can see what you would like to ask and answer more questions on. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick note, ones that might be worth suggesting could be topics around a certain event, i.e if a meteor shower is about to happen then having that as topic of the week before / during that period would obviously be very advantageous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weeks (active in bold):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;December 8-14, 2013 - &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/spectroscopy&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;spectroscopy&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;spectroscopy&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;December 15-21, 2013 - &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/amateur-observing&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;amateur-observing&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;amateur-observing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;December 21-28, 2013 - N/A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;December 29, 2013 - January 4, 2014 - &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/milky-way&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;milky-way&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;milky-way&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January 5-11, 2014&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/astrometry&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;astrometry&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;astrometry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If current week doesn't have a topic selected, then the previously week's topic stays active until a new topic is selected by votes on the suggestions in the answers below. Please vote on those answers that aren't indicated as already used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/questions/169/topic-of-the-week-archive&quot;&gt;Archived Topics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CommunityOwnedDate="2014-01-08T15:31:38.040" CreationDate="2013-10-13T06:42:42.180" FavoriteCount="2" Id="123" LastActivityDate="2014-01-07T15:45:42.383" LastEditDate="2017-03-16T15:52:10.620" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerDisplayName="user8" PostTypeId="1" Score="13" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;questions&gt;&lt;specific-question&gt;" Title="Topic of the Week: [astrometry]" ViewCount="286"/>
  <row AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;The Astro mods are considering the possibility of getting some ads put in astronomy-related magazines for Astronomy.SE. We could easily look up some popular magazines, and we probably will. But I thought I'd take a moment to ask our community, because you may make us aware of some that are important to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what (astronomy-related) magazines do you subscribe to?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Physics or science in general might be good target magazines too.)&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-10-14T13:24:27.243" Id="128" LastActivityDate="2013-10-14T14:55:23.270" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="4" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;" Title="Astronomers: What magazines do you subscribe to?" ViewCount="42"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;One magazine that I am aware of is &quot;All about space&quot; which has a fairly broad reach of about 63,000 readers, probably more since that measurement was taken. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It focuses a lot around space and planetary sciences and covers some far reaching topics such as the formation of the universe and creation of galaxies, as well as new discoveries and launches. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know it is certainly a good choice based in the UK, not sure how this compares in other countries though.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-10-14T14:55:23.270" Id="129" LastActivityDate="2013-10-14T14:55:23.270" OwnerUserId="96" ParentId="128" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row AnswerCount="6" Body="&lt;p&gt;It would be interesting if members (should they choose to) detailed their areas of interest and expertise.  Just as a very rough gauge about where the community is at with regards to Astronomy.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-10-15T10:54:40.007" FavoriteCount="1" Id="132" LastActivityDate="2013-12-10T20:43:28.300" LastEditDate="2013-11-07T20:43:16.747" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerDisplayName="user8" PostTypeId="1" Score="7" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;expertise&gt;" Title="Areas of interest and expertise of members" ViewCount="106"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expertise&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software engineering and design, project management&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Previous areas of study&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cosmology, black holes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interests&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;I'm going to list interests relevant to Space Exploration as well as here.&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Planetary sciences, colonization, astrobiology, exoplanets, cosmology&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-10-15T13:02:00.630" Id="134" LastActivityDate="2013-10-15T13:02:00.630" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="132" PostTypeId="2" Score="7"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="138" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;There have been some concerns raised about cosmology and theoretical astrophysics, as well as astrophysics in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concern is that this community does not support astrophysics questions, especially cosmology and theoretical astrophysics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you think this community can support astrophysics questions, make your case for it in an answer here. Try to bring more to bear than just &quot;I like astrophysics, and I'm a professional and I want it here.&quot; Bring existing posts (questions AND answers) to support your view. Show us why you think this community can support these types of questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And by &lt;em&gt;support&lt;/em&gt;, I mean that we actually have a sufficient userbase to &lt;strong&gt;ask and &lt;em&gt;answer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; these types of questions at an &lt;strong&gt;expert&lt;/strong&gt; level, not just show an interest in them!&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2013-10-15T16:33:20.010" FavoriteCount="1" Id="136" LastActivityDate="2013-12-12T09:23:39.713" LastEditDate="2013-11-07T20:40:38.267" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="11" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;on-topic&gt;&lt;scope&gt;" Title="How much is astrophysics, cosmology, and theoretical astrophysics on topic?" ViewCount="226"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The design team has now added &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackexchange.com/newsletters/newsletter?site=astronomy.stackexchange.com&quot;&gt;our newsletter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-10-15T17:11:15.143" Id="137" LastActivityDate="2013-10-15T17:11:15.143" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="112" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Here is a (non-exhaustive) list of astrophysical questions, with fairly good answers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/528/why-do-x-ray-binaries-such-as-grs-1915-have-active-and-quiet-states&quot;&gt;Why do X-ray binaries such as GRS-1915 have active and quiet states?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/537/why-does-the-earth-have-a-tilt-of-23&quot;&gt;Why does the Earth have a tilt of ~23&amp;#176;?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/546/why-is-our-solar-system-tipped-about-63-with-respect-to-the-plane-of-our-gala&quot;&gt;Why is our solar system &amp;quot;tipped&amp;quot; about 63&amp;#176; with respect to the plane of our galaxy?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/501/why-did-mars-lose-its-magnetic-field&quot;&gt;Why Did Mars lose its Magnetic Field?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/401/what-is-the-current-accepted-theory-for-the-fate-of-hot-jupiters&quot;&gt;What is the current accepted theory for the fate of hot Jupiters?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/381/why-is-there-a-matter-anti-matter-asymmetry-in-the-universe&quot;&gt;Why is there a matter/anti-matter asymmetry in the universe?&lt;/a&gt; (cosmology)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/362/what-is-the-current-accepted-theory-as-to-why-mercury-despite-its-size-has-a-s&quot;&gt;What is the current accepted theory as to why Mercury, despite its size, has a similar density to Earth?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/247/why-is-the-suns-atmosphere-the-corona-so-hot&quot;&gt;Why is the Sun&amp;#39;s atmosphere (the corona) so hot?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/782/two-species-of-dark-matter&quot;&gt;Two species of dark matter?&lt;/a&gt; (cosmology)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus, there are at least few people around with (or preparing) a degree in astrophysics who are able to handle this kind of questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/users/45/astromax&quot;&gt;astromax&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/users/2/guillochon&quot;&gt;guillochon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/users/86/francesco-montesano&quot;&gt;Francesco Montesano&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/users/8/uv-d&quot;&gt;UV-D&lt;/a&gt; (at least for planetary science/atmosphere)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;myself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/users/28/manishearth&quot;&gt;Manishearth&lt;/a&gt; (Currently an undergrad, has not yet decided a field but is leaning towards astrophysics)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/users/316/eduardo-guerras-valera&quot;&gt;Eduardo Guerras Valera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/users/467/freelanceastro&quot;&gt;Freelanceastro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did not check on everybody though.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="6" CreationDate="2013-10-16T12:38:44.917" Id="138" LastActivityDate="2013-12-12T09:23:39.713" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:06.230" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="88" ParentId="136" PostTypeId="2" Score="12"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="180" AnswerCount="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;We have basically three classes of geoscience questions here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Specific Geoscience Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/643/day-and-night-temperature-on-an-earthlike-planet-with-longer-rotational-period&quot;&gt;Day and night temperature on an earthlike planet with longer rotational period&lt;/a&gt; (Note: Says &quot;earth-like&quot; a few times, but the crux of the question is &quot;What would happen if Earth were tidal-locked?&quot;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/506/earth-and-ferromagnetism&quot;&gt;Earth and ferromagnetism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/706/why-is-the-earths-center-is-still-hot-after-millions-of-years&quot;&gt;Why is the Earth&amp;#39;s center still hot after millions of years?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;General Space Questions Directed at Earth&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;That is, types of questions that we very frequently ask about space objects that happen to be directed at Earth.&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/304/how-fast-do-we-travel-through-space&quot;&gt;How fast do we travel through space?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/492/why-isnt-earth-a-perfect-sphere&quot;&gt;Why isn&amp;#39;t Earth a perfect sphere?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/537/why-does-the-earth-have-a-tilt-of-23&quot;&gt;Why does the Earth have a tilt of ~23&amp;#176;?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/853/how-would-earths-climate-differ-if-its-axis-were-tilted-around-90-degrees-like&quot;&gt;How would Earth&amp;#39;s climate differ if it&amp;#39;s axis were tilted around 90 degrees like Uranus?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Questions about Earth that Involve Other Astronomical Bodies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/476/why-does-the-moon-stablize-earths-axis&quot;&gt;Why does the Moon stablize Earth&amp;#39;s axis?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/531/how-often-does-earth-cross-the-galaxy-regions-with-higher-supernovae-activity&quot;&gt;How often does Earth cross the galaxy regions with higher supernovae activity?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/334/if-the-moon-wasnt-receding-from-earth-what-would-be-the-impact-on-the-weather&quot;&gt;If the moon wasn&amp;#39;t receding from Earth, what would be the impact on the weather and tides?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/219/what-is-the-relevance-of-the-tropics-and-the-polar-circles-do-they-exist-on-oth&quot;&gt;What is the relevance of the Tropics and the Polar Circles? Do they Exist on other planets?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/604/does-the-moons-magnetic-field-affect-earths-magnetic-field&quot;&gt;Does the Moon&amp;#39;s magnetic field affect Earth&amp;#39;s magnetic field?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is easy to see why  the latter category is deemed on topic, because it involves other astronomical bodies. The middle category is somewhat more difficult. Especially the &quot;perfect sphere&quot; question, which really seems like it should belong in geoscience. The axial tilt question is of a lot more interest to astronomy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first category is the one that seems like it should be off topic. And in the case of the last question in it (&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/706/why-is-the-earths-center-is-still-hot-after-millions-of-years&quot;&gt;Why is the Earth&amp;#39;s center still hot after millions of years?&lt;/a&gt;), we have almost enough close votes from the community to close it (4 out of 5). Yet somehow the other two still managed to pass relatively unchallenged and got a number of upvotes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So here's the central question:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What stance do we take on geoscience questions?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If they are to be generally excluded from the site, how do we divide those that we include from those we don't?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you came here from a weird question on Astronomy, an explanation is in order.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have decided to allow planetary science as a topic on Astronomy.SE, which makes perfect sense. However it brings up the problem that Earth science is a special case of planetary science. Now when one thinks of geoscience they often think of geological questions, questions that frequently apply to other planets. However, geoscience in the broad sense encompasses all Earth science (just a fancy term for any science that studies stuff on Earth). This is a problem because there are a lot of Earth science questions that we probably &lt;em&gt;don't&lt;/em&gt; want here. There are milder cases (do we want plate tectonics here?), but there are also stronger cases (cockroaches...seriously?). We need to somehow draw the line between geoscience we allow and geoscience we don't. That way users don't get confused when their question is frowned upon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started my campaign of weird questions on Astronomy to draw attention to this issue. So if you are here, &lt;em&gt;please&lt;/em&gt; leave a comment or answer of how &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; think we can draw the line.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-10-21T13:19:22.780" FavoriteCount="3" Id="140" LastActivityDate="2013-12-12T07:08:01.880" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:06.230" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="8" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;scope&gt;&lt;on-topic&gt;&lt;questions&gt;" Title="How do we determine what geoscience questions are in scope?" ViewCount="309"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="155" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;On Space Exploration we had a discussion before about the use of the abbreviations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over there we decided to make our guideline: write things out in full the first time (with abbreviations in parentheses) then use abbreviations later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is our stance on abbreviations here?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-11-01T11:40:23.933" Id="154" LastActivityDate="2013-11-01T11:40:23.933" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="4" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;formatting&gt;" Title="Guideline regarding abbreviations" ViewCount="17"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I suggest that we use the same guideline as Space Exploration:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use the full terminology  the first time, with the abbreviation in parentheses, then use abbreviations later.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tags in general should avoid abbreviations except in cases where they are abundantly clear.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2013-11-01T11:40:23.933" Id="155" LastActivityDate="2013-11-01T11:40:23.933" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="154" PostTypeId="2" Score="4"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;It appears that the community has decided that &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; geoscience questions are on topic based on the retraction of close votes from the post that initiated this question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/706/why-is-the-earths-center-is-still-hot-after-millions-of-years&quot;&gt;Why is the Earth&amp;#39;s center still hot after millions of years?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-11-04T21:53:38.467" Id="157" LastActivityDate="2013-11-04T21:53:38.467" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:06.230" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="140" PostTypeId="2" Score="4"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="159" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;This question: &lt;a href=&quot;https://space.stackexchange.com/questions/2699/what-is-a-space-elevator&quot;&gt;What is a &quot;Space elevator&quot;?&lt;/a&gt; was migrated to the space exploration SE.  Whats the line between astronomy and the Space exploration SE site? The name would suggest that all space exploration questions are on topic on this site, but not vice versa. Is space exploration for technology around space travel? What kind of questions are better fit there than here on astronomy?  &lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-11-07T19:27:37.430" Id="158" LastActivityDate="2013-11-07T19:57:31.707" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:58:55.120" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="36" PostTypeId="1" Score="5" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;" Title="Why was this question migrated to space exploration?" ViewCount="33"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;You can see on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/help/on-topic&quot;&gt;on topic section&lt;/a&gt; of the help page for our site what is in scope here. A space elevator is a device (large-scale &lt;strong&gt;equipment&lt;/strong&gt;) which does not directly support astronomical observation or data gathering, so questions about it are off topic. Now, a question about how a space elevator might be used for astronomical data gathering would be on topic, though probably too speculative at this point. A question about how we might observe space elevators around other worlds would also be on topic, though that might also be too speculative.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-11-07T19:57:31.707" Id="159" LastActivityDate="2013-11-07T19:57:31.707" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:06.230" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="158" PostTypeId="2" Score="5"/>
  <row AnswerCount="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;Should we make some to help get some more traffic here from other stacks? Does anyone have design ideas?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For clarity, I am asking if we should make an ad for Astronomy.SE to put on other stacks. Astro is not ready for its own community promotion ads yet.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h3&gt;What are Community Promotion Ads?&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Community Promotion Ads are community-vetted advertisements that will
  show up on the main site, in the right sidebar. The purpose of this
  question is the vetting process. Images of the advertisements are
  provided, and community voting will enable the advertisements to be
  shown.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h3&gt;Why do we have Community Promotion Ads?&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This is a method for the community to control what gets promoted to
  visitors on the site. For example, you might promote the following
  things:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the site's twitter account&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;useful tools or resources for physics research&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;interesting articles or findings for the curious&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cool events or conferences&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;anything else your community would genuinely be interested in&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The goal is for future visitors to find out about &lt;em&gt;the stuff your
  community deems important&lt;/em&gt;. This also serves as a way to promote
  information and resources that are &lt;em&gt;relevant to your own community's
  interests&lt;/em&gt;, both for those already in the community and those yet to
  join. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h3&gt;Why do we reset the ads every year?&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Some services will maintain usefulness over the years, while other
  things will wane to allow for new faces to show up. Resetting the ads
  every year helps accommodate this, and allows old ads that have served
  their purpose to be cycled out for fresher ads for newer things. This
  helps keep the material in the ads relevant to not just the subject
  matter of the community, but to the current status of the community.
  We reset the ads once a year, every December.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The community promotion ads have no restrictions against reposting an
  ad from a previous cycle. If a particular service or ad is very
  valuable to the community and will continue to be so, it is a good
  idea to repost it. It may be helpful to give it a new face in the
  process, so as to prevent the imagery of the ad from getting stale
  after a year of exposure.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h3&gt;How does it work?&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The answers you post to this question &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; conform to the following
  rules, or they will be ignored. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;All answers should be in the exact form of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[![Tagline to show on mouseover][1]][2]
   [1]: http://image-url
   [2]: http://clickthrough-url 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Please &lt;strong&gt;do not add anything else to the body of the post&lt;/strong&gt;. If you want to discuss something, do it in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The question must always be tagged with the magic &lt;a href=&quot;/questions/tagged/community-ads&quot; class=&quot;post-tag moderator-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;community-ads&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;community-ads&lt;/a&gt; tag. In addition to enabling the
  functionality of the advertisements, this tag also pre-fills the
  answer form with the above required form.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;h3&gt;Image requirements&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The image that you create must be &lt;strong&gt;220 x 250 pixels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Must be hosted through our standard image uploader (imgur)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Must be GIF or PNG&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No animated GIFs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Absolute limit on file size of 150 KB&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2013-11-13T20:04:30.333" FavoriteCount="1" Id="161" LastActivityDate="2019-01-23T19:59:21.993" LastEditDate="2013-11-27T13:54:58.483" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="10" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;resources&gt;&lt;site-promotion&gt;&lt;stackexchange&gt;" Title="Off-site Astronomy community promotion ads" ViewCount="270"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;For questions about things specific to earth, geology, life sciences etc., many of these &quot;off-topic&quot; kinds of questions are not really off-topic; no matter how off-topic it seems, they usually are just badly worded good questions of the form:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How would this be different on a another planet/system/space, with features XYZ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2013-11-15T17:28:10.103" Id="162" LastActivityDate="2013-11-15T17:28:10.103" OwnerUserId="304" ParentId="140" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="174" AnswerCount="7" Body="&lt;p&gt;This is the archive of all Topics of the Week whose end date was more than 30 days ago. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/questions/123/topic-of-the-week-planetary-formation&quot;&gt;Return to the main Topic of the Week thread&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CommunityOwnedDate="2013-12-03T17:03:35.427" CreationDate="2013-12-03T17:03:25.097" FavoriteCount="1" Id="169" LastActivityDate="2014-01-07T15:39:12.017" LastEditDate="2017-03-16T15:52:10.620" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;" Title="Topic of the Week Archive" ViewCount="59"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/meteor&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;meteor&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;meteor&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;October 20 - October 26, 2013&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A meteor or &quot;shooting star&quot; is the visible streak of light from a meteoroid or micrometeoroid, heated and glowing from entering the Earth's atmosphere, as it sheds glowing material in its wake. Meteors typically occur in the mesosphere at altitudes between 76 km to 100 km (46–62 miles). The root word meteor comes from the Greek meteōros, meaning &quot;suspended in the air&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;from Wikipedia&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Meteor&lt;/em&gt; may also be used commonly as a shortened form of &lt;em&gt;meteoroid&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A meteoroid is a small rocky or metallic body travelling through space. Meteoroids are significantly smaller than asteroids, and range in size from small grains to 1 meter-wide objects. Most are fragments from comets or asteroids, while others are collision impact debris ejected from bodies such as the Moon or Mars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;from Wikipedia&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/348/have-we-ever-observed-a-large-asteroid-hit-the-moon&quot;&gt;Have we ever observed a large meteor hit the Moon?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/423/why-did-the-chelyabinsk-meteor-explode&quot;&gt;Why did the Chelyabinsk meteor explode?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Posted by:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/users/19/undo&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/users/flair/19.png&quot; width=&quot;208&quot; height=&quot;58&quot; alt=&quot;profile for Undo at Astronomy Meta Stack Exchange, Q&amp;amp;A about the site for astronomers and astrophysicists&quot; title=&quot;profile for Undo at Astronomy Meta Stack Exchange, Q&amp;amp;A about the site for astronomers and astrophysicists&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Upvotes: 2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CommunityOwnedDate="2013-12-03T17:07:03.727" CreationDate="2013-12-03T17:07:03.727" Id="171" LastActivityDate="2013-12-04T17:03:39.863" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:06.230" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="169" PostTypeId="2" Score="1"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/orionids&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;orionids&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;orionids&lt;/a&gt; (used &lt;strong&gt;October 20 - October 26, 2013&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Orionid meteor shower, usually shortened to the Orionids, is the most prolific meteor shower associated with Halley's Comet. The Orionids are so-called because the point they appear to come from, called the radiant, lies in the constellation Orion, but they can be seen over a large area of the sky. Orionids are an annual meteor shower which last approximately one week in late-October. In some years, meteors may occur at rates of 50-70 per hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;from Wikipedia&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suggest that this tag run next week during the Orionid meteor shower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Posted by:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/users/6/called2voyage&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/users/flair/6.png&quot; width=&quot;208&quot; height=&quot;58&quot; alt=&quot;profile for called2voyage at Astronomy Meta Stack Exchange, Q&amp;amp;A about the site for astronomers and astrophysicists&quot; title=&quot;profile for called2voyage at Astronomy Meta Stack Exchange, Q&amp;amp;A about the site for astronomers and astrophysicists&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Upvotes: 2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CommunityOwnedDate="2013-12-03T17:08:30.517" CreationDate="2013-12-03T17:08:30.517" Id="172" LastActivityDate="2013-12-04T17:04:00.553" LastEditDate="2017-03-16T15:52:10.620" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="169" PostTypeId="2" Score="0"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/cmb&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;cmb&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;cmb&lt;/a&gt; (cosmic microwave background radiation) (used &lt;strong&gt;October 27 - November 2, 2013&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The cosmic microwave background (CMB) is the thermal radiation left over from the &quot;Big Bang&quot; of cosmology. In older literature, the CMB is also variously known as cosmic microwave background radiation (CMBR) or &quot;relic radiation.&quot; The CMB is a cosmic background radiation that is fundamental to observational cosmology because it is the oldest light in the universe, dating to the epoch of recombination. With a traditional optical telescope, the space between stars and galaxies (the background) is completely dark. However, a sufficiently sensitive radio telescope shows a faint background glow, almost exactly the same in all directions, that is not associated with any star, galaxy, or other object. This glow is strongest in the microwave region of the radio spectrum. The CMB's serendipitous discovery in 1964 by American radio astronomers Arno Penzias and Robert Wilson was the culmination of work initiated in the 1940s, and earned the discoverers the 1978 Nobel Prize.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The CMB is a snapshot of the oldest light in our Universe, imprinted on the sky when the Universe was just 380,000 years old. It shows tiny temperature fluctuations that correspond to regions of slightly different densities, representing the seeds of all future structure: the stars and galaxies of today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;from Wikipedia&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/475/what-is-the-mass-of-hotspots-in-the-cosmic-microwave-background-radiation&quot;&gt;What is the mass of hotspots in the Cosmic Microwave Background radiation?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/447/future-of-cmb-observations-what-will-change-of-our-knowledge-about-the-first-ph&quot;&gt;Future of CMB observations: How will our knowledge of the early universe change?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Posted by:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/users/19/undo&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/users/flair/19.png&quot; width=&quot;208&quot; height=&quot;58&quot; alt=&quot;profile for Undo at Astronomy Meta Stack Exchange, Q&amp;amp;A about the site for astronomers and astrophysicists&quot; title=&quot;profile for Undo at Astronomy Meta Stack Exchange, Q&amp;amp;A about the site for astronomers and astrophysicists&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Upvotes: 3&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CommunityOwnedDate="2013-12-03T17:20:19.140" CreationDate="2013-12-03T17:20:19.140" Id="173" LastActivityDate="2013-12-04T17:04:21.053" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:06.230" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="169" PostTypeId="2" Score="0"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Index:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;October 20-26, 2013 - &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/meteor&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;meteor&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;meteor&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/orionids&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;orionids&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;orionids&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/a/171/6&quot;&gt;meteor nomination&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/a/172/6&quot;&gt;orionids nomination&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;October 27-Nov 2, 2013 - &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/cmb&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;cmb&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;cmb&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/a/173/6&quot;&gt;cmb nomination&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;November 10-16, 2013 - &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/dwarf-planets&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;dwarf-planets&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;dwarf-planets&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/stellar-dynamics&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;stellar-dynamics&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;stellar-dynamics&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/a/200/6&quot;&gt;dwarf planets nomination&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/a/201/6&quot;&gt;stellar dynamics nomination&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;November 24-30, 2013 - &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/planetary-formation&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;planetary-formation&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;planetary-formation&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/a/202/6&quot;&gt;planetary formation nomination&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CommunityOwnedDate="2013-12-03T18:00:35.507" CreationDate="2013-12-03T18:00:35.507" Id="174" LastActivityDate="2014-01-07T15:39:12.017" LastEditDate="2017-03-16T15:52:10.620" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="19" ParentId="169" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/spectroscopy&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;spectroscopy&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;spectroscopy&lt;/a&gt; (used &lt;strong&gt;December 8-14, 2013&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Astronomical spectroscopy is the technique of spectroscopy used in astronomy. The object of study is the spectrum of electromagnetic radiation, including visible light, which radiates from stars and other hot celestial objects. Spectroscopy can be used to derive many properties of distant stars and galaxies, such as their chemical composition, temperature, density, mass, distance, luminosity, and relative motion using Doppler shift measurements.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Astronomical spectroscopy can be broken down into three major bands: optical, radio, and X-ray. While all spectroscopy looks at specific areas of the spectrum, different methods are required to acquire the signal depending on the frequency/wavelength. Ozone (O3) and molecular oxygen (O2) absorb light with wavelengths under 300 nm, meaning that X-ray and ultraviolet spectroscopy require the use of a satellite telescope and/or rocket mounted detectors. Radio signals have much longer wavelengths than optical signals, and require the use of antennas or radio dishes. Infrared light is absorbed by atmospheric water and carbon dioxide, so while the equipment is similar to that used in optical spectroscopy, satellites are required to record much of the infrared spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt; from Wikipedia &lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/1013/how-does-one-determine-the-effective-temperature-of-a-star-from-its-spectrum&quot;&gt;How does one determine the effective temperature of a star from its spectrum?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/997/how-well-can-we-in-principle-determine-t-textrmeff-of-a-star&quot;&gt;How well can we in principle determine $T_{\textrm{eff}}$ of a star?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CommunityOwnedDate="2014-01-08T15:31:38.040" CreationDate="2013-12-09T21:31:30.243" Id="175" LastActivityDate="2014-01-07T15:45:08.727" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:06.230" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="123" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row Body="&lt;h1&gt;Backyard astronomy: &quot;Reflections&quot;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is to present astronomy as an activity available to everyone. The Moonrise is exaggerated in size to suggest magnification of even the hobbyist grade equipment like the ones depicted (refractor, reflector and binoculars), the numerous observers represent the helping community of people sharing same passion, and reflections in water represent experience. Strong, contrasting colors and shadows are intentional to help improve ad's visual impact. The main font used is &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fontspace.com/john-stracke/rockets&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&quot;Rockets&quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; in golden color of Moon's reflection and white &lt;em&gt;&quot;Man on the Moon&quot;&lt;/em&gt; O's decor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ad hypertext:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[![Astronomy Stack Exchange][1]][2]
  [1]: http://i.stack.imgur.com/HQ5S2.png
  [2]: https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Main image:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/SwXzD.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/HQ5S2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Space Exploration Stack Exchange&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/SwXzD.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Click for poster size (880x1000 px)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Posted on:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the Stack Exchange websites that the ad is currently competing for rotation frequency with other advertised community promotion ads:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stats.meta.stackexchange.com/questions/1865/community-promotion-ads-2014/1869#1869&quot;&gt;Cross Validated&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.meta.stackexchange.com/questions/5263/community-promotion-ads-2014/5295#5295&quot;&gt;Physics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://rpg.meta.stackexchange.com/questions/3222/community-promotion-ads-2014/3231#3231&quot;&gt;Role-playing Games&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://scifi.meta.stackexchange.com/questions/3239/community-promotion-ads-2014/3254#3254&quot;&gt;Science Fiction &amp;amp; Fantasy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional locations where &lt;em&gt;Backyard astronomy: &quot;Reflections&quot;&lt;/em&gt; will compete will be posted as the list updates. If you'll be adding this ad to any other location that could use our community support with votes, please mention location where you posed it in the comments below. Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Alternative variants:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are some of the prepared design previews that are a product of the work in progress. Feel free to use them for &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/&quot;&gt;Astronomy.SE&lt;/a&gt; promotion at your discretion:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/qtaxY.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/VEEG9.png&quot; alt=&quot;enter image description here&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/qtaxY.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://i.stack.imgur.com/VEEG9.png&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-12-10T10:03:24.420" Id="177" LastActivityDate="2013-12-11T01:38:13.437" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:06.230" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="13" ParentId="161" PostTypeId="2" Score="5"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Earth science, unless directly related to phenomena observable on other celestials, Solar system in general of which Earth is a constituent part, or as an origin of observational astronomy where its movement, local and global phenomena might affect observations and measurements in any way, is off-topic on &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/&quot;&gt;Astronomy&lt;/a&gt; but can be asked on &lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/&quot;&gt;Physics&lt;/a&gt; now or &lt;a href=&quot;http://area51.stackexchange.com/proposals/36296/geoscience&quot;&gt;Geoscience&lt;/a&gt; once this Stack Exchange site proposal reaches public beta.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2013-12-12T04:41:29.573" Id="180" LastActivityDate="2013-12-12T07:08:01.880" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:06.230" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="13" ParentId="140" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row AnswerCount="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;The site intend to be a Q&amp;amp;A site for astronomers and astrophysicists, even though amateur questions are welcome. It therefore seems to me that, since it is a &quot;science professional&quot; site, we should stick to scientists habits, that require to either source or mathematically demonstrate any statement. It seems to me that there are slightly to many answers that are either &quot;Wikipedia-based&quot; or without any proper reference at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Questions&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Am I the only one to perceive that as a problem?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What could/should we do to encourage members to source their answers? (if we consider that something is to be done)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="7" CreationDate="2013-12-13T15:20:22.737" Id="181" LastActivityDate="2014-09-23T00:12:29.043" OwnerUserId="88" PostTypeId="1" Score="4" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;" Title="Reference policy" ViewCount="157"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I think the best course of action is to downvote unsourced or poorly sourced answers, and make a comment regarding how the answer can be improved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, for users who are new to the site, you may choose to comment and talk to them before downvoting, but if their question or answer remains unchanged for a while you should either downvote or improve yourself. Otherwise, the Stack Exchange model for quality will fail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on how this is in line with the Stack Exchange system, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://gamedev.meta.stackexchange.com/questions/496/what-is-the-exact-meaning-of-a-downvote-upvote/497#497&quot;&gt;What is the exact meaning of a downvote/upvote?&lt;/a&gt;. Relevant portion:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The goal of voting is to help steer people on the site to do the right kind of behavior you think should be on the site by rewarding the user with points and by sorting their content to the top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
" CommentCount="12" CreationDate="2013-12-13T15:27:10.227" Id="182" LastActivityDate="2014-04-14T15:57:55.627" LastEditDate="2017-03-16T15:43:58.153" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="181" PostTypeId="2" Score="1"/>
  <row Body="&lt;h2&gt;Ask the Universe&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bottom line&lt;/strong&gt;: emphasize the balance between enthusiasts &amp;amp; professionals: it's not that hard to observe such a large Moon, but if you want to get any more details, better ask professionals and their big toys. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;&lt;strong&gt;Ask the Universe&lt;/strong&gt;&quot;: come on astro.SE to ask any question about the Universe. And these radiotelescopes are also, in their own way, used to ask the Universe fundamental questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  [![Astronomy Stack Exchange] [1]][2]
  [1]: http://i.stack.imgur.com/44G6J.png
  [2]: http://astronomy.stackexchange.com/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/44G6J.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Font&lt;/strong&gt;: Linux Biolinum (plus an home-made &quot;A&quot;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moon&lt;/strong&gt;: adapted from a picture I took of the full Moon on December, 2012&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Radiotelescopes&lt;/strong&gt;: adapted from &lt;a href=&quot;http://apod.nasa.gov/apod/ap080310.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;this APOD picture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Posted on:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stats.meta.stackexchange.com/a/1879/35976&quot;&gt;Cross Validated&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://rpg.meta.stackexchange.com/a/3240/7890&quot;&gt;Role-playing Games&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-12-16T15:19:59.823" Id="183" LastActivityDate="2013-12-16T16:27:13.527" LastEditDate="2017-03-16T16:03:02.777" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="88" ParentId="161" PostTypeId="2" Score="5"/>
  <row AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/1266/internet-resource-which-register-all-ultra-long-gamma-ray-bursts#question&quot;&gt;This question&lt;/a&gt; has been flagged as possibly being off topic with the reason &quot;Request for an external resource - normally considered off topic on other sites.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of this specific question, I am inclined to leave it, more because of the quality of the answer than of the question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, in general should they be regarded as on or off topic?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-12-31T17:02:56.407" Id="195" LastActivityDate="2014-02-05T20:34:37.120" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:06.230" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="38" PostTypeId="1" Score="6" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;on-topic&gt;" Title="External resource questions on Astronomy" ViewCount="130"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="208" AnswerCount="4" Body="&lt;p&gt;We all love &lt;a href=&quot;http://astronomy.stackexchange.com&quot;&gt;Astronomy Stack Exchange&lt;/a&gt;, but there is a whole world of people out there who need answers to their questions and don't even know that this site exists. When they arrive from Google, what will their first impression be? Let's try to look at this site through the eyes of someone who's never seen it before, and see how we stack up against the rest of the 'Net.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/review/site-eval&quot;&gt;Site Self-Evaluation review queue&lt;/a&gt; is open and populated with 10 questions that were asked and answered in the last quarter. 
Run a few Google searches to see how easy they are to find and compare the answers we have with the information available on other sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rating the questions is only a part of the puzzle, though. Do you see a pattern of questions that should have been closed but are not? Questions or answers that could use an edit? Anything that's going really well? &lt;strong&gt;Post an answer below to share your thoughts&lt;/strong&gt; and discuss these questions and the site's health with your fellow users!&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2014-01-07T03:01:05.867" Id="199" LastActivityDate="2014-01-24T17:50:39.227" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:06.230" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="-1" PostTypeId="1" Score="4" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;site-evaluation&gt;" Title="Let's get critical: Jan 2014 Site Self-Evaluation" ViewCount="109"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/dwarf-planets&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;dwarf-planets&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;dwarf-planets&lt;/a&gt; (used &lt;strong&gt;November 10 - November 16, 2013&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A dwarf planet is a planetary-mass object that is neither a planet nor a satellite. More explicitly, the International Astronomical Union (IAU) defines a dwarf planet as a celestial body in direct orbit of the Sun that is massive enough for its shape to be controlled by gravitation, but that unlike a planet has not cleared its orbital region of other objects. The term dwarf planet was adopted in 2006 as part of a three-way categorization of bodies orbiting the Sun, brought about by an increase in discoveries of trans-Neptunian objects that rivaled Pluto in size, and finally precipitated by the discovery of an even more massive object, Eris. This classification states that bodies large enough to have cleared the neighbourhood of their orbit are defined as planets, while those that are not massive enough to be rounded by their own gravity are defined as small Solar System bodies. Dwarf planets come in between.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt; from Wikipedia &lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/212/what-physical-features-determine-if-a-planet-is-a-major-minor-or-dwarf-planet&quot;&gt;What physical features determine if a planet is a major, minor or dwarf planet?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/539/how-many-planets-are-there-in-this-solar-system&quot;&gt;How many planets are there in this solar system?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Posted by:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/users/19/undo&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/users/flair/19.png&quot; width=&quot;208&quot; height=&quot;58&quot; alt=&quot;profile for Undo at Astronomy Meta Stack Exchange, Q&amp;amp;A about the site for astronomers and astrophysicists&quot; title=&quot;profile for Undo at Astronomy Meta Stack Exchange, Q&amp;amp;A about the site for astronomers and astrophysicists&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Upvotes: 1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CommunityOwnedDate="2014-01-07T15:25:36.187" CreationDate="2014-01-07T15:25:36.187" Id="200" LastActivityDate="2014-01-07T15:25:36.187" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:06.230" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="169" PostTypeId="2" Score="0"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/stellar-dynamics&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;stellar-dynamics&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;stellar-dynamics&lt;/a&gt; (used &lt;strong&gt;November 10 - November 16, 2013&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Stellar dynamics is the branch of astrophysics which describes in a statistical way the collective motions of stars subject to their mutual gravity. The essential difference from celestial mechanics is that each star contributes more or less equally to the total gravitational field, whereas in celestial mechanics the pull of a massive body dominates any satellite orbits. Stellar dynamics is usually concerned with the more global, statistical properties of several orbits rather than with the specific data on the positions and velocities of individual orbits. The motion of stars in a galaxy or in a globular cluster are principally determined by the average distribution of the other, distant stars, and little influenced by the nearest stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt; from Wikipedia &lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/214/relativistic-effects-in-stellar-dynamical-systems&quot;&gt;Relativistic effects in stellar dynamical systems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Posted by:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/users/6/called2voyage&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/users/flair/6.png&quot; width=&quot;208&quot; height=&quot;58&quot; alt=&quot;profile for called2voyage at Astronomy Meta Stack Exchange, Q&amp;amp;A about the site for astronomers and astrophysicists&quot; title=&quot;profile for called2voyage at Astronomy Meta Stack Exchange, Q&amp;amp;A about the site for astronomers and astrophysicists&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Upvotes: 1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CommunityOwnedDate="2014-01-07T15:29:52.713" CreationDate="2014-01-07T15:29:52.713" Id="201" LastActivityDate="2014-01-07T15:29:52.713" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:06.230" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="169" PostTypeId="2" Score="0"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/planetary-formation&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;planetary-formation&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;planetary-formation&lt;/a&gt; (used &lt;strong&gt;November 24-30, 2013&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In cosmogony, the nebular hypothesis is the most widely accepted model explaining the formation and evolution of the Solar System. There is evidence that it was first proposed in 1734 by Emanuel Swedenborg. Originally applied only to our own Solar System, this method of planetary system formation is now thought to be at work throughout the universe. The widely accepted modern variant of the nebular hypothesis is Solar Nebular Disk Model (SNDM) or simply Solar Nebular Model.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;According to the nebular hypothesis, stars form in massive and dense clouds of molecular hydrogen—giant molecular clouds (GMC). They are gravitationally unstable, and matter coalesces to smaller denser clumps within, which then proceed to collapse and form stars. Star formation is a complex process, which always produces a gaseous protoplanetary disk around the young star. This may give birth to planets in certain circumstances, which are not well known. Thus the formation of planetary systems is thought to be a natural result of star formation. A sun-like star usually takes around 100 million years to form.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The protoplanetary disk is an accretion disk which proceeds to feed the central star. Initially very hot, the disk later cools in what is known as the T tauri star stage; here, formation of small dust grains made of rocks and ices is possible. The grains may eventually coagulate into kilometer-sized planetesimals. If the disk is massive enough the runaway accretions begin, resulting in the rapid—100,000 to 300,000 years—formation of Moon- to Mars-sized planetary embryos. Near the star, the planetary embryos go through a stage of violent mergers, producing a few terrestrial planets. The last stage takes around 100 million to a billion years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;from Wikipedia&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/1023/why-havent-asteroid-belts-turned-into-new-large-bodies&quot;&gt;Why haven&amp;#39;t asteroid belts turned into new large bodies?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/1005/can-protoplanetary-disks-form-main-sequence-stars&quot;&gt;Can protoplanetary disks form main-sequence stars?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/987/generalised-planets&quot;&gt;Generalised planets?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Posted by:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/users/6/called2voyage&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/users/flair/6.png&quot; width=&quot;208&quot; height=&quot;58&quot; alt=&quot;profile for called2voyage at Astronomy Meta Stack Exchange, Q&amp;amp;A about the site for astronomers and astrophysicists&quot; title=&quot;profile for called2voyage at Astronomy Meta Stack Exchange, Q&amp;amp;A about the site for astronomers and astrophysicists&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Upvotes: 1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CommunityOwnedDate="2014-01-07T15:37:59.563" CreationDate="2014-01-07T15:37:59.563" Id="202" LastActivityDate="2014-01-07T15:37:59.563" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:06.230" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="169" PostTypeId="2" Score="0"/>
  <row AnswerCount="0" Body="&lt;p&gt;I notice that it comes up a lot around here and Space Exploration that someone seems to have a misconception regarding the &quot;dark side of the moon&quot;. Would it be beneficial to our community to have a self-answered question addressing this to point people to from both Space Exploration and Astronomy?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2014-01-08T15:36:46.260" Id="205" LastActivityDate="2014-01-08T15:56:30.270" LastEditDate="2014-01-08T15:56:30.270" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerDisplayName="called2voyage" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;questions&gt;" Title="Would we benefit from having a self-answered question explaining why the &quot;dark side of the moon&quot; terminology is confusing?" ViewCount="32"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I think resource requests should be treated, for the most part, like list questions. If there is a way to produce a finite, best quality list of resources, then the question is good. If the only problem is that the list might increase over time, it might be worthwhile making a community wiki question. Otherwise, it should be closed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These types of questions should be careful to cite the resources as fully as possible (title, author, publication data, etc.) so that it is possible to track down the resource (links to amazon pages or other webpages showing the resource are not sufficient because they are subject to link rot). For web-based resources, check the Wayback Machine and make sure they are cataloged before adding to the answer. This way if the pages go down, there is a backup reference.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2014-01-09T21:30:00.247" Id="206" LastActivityDate="2014-01-09T21:30:00.247" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="195" PostTypeId="2" Score="4"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;My two cents: we may have a lot of improvement to be done to make our Q&amp;amp;A better, but lately we have had a lot more visitors and a lot more posts with a solid curiosity for diverse and interesting topics. I think the site is doing well and will continue to do better; especially if we strive to improve where we can.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2014-01-13T16:28:18.250" Id="207" LastActivityDate="2014-01-13T16:28:18.250" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="199" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;In other Stack Exchanges, when I click on the summary vote count it resolves into how many upvotes vs downvotes.  This doesn't work in Astronomy.  Is this something that is disabled for this SE?  &lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2014-01-15T17:42:12.443" FavoriteCount="1" Id="211" LastActivityDate="2014-01-16T10:35:09.967" LastEditDate="2014-01-16T10:35:09.967" LastEditorUserId="817" OwnerUserId="718" PostTypeId="1" Score="4" Tags="&lt;support&gt;&lt;voting&gt;" Title="Why can't I click on the up/down vote counter to see how the breakdown looks?" ViewCount="46"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Clicking on the counter to see the breakdown is an ability that you get at a higher rep level. If you check out your privileges page, you will see that you get that ability at 750 rep.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2014-01-15T17:49:39.140" Id="212" LastActivityDate="2014-01-15T17:49:39.140" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="211" PostTypeId="2" Score="8"/>
  <row AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;I posted a comment to &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/a/647/1050&quot;&gt;this answer&lt;/a&gt;. It was about the irrelevance of giving numbers in 18 significant digits, especially if one of the factors for the calculation only has 4 significant digits. I thought this comment was to the point, especially if the site wants to be professional, and IIRC it also had a couple of votes. I just wonder why it was removed (together with a reply to it).&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2014-02-23T17:13:04.740" FavoriteCount="1" Id="221" LastActivityDate="2014-02-24T16:42:44.960" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:06.230" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="1050" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;" Title="Why was my comment removed?" ViewCount="60"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;It was requested that the comment thread be removed because it was degenerating into argument without any action being taken, or needing to be taken. If you feel the significant digit issue still needs to be dealt with, you can suggest an edit to the answer or post your own.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2014-02-24T16:42:44.960" Id="224" LastActivityDate="2014-02-24T16:42:44.960" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="221" PostTypeId="2" Score="6"/>
  <row AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/2096/why-is-there-a-daily-inequality-for-low-tides&quot;&gt;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/2096/why-is-there-a-daily-inequality-for-low-tides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I understand the reason for asking this question on Astronomy. The OP likely assumed that the answer to his question had something to do with gravitational influence of astronomical bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, the question is about tides on Earth and the answer is Earth science based. Robert Cartaino has correctly pointed out that this should lead to it being off topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because this question is of reasonably good quality and already has a couple of good answers, my inclination is to leave it alone for now then migrate it to Earth Science once it hits beta (an assumption, I know, but I think it is a pretty good one).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does the community think?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2014-04-02T13:53:03.157" Id="227" LastActivityDate="2014-04-02T20:09:01.893" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:06.230" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;questions&gt;&lt;specific-question&gt;" Title="Question on daily inequality for tides" ViewCount="55"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I agree it to be mainly geoscience; Moon and Sun trigger tides, but the physics implied is much more complex, and may trigger a couple of follow-up questions in Earth Science clearly off topic in Astronomy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leaving it here (in the meanwhile) is ok for me.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2014-04-02T14:06:50.987" Id="228" LastActivityDate="2014-04-02T20:09:01.893" LastEditDate="2014-04-02T20:09:01.893" LastEditorUserId="746" OwnerUserId="746" ParentId="227" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;One of the custom off-topic close reasons on this site currently reads as follows: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Questions about Earth science, unless directly related to phenomena observable on other celestials, Solar system in general of which Earth is a part, or as an origin of observational astronomy where its movement, local/global phenomena might affect observations and measurements, is off-topic. For more information, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/questions/140/how-do-we-determine-what-geoscience-questions-are-in-scope&quot;&gt;the meta discussion&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that &lt;a href=&quot;https://earthscience.stackexchange.com/&quot;&gt;Earth Science&lt;/a&gt; has been in public beta for a little while, I would like to suggest that the close reason be edited to include a link to earthscience.SE. Perhaps something like this (changes in bold, most of which is just copyediting besides the added last sentence):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Questions about Earth science, unless directly related to phenomena observable on other &lt;strong&gt;celestial bodies&lt;/strong&gt;, the Solar &lt;strong&gt;System&lt;/strong&gt; in general of which Earth is a part, &lt;strong&gt;or observational astronomy&lt;/strong&gt; where &lt;strong&gt;the Earth's&lt;/strong&gt; movement &lt;strong&gt;or&lt;/strong&gt; local/global phenomena might affect observations and measurements, &lt;strong&gt;are&lt;/strong&gt; off-topic. For more information, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/questions/140/how-do-we-determine-what-geoscience-questions-are-in-scope&quot;&gt;the meta discussion&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;You may be able to get help at &lt;a href=&quot;https://earthscience.stackexchange.com/&quot;&gt;Earth Science Stack Exchange&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2014-05-27T03:25:22.153" Id="235" LastActivityDate="2014-05-27T22:24:36.197" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:50:29.583" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="325" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;close-reasons&gt;" Title="Should a link to earthscience.SE be added to the custom off-topic close reason?" ViewCount="39"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I'm not sure how I feel about that. It may encourage cross-posting over migration, but on the other hand not everything that we close with that close reason do we want to migrate--yet the OP is certainly free to attempt posting it at Earth Science to see how it is received. I'll let some others weigh in on this.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2014-05-27T21:35:33.027" Id="236" LastActivityDate="2014-05-27T21:35:33.027" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="235" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;I want to ask a question asking for book recommendations (specifically an introductory text on cosmology for advanced undergrad/beginning grad level).  I am wondering what the policy is for asking for book recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2014-05-27T23:52:47.113" Id="237" LastActivityDate="2014-05-28T13:48:33.267" OwnerUserId="128" PostTypeId="1" Score="5" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;support&gt;" Title="Policy on asking for book recommendations" ViewCount="44"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Just be careful with recommendation questions that your requirements are pretty narrow. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What is the best cosmology textbook?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above is too broad and subjective. The following is better:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What introductory texts on cosmology for advanced undergrad or beginning grad level would satisfy X, Y, Z needs of mine?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What introductory texts on cosmology for advanced undergrad or beginning grad level would contain X, Y, Z information I'm looking for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2014-05-28T13:48:33.267" Id="238" LastActivityDate="2014-05-28T13:48:33.267" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="237" PostTypeId="2" Score="5"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="240" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;I was browsing through the list of silver badges. And I came across a few explanations to which are not that easy to understand. For example, &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Silver badge : TENACIOUS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It says: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Zero score accepted answers: more than 5 and 20% of total.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't get it. What is it exactly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many other explanations are not that obvious too. They need to be more explained, I guess. I hope I am at the right platform asking the right question.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2014-06-18T05:36:05.820" Id="239" LastActivityDate="2014-06-18T12:08:56.763" OwnerUserId="1702" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;support&gt;&lt;badges&gt;" Title="silver badge tenacious" ViewCount="36"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;If you post all of the ones that need an explanation, I will expand this answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That description you posted means that your answers that were accepted yet have a zero score (no votes, or upvotes and downvotes cancel out) represent 20% of your total answers. There must be more than 5 of these to get the badge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does that make sense?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2014-06-18T12:08:56.763" Id="240" LastActivityDate="2014-06-18T12:08:56.763" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="239" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="244" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;I have been going through some questions on &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/&quot;&gt;astronomy.stackexchange.com&lt;/a&gt; and noticed that some questions were merged from &lt;a href=&quot;http://space.stackexchange.com&quot;&gt;space.stackexchange.com&lt;/a&gt; and vise versa. My question is simply what is the difference? Would it be a good idea to combine the two websites? If not, why not? &lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2014-07-23T19:35:42.157" Id="243" LastActivityDate="2014-07-23T20:55:36.080" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:06.230" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="65" PostTypeId="1" Score="1" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;" Title="What is the difference between astronomy and space stack exchange websites?" ViewCount="153"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Space exploration is an enterprise, but Astronomy is a study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As specifically mentioned in the Space Exploration &lt;a href=&quot;https://space.stackexchange.com/help/on-topic&quot;&gt;help center&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Space Exploration is primarily about spacecraft, how to send them to space, and their functions there. Specifically, questions on these topics are encouraged.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Space exploration&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Satellite design and operation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Systems with potential use in space&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scientific discoveries made by space probes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Questions these topics (and many others) are not on topic here:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The study of exosolar objects, except as they relate to space travel.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Physical sciences, such as geology, astronomy, meteorology, except as they relate to spacecraft and space exploration.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here on Astronomy we explain in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/help/on-topic&quot;&gt;help center&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Astronomy Stack Exchange is a Question and Answer site about astronomy and astronomy related topics; the study of objects and matter outside the Earth's atmosphere and of their physical and chemical properties&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The purpose of this site is to provide expert level answers to questions on:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Setting up, using and maintaining your astronomy related equipment&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Astronomical observations, for all celestial objects across the entire spectral range.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Astrophysics and Cosmology &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Planetary Science and Celestial mechanics&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data returned by space missions such as probes, rovers and satellites&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What type of equipment will allow you to see a certain entity&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What questions are off topic here?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earth science, unless directly related to phenomena observable on other celestials, Solar system in general of which Earth is a constituent part, or as an origin of observational astronomy where its movement, local and global phenomena might affect observations and measurements in any way, is off-topic on Astronomy but can be asked on Physics now or Geoscience once this Stack Exchange site proposal reaches public beta.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Questions about maintenance and general use-age of equipment such as the Curiosity Rover. A question &lt;strong&gt;can&lt;/strong&gt; be about data returned by these pieces of equipment, such as atmospheric composition and planetary composition, but questions about the tools on the rover or how the rover cleans its solar panel are off-topic&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Questions that are purely hypothetical, for example a question such as 'Could a black hole destroy the universe' or 'What if our solar system had two suns'&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Questions about artificial satellites whose purpose is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; directly related to astronomy. You &lt;em&gt;may&lt;/em&gt; ask about their orbit, but &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; their purpose, use-age and safety features&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Questions asking for a specific brand or model of telescope, these are very time and opinion specific and are likely to incite debate&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important that we have these distinctions because these two areas are separate in the career world as well. They certainly have a large degree of overlap, but Space Exploration has a strong engineering emphasis whereas Astronomy has a strong science emphasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Space Exploration has a strong enough following to hold itself as a separate area, and Astronomy is growing a similar base.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2014-07-23T20:16:10.353" Id="244" LastActivityDate="2014-07-23T20:55:36.080" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:06.230" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="243" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;In particular, PyRAF is a tool for analyzing spectra. Aside from &lt;a href=&quot;http://stsdas.stsci.edu/pyraf.new/doc/pyraf_tutorial/Unimplemented.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;its documentation&lt;/a&gt; there are few online resources about it, and no question and answer sites for it. Can the Astronomy Stack Exchange fill that gap?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proposed question: After installing PyRAF with 
        &lt;code&gt;$pip install stsci.distutils&lt;/code&gt; and
        &lt;code&gt;$pip install stscipython&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I try to run it with &lt;code&gt;$pyraf&lt;/code&gt; or, in python, &lt;code&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; import pyraf&lt;/code&gt;. Both actions give a &lt;code&gt;segmentation fault: 11&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I install the software so that it will run properly?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2015-06-17T18:15:46.317" Id="299" LastActivityDate="2015-06-17T19:31:46.660" OwnerDisplayName="user5341" PostTypeId="1" Score="5" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;specific-question&gt;" Title="Are questions about installing astronomy-related python packages on topic?" ViewCount="82"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I see no reason that such a question couldn't be asked here since our relevant topics include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Setting up, using and maintaining your astronomy related equipment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software could be viewed in a sense as virtual equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, if the software package were not astronomy specific it would not be on topic. There is the risk that the answer to the question is not specific to that particular software package, but I don't think that is a good reason to deem the question irrelevant.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2015-06-17T19:31:46.660" Id="300" LastActivityDate="2015-06-17T19:31:46.660" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="299" PostTypeId="2" Score="6"/>
  <row AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;Does this site (meaning the actual site, not the meta site) have a FAQ? I notice several questions are asked repeatedly, and it might be nice to have a prominently displayed FAQ.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2015-10-21T17:15:00.600" FavoriteCount="2" Id="309" LastActivityDate="2017-08-03T04:10:39.133" LastEditDate="2016-09-06T20:37:51.973" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="21" PostTypeId="1" Score="8" Tags="&lt;feature-request&gt;&lt;status-bydesign&gt;" Title="Do we have a FAQ?" ViewCount="483"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;What kinds of questions? You mean like posts on the main site? Normally, the course of action with these is to close as duplicate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In cases like &quot;where can I find the positions of the planets tonight&quot; or &quot;where can I find a catalog of stars&quot; or &quot;how can I visualize what tonight's sky will look like&quot; the titles are certainly generic enough to have one canonical post (not necessarily one canonical answer, one post can have multiple answers). If the body of the posts is actually more specific than the title, than either the title should be edited to be more specific or the body should be edited to be more generic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is possible to answer &quot;where can I see Venus&quot; in a way that is more specific than &quot;how can I see what the sky looks like tonight&quot;. Regardless, there are some cases where it is appropriate to ask the user to broaden the question. Creating a question just to provide a canonical answer is not looked well upon on all SE sites--each site handles it differently. Maybe propose that as an answer to this question (answering your own meta question is always fine) and see how people vote on it.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2015-11-05T15:50:24.373" Id="313" LastActivityDate="2015-11-05T15:50:24.373" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="309" PostTypeId="2" Score="1"/>
  <row AnswerCount="0" Body="&lt;p&gt;Shameless copy from &lt;a href=&quot;https://space.meta.stackexchange.com/questions/700/feature-request-add-marvosym-package-to-our-mathjax-set-for-celestial-body-sym&quot;&gt;SF.'s question on Space Meta&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;\usepackage{marvosym}&lt;/code&gt; allows you to write &lt;code&gt;M_\Sun&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;r_\Earth&lt;/code&gt; to have variables annotated with celestial body symbols. It would be surely nice to have in the mark-up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The list of planet symbols included is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;\Sun \Moon \Mercury \Venus \Mars \Jupiter \Saturn \Uranus \Neptune \Pluto \Earth&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would it be much trouble to include this package in our set, so that this would work?:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$M_\Sun = 1.989e30 kg$&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2015-12-17T14:31:53.023" FavoriteCount="1" Id="317" LastActivityDate="2016-07-12T17:13:32.400" LastEditDate="2017-03-16T15:52:04.387" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="8" Tags="&lt;feature-request&gt;" Title="Feature request: add marvosym package to our MathJax set (for celestial body symbols)" ViewCount="35"/>
  <row Body="&lt;h1&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discover our universe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Updated ad:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/1tczj.png&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/1tczj.png&quot; alt=&quot;enter image description here&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up on these sites (2019):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.meta.stackexchange.com/questions/11001/community-promotion-ads-2019/11006#11006&quot;&gt;Physics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chemistry.meta.stackexchange.com/questions/4364/community-promotion-ads-2019/4369#4369&quot;&gt;Chemistry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://academia.meta.stackexchange.com/questions/4407/community-promotion-ads-2019/4411#4411&quot;&gt;Academia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cs.meta.stackexchange.com/questions/1582/community-promotion-ads-2019/1584#1584&quot;&gt;Computer Science&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://worldbuilding.meta.stackexchange.com/questions/7063/community-promotion-ads-2019/7065#7065&quot;&gt;Worldbuilding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="7" CreationDate="2016-02-20T01:31:57.733" Id="335" LastActivityDate="2019-01-23T19:59:21.993" LastEditDate="2019-01-23T19:59:21.993" LastEditorUserId="9301" OwnerUserId="9301" ParentId="161" PostTypeId="2" Score="4"/>
  <row AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;I have seen a few questions relating to or using light speed. These seem to often be tagged with &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/speed&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;speed&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;speed&lt;/a&gt; and/or &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/light&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;light&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;light&lt;/a&gt;. I would think the &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/speed&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;speed&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;speed&lt;/a&gt; tag would be better categorised as kinematics/motion sort of questions and &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/light&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;light&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;light&lt;/a&gt; lends itself more to questions about the EM spectrum or visible wavelengths. Should we make a &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/speed-of-light&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;speed-of-light&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;speed-of-light&lt;/a&gt; tag to be used for questions more about relativity/quantum/faster than light travel etc.?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/13698/when-stars-explode-why-can-we-still-see-them&quot;&gt;When stars explode why can we still see them?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/13467/is-there-an-objective-difference-between-space-expansion-and-reduction-in-speed&quot;&gt;Is there an objective difference between space expansion and reduction in speed of light&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/12925/is-darkness-faster-than-light&quot;&gt;Is Darkness Faster Than Light?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="5" CreationDate="2016-02-23T10:14:49.717" Id="336" LastActivityDate="2019-09-19T13:15:56.953" LastEditDate="2019-09-19T13:15:56.953" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="2270" PostTypeId="1" Score="2" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;status-declined&gt;&lt;tags&gt;" Title="Should we have a speed-of-light tag?" ViewCount="66"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I've thought about this some more. How about a more generic &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/physical-constants&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;physical-constants&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;physical-constants&lt;/a&gt; tag?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2016-05-19T16:34:26.827" Id="346" LastActivityDate="2016-05-20T16:10:42.430" LastEditDate="2016-05-20T16:10:42.430" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="336" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="352" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;I didn't notice anything that really leaned one way or the other on this, but let me know if this is redundant or irrelevant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should answers such as Jack R. Woods's answer on this question be permitted? &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/418/what-practical-considerations-are-there-for-amateur-observations-of-transiting-e?rq=1&quot;&gt;What practical considerations are there for amateur observations of transiting exoplanets?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google results change frequently, and also depend on where you are in the world and your search history, so I don't think this is a valid answer.  At the very least, hyperlinks ought to have been provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, (although I don't this suggestion has any chance of actually being accepted) it would be nice to reduce (or remove) the points minimum required for commenting on answers.  In cases like above, it doesn't take a frequent contributor to realize that the answer is substandard.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2016-06-05T23:58:30.120" Id="351" LastActivityDate="2016-06-06T14:04:53.353" OwnerUserId="9504" PostTypeId="1" Score="2" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;" Title="&quot;Just Google it&quot; answers" ViewCount="62"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;No, that post did not answer the question, and it has been deleted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In regard to your question about changing the points. We can't change the points locally for our site, so that is technically a question for Meta Stack Exchange. I think some explanation is in order though. Stack Exchange sites are not really meant to be discussion boards, and so the comments are a secondary communication medium intended for use only to discuss changes to posts and then eventually be deleted. In practice, many comments often go on for a while without deletion, particularly where the comments are brief and do not result in much distraction from the subject matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, new users are typically still learning the written rules and culture of the site, and in order to avoid the site turning into a forum Stack Exchange has implemented a reputation point limit for making comments. If you have an idea on how this situation can be improved, I highly recommend that you post a question about it on Meta Stack Exchange.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2016-06-06T14:04:53.353" Id="352" LastActivityDate="2016-06-06T14:04:53.353" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="351" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="354" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I asked this question: &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/16147/10102&quot;&gt;What&amp;#39;s the distinction between &amp;quot;planetary formation mechanisms&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;gravitational collapse&amp;quot;?&lt;/a&gt;
And it got edited when I had not that much time to check the content. 
Now when I checked it, I noticed that the edit made my question ask for something completly different as I was interested in, forming a diferent question.
While &quot;both&quot; questions received upvotes and I'm also pretty much interested in answers about the past edit question, I'm not sure how to preceed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should I let the OP as it is now and just repost my original question again?
Or should I rollback and ask the past edit question seperately?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While tending to option 2, just while writing the post received a past edit related answer (as far I can tell), Making it even harder to decide what to do.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2016-06-07T08:21:29.713" Id="353" LastActivityDate="2016-06-07T14:28:08.053" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:06.230" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="10102" PostTypeId="1" Score="2" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;" Title="What to do when an edit forms an totally different question which is a good question at all anyway?" ViewCount="38"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;It is still early. Since you are the OP and the question was edited in a way that changed the question you were asking, you should roll it back. If someone wants to ask the question it was changed to, they can do so separately. When edits occur by low rep users, this is one of the things that reviewers check for--to make sure that edits don't alter the actual question beyond the author's intent. Unfortunately, there are sometimes cases where high rep user edits that don't get reviewed may cause this, and it can get overlooked. Thanks for catching it early on!&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2016-06-07T14:28:08.053" Id="354" LastActivityDate="2016-06-07T14:28:08.053" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="353" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;Is the intended group to be serviced by this Q&amp;amp;A community the professional and semi-professional amateur astronomers on specific technical questions. Or is it intended to include astronomy hobbyists, or members of the general public type questions? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professional astronomers have their own channels to date (I assume - like email), though as a small international community (relatively speaking) such a Stackexchange Q&amp;amp;A community could be useful and an asset I would think.  Then there are the hobbyists with technical questions like: tweaking camera software, telescope drives, photo analysis, analysis of variable star light curves, current aspect of astronomical objects being observed, those kind of things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it is just to be professional astronomers, given the level of public interest people will find this community and ask basic non technical public interest questions. Like &quot;How is a planetary nebula not a planet?&quot; type questions. An explanatory header could make it clear such questions are for other sites like Wikipedia. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One could consider two groups, Astronomy Professional, and Astronomy Amateurs. However any professional group is going to receive a lot of questions from highly keen inspired non-professionals, and likely to the point of the professional group not being useful. On the other hand, Stackoverflow seems to manage that boundary well in their version of it, software GUI users versus programmers. But then Stackoverflow have a much larger level of participants as a professional and hobbyist group to handle new interested programmer questions, help vampires, post redirects, etc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, again related to boundaries, where should a question on a python package like Glue in the raft of astronomy python packages be posted? Its an overlap of either Stackoverflow or Superuser depending on the nature of the question. At this point, being a python package, I think the latter, however techniques and strategies for use may be of topic in this Q&amp;amp;A group. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there is the question of this Q&amp;amp;A community vs Space Exploration (which I ran into posting a recent question). What tolerance to the overlap should participants or moderators exercise? I am not sure it is meaningful to seek to discriminate too tightly on this boundary. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think a key division is interest questions on astronomy vs technical questions related to doing astronomy. For the first there is Wikipedia and other question and answer sites, the latter for a Q&amp;amp;A community like this.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="12" CreationDate="2016-07-05T23:09:38.357" Id="356" LastActivityDate="2016-08-10T18:01:25.323" LastEditDate="2016-08-10T18:01:25.323" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="13359" PostTypeId="1" Score="6" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;" Title="What are the intended boundaries of this question and answers community?" ViewCount="183"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The Tour puts it well:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Get answers to practical, detailed questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professional or amateur, our site is meant to deal with questions that are practical and detailed. It is up to our site to help define those boundaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;hobbyists with technical questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acceptable:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/11278/problem-with-dobsonian-reflector-telescope&quot;&gt;Problem with Dobsonian reflector telescope&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;professional astronomers[' questions]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acceptable:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/658/what-is-the-lyman-alpha-forest-used-for&quot;&gt;What is the Lyman Alpha forest Used For?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;basic non technical public interest questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acceptable:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/138/does-the-sun-rotate&quot;&gt;Does the Sun rotate?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;However any professional group is going to receive a lot of questions from highly keen inspired non-professionals, and likely to the point of the professional group not being useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't necessarily see that as being the case. A professional is never &lt;em&gt;obliged&lt;/em&gt; to answer a question--it is purely on a volunteer basis. In fact, often a professional is not even required to answer a basic question, since a non-professional who had read enough would be able to answer. Our site gives us lots of tools to help sort questions so that professionals can find those that they are interested in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Also, again related to boundaries, where should a question on a python package like Glue in the raft of astronomy python packages be posted? Its an overlap of either Stackoverflow or Superuser depending on the nature of the question. At this point, being a python package, I think the latter, however techniques and strategies for use may be of topic in this Q&amp;amp;A group. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some questions are acceptable at more than one Stack Exchange site. In this case, if your question about the software package is of particular interest to astronomers, then it would likely be well received here, even if it were also on topic at Stack Overflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Then there is the question of this Q&amp;amp;A community vs Space Exploration (which I ran into posting a recent question). What tolerance to the overlap should participants or moderators exercise? I am not sure it is meaningful to seek to discriminate too tightly on this boundary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The community has defined some standards on this boundary already. You can check our &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/help/on-topic&quot;&gt;Help Center&lt;/a&gt; for guidance on what topics are allowed, and if it is unclear or you have other questions you can ask here on Meta. Furthermore, if you ask a question that doesn't seem to violate the guidelines in the Help Center, then you should also ask a question here in Meta so that the community can work out what the issue is, or if our guidelines need to be revised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I think a key division is interest questions on astronomy vs technical questions related to doing astronomy. For the first there is Wikipedia and other question and answer sites, the latter for a Q&amp;amp;A community like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all interest questions on astronomy are easily answerable through Wikipedia or other Q&amp;amp;A sites, so we do allow those that are not too trivial here, but we also highly encourage technical questions related to the practice of astronomy.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="5" CreationDate="2016-07-06T14:46:28.697" Id="357" LastActivityDate="2016-07-06T14:46:28.697" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:06.230" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="356" PostTypeId="2" Score="4"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="364" AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;I am newcommer on this site ,  and would like to know &lt;strong&gt;whether we can ask questions relating to cosmology&lt;/strong&gt; on this site?. As I am a enthusiast in both subjects. But these are not my professions. It is quite possible that I might be asking a non related question. &lt;strong&gt;Also I would like to know that ,can we ask question's related to ancient astronomy and it's findings?&lt;/strong&gt;.As they are not scientific questions, but will be relating to history of astronomy. So requesting calrification.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2016-07-27T21:11:34.810" Id="363" LastActivityDate="2016-10-27T16:49:44.910" OwnerUserId="11951" PostTypeId="1" Score="5" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;questions&gt;" Title="Are Questions related to Cosmology and ancient history of astronomy allowed in Astronomy SE?" ViewCount="72"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Yes, scientific cosmology is perfectly acceptable here, and ancient astronomy (note: &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; astrology) is generally regarded as on topic as well, though we don't have many with expertise in the topic of ancient astronomy, to my knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;History of astronomy is also covered to some extent at &lt;a href=&quot;https://history.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/astronomy&quot;&gt;History SE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2016-07-27T21:14:58.980" Id="364" LastActivityDate="2016-10-27T16:49:44.910" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:47:53.217" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="363" PostTypeId="2" Score="7"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="373" AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;Recently, a new user, who I would consider to be a reasonable individual who actually took the time to try to learn the system, complained that the topic scope of the site is too confusing for new users. While closing is just a part of the way SE works, perhaps we are not doing enough to explain the scope of what is on topic here? Ideally, a user who puts in the effort should be able to figure out somewhat quickly what the scope of the site is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think we might need to look at beefing up the on/off topic guidelines. Or maybe there is another solution? What are your thoughts?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="5" CreationDate="2016-08-08T15:08:42.037" FavoriteCount="1" Id="367" LastActivityDate="2016-09-13T20:43:10.663" LastEditDate="2016-09-13T20:43:10.663" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="5" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;status-completed&gt;&lt;on-topic&gt;&lt;new-users&gt;" Title="Is the topic scope too confusing for new users?" ViewCount="162"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;My top two favorite resources for the scope of any Stack Exchange site are, in order, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/tour&quot;&gt;tour&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/help&quot;&gt;help center&lt;/a&gt;. The former takes maybe a minute or two to read and should clear up some basic questions; the latter is useful for more specific concerns about scope and allows us to be more explicit about certain unique rules and guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The help center is in decent shape; moderators can edit certain pages, and, in general, this can/should be done early on, and revised later. The Astronomy &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/help/on-topic&quot;&gt;What topics can I ask about here? page&lt;/a&gt; (moderator-editable) is one of the better ones I've seen, and I think it outlines the scope nicely. The Astronomy &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/help/dont-ask&quot;&gt;What types of questions should I avoid asking? page&lt;/a&gt; is substantially vaguer, but it's not moderator-editable and is the same for each site; at any rate, I think it's intended to be less important than the other page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tour on Astronomy could, I think, be better. It's the first place I visit when joining any Stack Exchange site, because it's concise. However, it's currently using the default text in most areas, I believe, which isn't good. Some parts can be edited, including the sections under the headings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Welcome to Astronomy Stack Exchange&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask questions, get answers, no distractions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get answers to practical, detailed questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second one has been changed from the default to use a modified version of &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/11070/2153&quot;&gt;What is the name of our Solar System?&lt;/a&gt;; whether another question should be chosen is maybe something we should think about (criteria are given &lt;a href=&quot;https://meta.stackexchange.com/q/163947/274942&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). The third one is what I think needs to be changed; a good example is the version on &lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/tour&quot;&gt;Physics Stack Exchange&lt;/a&gt;. It has&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Examples of things to ask &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; not ask about&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Links to meta questions on topics that need more detail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A couple of the default bullet points&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think we need to edit this section, as it's easy to point people to and easy to read; I'd also guess that many more people are willing to look there than in the help center, even if it's just to get &lt;a href=&quot;https://meta.stackexchange.com/a/188733/274942&quot;&gt;the informed badge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's my proposed text (it's just an example; we can change it):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Ask about . . .&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Experimental and theoretical problems in astronomy, astrophysics, cosmology, and planetary science&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Astronomical equipment, both professional and amateur&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The use of space probes, telescopes, and rovers for astronomical purposes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/q/195/2153&quot;&gt;Certain resource requests&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Don't ask about . . .&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/q/97/2153&quot;&gt;Questions about physics or space exploration that do not involve astronomy&lt;/a&gt; (e.g. how a certain rocket works)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Questions that are primarily opinion-based&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Questions with too many possible answers or that would require an extremely long answer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/q/149/2153&quot;&gt;Astrology&lt;/a&gt; or astronomy-related pseudosciences&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, some of this needs to be a bit clearer, but you get the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, we &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; instead just add in a version of the text from the What topics can I ask about here? page in the help center, as Space Exploration has done, but I feel like that would be too long and bulky - not concise enough for a good tour.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="9" CreationDate="2016-08-22T15:20:51.333" Id="373" LastActivityDate="2016-08-22T15:50:14.517" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:06.230" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="2153" ParentId="367" PostTypeId="2" Score="4"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I think on the topic of spacecraft specifically the answer is yes. The linked question is about an astronomical instrument. It was closed as off topic. This does seem counterintuitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/help/on-topic&quot;&gt;What topics can I ask about here?&lt;/a&gt; page doesn't seem to exclude this. It excludes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Questions about artificial satellites whose purpose is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; directly related to astronomy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the question was about the Hubble Space Telescope which is clearly completely devoted to astronomical research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe some specific clarification on which questions about astronomical instruments are off topic would help.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2016-09-06T15:10:32.647" Id="378" LastActivityDate="2016-09-06T15:10:32.647" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:06.230" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="14116" ParentId="367" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;Twice in the last 24 hours I have rolled back edits that the OP has made to their own question, because the nature of the question was completely changed or substantial supplementary questions were added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/18708/does-the-recent-news-of-ten-times-more-galaxies-imply-that-there-is-correspond&quot;&gt;Does the recent news of &amp;quot;ten times more galaxies&amp;quot; imply that there is correspondingly less dark matter?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/18714/how-to-convert-radec-between-different-epoches&quot;&gt;How to convert ra&amp;amp;dec between different epoches?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think such edits are fine when no answers to a question have been advanced, but in both these cases, I had given a substantial answer that had received upvotes and in one case been accepted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please could question askers not do this, it makes existing answers look ill thought-out, incomplete or even irrelevant. If you have a different question, ask a different question.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2016-10-15T14:27:06.267" FavoriteCount="0" Id="384" LastActivityDate="2016-10-17T14:10:09.850" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:06.230" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="2531" PostTypeId="1" Score="4" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;asking-questions&gt;&lt;editing&gt;" Title="Rolling back question edits that have changed the question" ViewCount="44"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Yes, in both of those cases inappropriate changes were made to the question. In the first, the nature of the question was changed completely. In the second, the additions were more suitable for new question(s). We do accept some level of modification to questions after they have been answered, but that is mostly for minor adjustments/clarifications to the central question. It is not intended to allow for the scope of the question to change completely, or for additional separate questions to be added. When this happens, the correct approach is to roll back the edit, as you did here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If an edit war starts, flag the post for moderator attention.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2016-10-17T14:10:09.850" Id="385" LastActivityDate="2016-10-17T14:10:09.850" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="384" PostTypeId="2" Score="4"/>
  <row AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;On Bio SE the badges look like genes. Could Astronomy SE change the badges to a ringed planet like Saturn?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2016-11-12T16:58:51.483" FavoriteCount="0" Id="391" LastActivityDate="2016-11-17T20:30:16.393" LastEditDate="2016-11-17T20:30:16.393" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="14078" PostTypeId="1" Score="1" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;feature-request&gt;" Title="Could we change the badges to a saturn like planet?" ViewCount="72"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Building site design is a large effort, so this effort is limited to &quot;graduated&quot; sites. Further explanation is below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is graduation? From &lt;a href=&quot;https://meta.stackexchange.com/questions/257614/graduation-site-closure-and-a-clearer-outlook-on-the-health-of-se-sites&quot;&gt;Graduation, site closure, and a clearer outlook on the health of SE sites - Meta Stack Exchange&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Graduation is a hard concept to pin down quantitatively, but we basically expect that a graduated site should be able to continue growing and governing itself indefinitely without any outside help unless something truly catastrophic happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;User summary of graduation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[T]here are six effects of graduation:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Site Design:&lt;/strong&gt; [...]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moderator Elections:&lt;/strong&gt; [...]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community Ads:&lt;/strong&gt; [...]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reputation Levels:&lt;/strong&gt; [...]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full migration target:&lt;/strong&gt; [...]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Being listed in the footer:&lt;/strong&gt; [...]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;https://meta.stackexchange.com/questions/107246/what-are-the-design-elements-that-could-be-changed-upon-graduation-of-a-site&quot;&gt;What are the design elements that could be changed upon graduation of a site? - Meta Stack Exchange&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Each graduating site gets its own unique design theme created by Stack Exchange's professional in-house design team (currently Jin), working with other designers as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So far, every site's theme has included&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a custom logo and favicon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;custom decorative graphics (or intentional lack thereof)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a consistent color scheme&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Most sites have also received&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;unique fonts consistent with the site theme&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;decorative boxes and borders consistent with the site theme&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;themed badge shapes/sizes/colors (color referring to background color, not bronze/silver/gold)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;themed tag shapes/sizes/colors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;unique upvote/downvote/favorite button images&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Some sites have other changes that have to do with their topics. Photography's top bar is organized differently to make room for a &quot;featured photo.&quot; Unix and Linux has slashes prepended to the text of its header buttons to give the feel that those link to &quot;subdirectories&quot; of the site. And Apple's &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;kbd&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; markup looks like an Apple keyboard's key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.blog/2010/10/when-will-my-site-graduate/&quot;&gt;When Will My Site Graduate? - Stack Overflow Blog&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h1&gt;How long can a site stay in beta?&lt;/h1&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The simple answer is, it takes as long as it takes. We'll wait. If a site needs more activity, go out and evangelize it. As long as your site shows steady progress and continues to make the Internet a better place to get expert answers to your questions, it will march on. We don't want to kill a site because it hasn't reached full status in 90 days. Nor do we want to set a hard 90-day limit and launch a site too soon.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There's more to the health of a Stack Exchange site than having a lot of questions and answers. There's an economy to the site with reputation as its currency, and voting drives that economy. A site absolutely needs on-going, sustained voting to build a class of leaders that help run and govern the site. Without leadership, there can be no community.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So from this point forward, the graduation date of a site will depend heavily on having enough users with sufficient reputation to properly lead and govern the site. It's much more important to graduate a site when it has become self-sustaining, and has established a healthy community of avid users, closers, and editors -- rather than imposing an arbitrary 90-day limit.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Thus, the order of launch will favor those beta sites which have achieved the most &quot;excellent&quot; ratings on our Area 51 stats panel. For everyone else -- keep going!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, now, graduation does not necessarily mean that we will receive a design right away. From &lt;a href=&quot;https://meta.stackexchange.com/questions/260754/feedback-requested-design-independent-graduation&quot;&gt;Feedback Requested: Design-Independent Graduation - Meta Stack Exchange&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;The Community Team announces that a site is cleared for graduation. Without delay...&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the beta label is removed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;elections are held&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;migration paths are set up&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;community ads are run  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a link to the site is added to the footer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;...Then, as it becomes available&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the site gets their custom design.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;privilege thresholds are increased to graduated site levels&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2016-11-14T19:36:06.793" Id="394" LastActivityDate="2016-11-15T14:31:35.767" LastEditDate="2017-03-20T10:31:57.263" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="391" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;It's that time of year again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The year is rapidly coming to a close, which means even though we typically &lt;a href=&quot;https://meta.stackexchange.com/questions/19478/the-many-memes-of-meta/268583#268583&quot;&gt;hate it&lt;/a&gt;, it’s time to have some fun...with hats!  That’s right - &lt;strong&gt;it’s time for Winter Bash 2016!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Most of you remember previous years’ events, but here is a quick little reminder. Winter Bash is an annual event that can run on any Stack Exchange site that chooses to participate. Users have fun by earning “hats” for their gravatars by completing certain tasks (very similar to badges). We track everyone’s progress using hats in a leaderboard that looks similar to this:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/GxiD3.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/GxiD3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Winter Bash 2016 Leaderboard&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As always, we’re coming up with new hat designs for this year’s fun!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Details&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The event will run from &lt;strong&gt;19 December 2016&lt;/strong&gt; up to and including &lt;strong&gt;08 January 2017&lt;/strong&gt;. Users will be able to see all the hats they’ve earned on &lt;a href=&quot;http://winterbash2016.stackexchange.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;http://winterbash2016.stackexchange.com&lt;/a&gt;. That site will also have a landing page, explaining the rules and other details of the event. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Individual users who don’t want to participate, don’t want to see hats, and/or are generally anti-hat will have an “I hate hats” option available. And just like last time, &lt;strong&gt;at the end of the event, all hats will go back into storage.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The only visual change to the Stack Exchange sites themselves will be the presence of the hats and the “I hate hats” button in the footer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So...hats or no hats? We have until &lt;strong&gt;Tuesday, 13 December 2016&lt;/strong&gt; to decide.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2016-11-29T20:23:43.840" Id="396" LastActivityDate="2016-12-19T13:38:52.737" LastEditDate="2017-03-20T10:31:57.263" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="8" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;" Title="Winter Bash 2016: Do we want hats?" ViewCount="127"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I was going to make some sort of pun, involving the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HATNet_Project&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HATNet Project&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (or &lt;a href=&quot;http://hatsouth.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HATSouth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) or a &lt;a href=&quot;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/PlanetOfHats&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Planet of Hats&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. But I think I'll spare everyone the pain and just say&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Yes! Bring on the hats!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, here's a modified photograph of the Mauna Kea Observatory:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/6pyul.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/6pyul.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;enter image description here&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Mauna_Kea_observatory.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Original image&lt;/a&gt; courtesy of Wikipedia user Cropbot under &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/deed.en&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;the Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 Generic license&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2016-11-30T00:43:00.980" Id="397" LastActivityDate="2016-11-30T00:43:00.980" OwnerUserId="2153" ParentId="396" PostTypeId="2" Score="6"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Absolutely bring on the hats - I can say from experience that there is something truly awe-inspiring about a group of astronomers with hats of all kinds on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a great c&lt;strong&gt;hat&lt;/strong&gt; about hats!&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2016-12-19T13:38:52.737" Id="398" LastActivityDate="2016-12-19T13:38:52.737" OwnerDisplayName="user15217" ParentId="396" PostTypeId="2" Score="1"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="407" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;We have three tags that should be synonyms: &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/moon&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;moon&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;moon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/the-moon&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;the-moon&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;the-moon&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/lunar&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;lunar&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;lunar&lt;/a&gt;. Tags related to the Sun (&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/the-sun&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;the-sun&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;the-sun&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/solar&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;solar&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;solar&lt;/a&gt;) have been marked as synonyms of &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/sun&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;sun&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;sun&lt;/a&gt;, which is the master tag for this group. In keeping with this, tag:moon should be the master tag for questions related to the Moon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a number problems with this, however. The correct tag for the Sun should be Sun rather than sun, and for the Moon, Moon rather than moon. This is not possible as SE tags are lowercased. Related to this is that there's a big difference between a moon (with a lowercase m) and the Moon (with an uppercase M). Despite the verbiage, there are already some questions tagged as &quot;moon&quot; that pertain to moons other than the Moon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another problem is that the tag &quot;the-moon&quot; has many more questions (247) than do the tags &quot;moon&quot; (32 questions) and &quot;lunar&quot; (10 questions). Making &quot;moon&quot; the master (without a capital M) will invite continued mis-tagging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My proposal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make &quot;the-moon&quot; the master tag for questions pertaining to the Moon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make &quot;lunar&quot; tag a synonym of &quot;the-moon&quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a new tag &quot;moons&quot;, a synonym of &quot;natural-satellite&quot;, and retag the few questions tagged as &quot;moon&quot; that don't belong in that category as  &quot;moons&quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Retag as &quot;the-moon&quot; all the remaining questions tagged as &quot;moon&quot; that do indeed pertain to the Moon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lock the tag &quot;moon&quot; as ambiguous given the lowercase nature of SE tags.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can't do the retagging presently; work beckons. I can undertake this effort later this evening, about 12 to 13 hours from now.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2017-03-06T11:58:02.660" FavoriteCount="0" Id="406" LastActivityDate="2017-03-14T14:13:05.990" LastEditDate="2017-03-14T14:13:05.990" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="2618" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;status-completed&gt;&lt;tags&gt;&lt;tag-synonyms&gt;" Title="Tag synonyms for the Moon" ViewCount="61"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/the-sun&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;the-sun&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;the-sun&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/the-moon&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;the-moon&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;the-moon&lt;/a&gt; are now the official tags. &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/lunar&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;lunar&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;lunar&lt;/a&gt; is now a synonym of &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/the-moon&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;the-moon&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;the-moon&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/moons&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;moons&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;moons&lt;/a&gt; is now a synonym of &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/natural-satellite&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;natural-satellite&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;natural-satellite&lt;/a&gt;. Only developers can blacklist tags, but I don't think we need to blacklist &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/moon&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;moon&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;moon&lt;/a&gt;. I made it a synonym of &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/the-moon&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;the-moon&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;the-moon&lt;/a&gt;. Even though &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/moon&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;moon&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;moon&lt;/a&gt; is ambiguous, in most cases people will be looking for &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/the-moon&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;the-moon&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;the-moon&lt;/a&gt;. When they are not, they will see that they have not used the correct tag and can either look for another or seek assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have not done any retagging, so folks will want to keep their eyes out for Qs that need retagging.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2017-03-07T01:50:28.080" Id="407" LastActivityDate="2017-03-07T01:50:28.080" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="406" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="427" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;Is it ok to take my early questions, sharpen them up and repost them here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 &lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/281828/if-earth-had-rings&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/281828/if-earth-had-rings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 &lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/225693/using-a-naked-black-hole-as-a-mirror/225697#225697&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/225693/using-a-naked-black-hole-as-a-mirror/225697#225697&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 &lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/297890/rainbow-blackhole&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/297890/rainbow-blackhole&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 &lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/283322/why-is-venus-cloud-covered-but-not-in-an-ice-age&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/283322/why-is-venus-cloud-covered-but-not-in-an-ice-age&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 &lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/297729/can-a-photon-that-is-emitted-from-a-denser-part-of-the-universe-to-a-less-dense&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/297729/can-a-photon-that-is-emitted-from-a-denser-part-of-the-universe-to-a-less-dense&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6 &lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/226458/do-magnetic-fields-exist-beyond-the-gravity-of-a-black-hole&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/226458/do-magnetic-fields-exist-beyond-the-gravity-of-a-black-hole&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7 &lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/226917/with-gravitational-lensing-could-we-see-our-selves-from-a-right-angle&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/226917/with-gravitational-lensing-could-we-see-our-selves-from-a-right-angle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8 &lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/232862/gases-expanding-and-bonding-in-the-vacuum-frozen-clouds&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/232862/gases-expanding-and-bonding-in-the-vacuum-frozen-clouds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9 &lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/298346/are-most-galaxies-expanding-from-us-as-previously-calculated&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/298346/are-most-galaxies-expanding-from-us-as-previously-calculated&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10 &lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/269934/extinction-level-meteor-effects-on-earths-crust-pending-on-the-surface-area-upo&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/269934/extinction-level-meteor-effects-on-earths-crust-pending-on-the-surface-area-upo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11 &lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/227738/time-dilation-equals-red-shift-looking-in-or-blue-shift-looking-out&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/227738/time-dilation-equals-red-shift-looking-in-or-blue-shift-looking-out&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;12 &lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/225680/what-is-this-black-hole-merger-orbital-speed&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/225680/what-is-this-black-hole-merger-orbital-speed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13 &lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/225673/see-behind-the-black-hole&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/225673/see-behind-the-black-hole&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;14 &lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/232759/until-when-travel-the-particles-after-the-big-bang-with-light-speed&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/232759/until-when-travel-the-particles-after-the-big-bang-with-light-speed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15 &lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/229629/black-hole-matter-to-subatomic-exchange&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/229629/black-hole-matter-to-subatomic-exchange&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;16 &lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/231561/super-massive-black-hole-and-photon-reduction&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/231561/super-massive-black-hole-and-photon-reduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;17 &lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/243863/spacetime-mercury-vs-earth&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/243863/spacetime-mercury-vs-earth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;18 &lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/228379/does-the-size-of-a-naked-black-hole-make-a-diffrence-in-photon-sphere-proximity&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/228379/does-the-size-of-a-naked-black-hole-make-a-diffrence-in-photon-sphere-proximity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;19 &lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/271148/black-hole-and-critical-mass&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/271148/black-hole-and-critical-mass&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;20 &lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/231564/can-the-outer-most-layer-of-a-black-hole-be-composed-of-magnetically-trapped-pho&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/231564/can-the-outer-most-layer-of-a-black-hole-be-composed-of-magnetically-trapped-pho&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;21 &lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/234352/o-energy-asolute-0-matter-at-the-end-of-a-black-holes-acceleration-disk&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/234352/o-energy-asolute-0-matter-at-the-end-of-a-black-holes-acceleration-disk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fell free to list the one that make a good fit or the bad ones that can't be helped. Some of the questions could be spit into 2 questions.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="6" CreationDate="2018-02-16T19:48:09.727" Id="426" LastActivityDate="2018-02-16T20:35:14.433" LastEditDate="2018-02-16T20:35:14.433" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="15415" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;support&gt;&lt;asking-questions&gt;&lt;scope&gt;" Title="Can I migrate some questions from Physics SE to here that are in scope?" ViewCount="74"/>
  <row Body="&lt;h2&gt;Should stay on Physics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/281828/if-earth-had-rings&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/281828/if-earth-had-rings&lt;/a&gt; (Well accepted there, no need to migrate)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/225693/using-a-naked-black-hole-as-a-mirror&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/225693/using-a-naked-black-hole-as-a-mirror&lt;/a&gt; (Same)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/297890/rainbow-blackhole&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/297890/rainbow-blackhole&lt;/a&gt; (Same)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/283322/why-is-venus-cloud-covered-but-not-in-an-ice-age&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/283322/why-is-venus-cloud-covered-but-not-in-an-ice-age&lt;/a&gt; (Same)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/297729/can-a-photon-that-is-emitted-from-a-denser-part-of-the-universe-to-a-less-dense&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/297729/can-a-photon-that-is-emitted-from-a-denser-part-of-the-universe-to-a-less-dense&lt;/a&gt; (Same)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/226458/do-magnetic-fields-exist-beyond-the-gravity-of-a-black-hole&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/226458/do-magnetic-fields-exist-beyond-the-gravity-of-a-black-hole&lt;/a&gt; (Same)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/226917/with-gravitational-lensing-could-we-see-our-selves-from-a-right-angle&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/226917/with-gravitational-lensing-could-we-see-our-selves-from-a-right-angle&lt;/a&gt; (Same)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/232862/gases-expanding-and-bonding-in-the-vacuum-frozen-clouds&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/232862/gases-expanding-and-bonding-in-the-vacuum-frozen-clouds&lt;/a&gt; (Same)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/298346/are-most-galaxies-expanding-from-us-as-previously-calculated&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/298346/are-most-galaxies-expanding-from-us-as-previously-calculated&lt;/a&gt; (Same)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/269934/extinction-level-meteor-effects-on-earths-crust-pending-on-the-surface-area-upo&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/269934/extinction-level-meteor-effects-on-earths-crust-pending-on-the-surface-area-upo&lt;/a&gt; (Same)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/227738/time-dilation-equals-red-shift-looking-in-or-blue-shift-looking-out&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/227738/time-dilation-equals-red-shift-looking-in-or-blue-shift-looking-out&lt;/a&gt; (Same)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/225673/see-behind-the-black-hole&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/225673/see-behind-the-black-hole&lt;/a&gt; (Same)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/229629/black-hole-matter-to-subatomic-exchange&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/229629/black-hole-matter-to-subatomic-exchange&lt;/a&gt; (Answered though not well accepted, but not a net negative score, too old to migrate)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/243863/spacetime-mercury-vs-earth&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/243863/spacetime-mercury-vs-earth&lt;/a&gt; (Same)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Too old to migrate, but can be reasked here&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/225680/what-is-this-black-hole-merger-orbital-speed&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/225680/what-is-this-black-hole-merger-orbital-speed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/231561/super-massive-black-hole-and-photon-reduction&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/231561/super-massive-black-hole-and-photon-reduction&lt;/a&gt; (It does have a couple answers, but I don't think it would hurt to reask with a clearer question)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/228379/does-the-size-of-a-naked-black-hole-make-a-diffrence-in-photon-sphere-proximity&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/228379/does-the-size-of-a-naked-black-hole-make-a-diffrence-in-photon-sphere-proximity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/231564/can-the-outer-most-layer-of-a-black-hole-be-composed-of-magnetically-trapped-pho&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/231564/can-the-outer-most-layer-of-a-black-hole-be-composed-of-magnetically-trapped-pho&lt;/a&gt; (Needs to be substantially revised)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/234352/o-energy-asolute-0-matter-at-the-end-of-a-black-holes-acceleration-disk&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/234352/o-energy-asolute-0-matter-at-the-end-of-a-black-holes-acceleration-disk&lt;/a&gt; (Needs to be substantially revised)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Unsalvageable&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/232759/until-when-travel-the-particles-after-the-big-bang-with-light-speed&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/232759/until-when-travel-the-particles-after-the-big-bang-with-light-speed&lt;/a&gt; (look up other questions about the Big Bang here)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/271148/black-hole-and-critical-mass&quot;&gt;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/271148/black-hole-and-critical-mass&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="8" CreationDate="2018-02-16T20:34:07.527" Id="427" LastActivityDate="2018-02-16T20:34:07.527" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="426" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;We've had a question about a homework tag before and the consensus was to not have one.  However I'm a little bothered that we're getting questions that have absolutely no effort to answer from common sources (not just this site but e.g. Wikipedia or a simple web search).  Some questions also do sound like straight &quot;do my homework for me&quot; requests (although not indicated as such).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I'm asking for opinions on whether we should make an absence of effort to do prior research to try and answer a question a reason to close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example I'd suggest that &quot;I checked Wikipedia but I don't quite get why X implies Y, please explain.&quot; would be fine (minimal effort and needs help understanding a concept) but &quot;Name three X type objects&quot; would not (no effort and a trivial web search gets the answer).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One objection (playing devil's advocate) is that we may discourage people genuinely trying to learn.  In some ways this question is also asking to what extent we view Astronomy SE as a teaching site, I suppose.  I confess I'm ambivalent about this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opinions ?  Alternative ideas ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note : &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; suggesting adding a homework tag, just looking for a community consensus on certain types of questions.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2018-04-05T23:23:24.017" Id="428" LastActivityDate="2018-04-06T13:56:40.067" OwnerUserId="10196" PostTypeId="1" Score="2" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;" Title="Make no prior research or effort a reason to close?" ViewCount="29"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, no research effort does not &lt;em&gt;necessarily&lt;/em&gt; mean that the underlying question is bad, just the post--which to me means downvote, not close (unless you want to close as unclear).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I think what you're ultimately getting at is something like the History SE custom close reason:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This question is &lt;strong&gt;too basic&lt;/strong&gt;; it can be definitively answered by a single link to the relevant topic on Wikipedia or another standard reference source. If you are instead questioning the correctness of a reference source, please edit the post to supply a link and explain what you find unclear, or why you believe it to be wrong or incomplete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do think there could be some value to having this type of close reason here.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2018-04-06T13:56:40.067" Id="429" LastActivityDate="2018-04-06T13:56:40.067" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="428" PostTypeId="2" Score="4"/>
  <row AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;I was rather distressed to find &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.co.uk/books?id=ODhRDwAAQBAJ&amp;amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;amp;hl=en#v=onepage&amp;amp;q&amp;amp;f=false&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;this book&lt;/a&gt; available for sale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is just a cut and paste job of hundreds of Astronomy SE questions and answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I understand that people are allowed to do this under the terms of the creative commons license, but I rather thought they had to provide links to the original source and links to the user profiles of the people who had actually provided the material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can be done about this?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2018-04-10T20:59:20.560" Id="430" LastActivityDate="2018-04-13T14:14:59.670" LastEditDate="2018-04-10T21:29:20.653" LastEditorUserId="2531" OwnerUserId="2531" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;" Title="What to do about intellectual copyright infringement?" ViewCount="55"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I just found out that the Stack Exchange modification to the Creative Commons license to require attribution is not legally valid. So, even without SE's attribution requirements present this reuse of the material is legally not copyright infringement (as long as it follows CC's attribution requirements):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://meta.stackexchange.com/a/258180/228367&quot;&gt;https://meta.stackexchange.com/a/258180/228367&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2018-04-13T14:07:24.640" Id="433" LastActivityDate="2018-04-13T14:14:59.670" LastEditDate="2018-04-13T14:14:59.670" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="430" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;I can't find that discussion back, but at least stack overflow (the granddady of stack exchanges), I seem to recall community wikis were not an encouraged practice. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is the astronomy SE against, neutral or pro community wikis?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the gist of the opposition against community wiki is that much of the same could be achieved by proposing edits to an existing good answer, but then all the reputations etc. which is an important part of the general workings of an exchange isn't really included anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://meta.stackexchange.com/questions/11740/what-are-community-wiki-posts?utm_medium=organic&amp;amp;utm_source=google_rich_qa&amp;amp;utm_campaign=google_rich_qa&quot;&gt;The general SE meta post on community wiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2018-05-01T22:25:56.150" Id="437" LastActivityDate="2018-10-09T05:13:53.840" LastEditDate="2018-10-09T05:13:53.840" LastEditorUserId="23748" OwnerUserId="22894" PostTypeId="1" Score="4" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;community-wiki&gt;" Title="What does astronomy meta thinks of community wiki?" ViewCount="48"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Community wiki is a valuable tool for answers in some cases, but we do not use it on questions. In some cases the best way to arrive at an answer is by the collaboration of multiple users, that is when community wiki becomes a useful tool--because the post is no longer perceived as being primarily the view of a single author.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2018-05-02T15:03:47.790" Id="438" LastActivityDate="2018-05-02T15:03:47.790" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="437" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="440" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;I had the Observatory chat window open and when I looked at it I saw four copies of the message  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.google.com/news&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;This RSS feed URL is deprecated&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does this mean? The link in the messages is just &lt;code&gt;https://news.google.com/news&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/yhLt3.png&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/yhLt3.png&quot; alt=&quot;screen shot Observatory chat&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2018-05-05T09:51:21.573" Id="439" LastActivityDate="2018-05-05T16:29:19.157" OwnerUserId="7982" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;support&gt;" Title="What does &quot;This RSS feed URL is deprecated&quot; mean in chat?" ViewCount="19"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;We had a Google News feed for Astronomy set up, but it appears to be no longer functional. I'm removing the feed now.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2018-05-05T16:29:19.157" Id="440" LastActivityDate="2018-05-05T16:29:19.157" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="439" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="459" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;I've asked the question &lt;a href=&quot;https://space.stackexchange.com/q/31815/12102&quot;&gt;What might the first deep space telescope using the Sun or Jupiter as a gravitational lens be like?&lt;/a&gt; in Space Exploration SE. I chose that site because it involves propulsion and coordination of possibly an array of space telescopes. I left a message in The Observatory (chat) as well as a &quot;heads-up&quot; to whomever actually checks there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the question also about telescope instrumentation, data analysis, and image reconstruction from a gravitational lens which do not work the same as &quot;normal&quot; lenses (deflection varies as &lt;span class=&quot;math-container&quot;&gt;$r^{-1}$&lt;/span&gt; rather than &lt;span class=&quot;math-container&quot;&gt;$r$&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder, should I split this into two, and ask the imaging part here? Or perhaps just ask an open-ed up, basic question about image reconstruction from gravitational lenses here instead? (do algorithms exist, how hard would it be, what would need to be measured, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2018-11-14T02:54:48.583" Id="458" LastActivityDate="2018-11-14T16:33:06.380" OwnerUserId="7982" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;" Title="Would this question have been better to ask in Astronomy? Could it be split it into two? Something else?" ViewCount="18"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Your question there seems well-received. I would leave it as is, and if you would like, ask a new question here tailored to this community to gather further detail.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2018-11-14T16:33:06.380" Id="459" LastActivityDate="2018-11-14T16:33:06.380" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="458" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="469" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;As some of you might know, &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldbuilding.meta.stackexchange.com/q/2590/627&quot;&gt;Worldbuilding Stack Exchange has a blog&lt;/a&gt;, which we call &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/universe-factory&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Universe Factory&lt;/a&gt;. Though less active than it was when it started up a couple of years ago, we still manage 2-3 post per month, in general. It's been a great community building strategy, and has managed to bring together users interested in disparate topics, as well as attracting non-users to the site, through reading or writing blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've seen a lot of questions recently on Astronomy that make me think &quot;Hey, this is cool. But what about [X, Y, Z]? I'd like to learn more about that.&quot; For example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/28083/2153&quot;&gt;this question about mapping the Milky way via HI regions&lt;/a&gt; made me wonder, among other things, about how assumptions of non-Keplerian orbits would change certain calculations. In some cases, a follow-up question would be appropriate, but in others, there's just too much information to discuss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;What would it look like?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://meta.stackexchange.com/q/291741/274942&quot;&gt;Stack Exchange no longer hosts blogs&lt;/a&gt;, meaning that if a community wants to start its own, it has to go off-site (and make the blog unofficial, although SE will likely say &quot;Yeah, it's okay to do that.&quot;). Worldbuilding and &lt;a href=&quot;https://scifi.meta.stackexchange.com/q/10256/41082&quot;&gt;Science Fiction &amp;amp; Fantasy&lt;/a&gt; are probably the two communities which have the highest-visibility blogs. SFF's uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://thesffblog.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;a WordPress site&lt;/a&gt;, as I understand it, while  Worldbuilding uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;, a blogging platform that I think makes contributing to a group blog much easier. I certainly like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://worldbuilding.meta.stackexchange.com/a/2878/627&quot;&gt;Worldbuilding has lots and lots of information on the site meta&lt;/a&gt; about how the blog works, but I can summarize the technical details:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We have our own &quot;publication&quot; on medium.com.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A small set of users have editor status, meaning they are the ones who can launch posts. At least one should be a site moderator (in the case of Worldbuilding, two of us are).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anyone can write a blog post (although they okay it with the blog team first); they just need to set up an account on Medium.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We update &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldbuilding.meta.stackexchange.com/q/4037/627&quot;&gt;a meta post&lt;/a&gt; and the Community Bulletin (which requires a mod) to promote the current post(s).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially, it's a third-party host, and an unofficial blog, but all of the important information is open to the community on the site. We even have &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.stackexchange.com/rooms/27736/universe-factory&quot;&gt;a chat room&lt;/a&gt; for coordinating and planning posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;What could we write about?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both sites have their own types of posts. SFF includes movie reviews, discussions of conventions and related events, editorials, etc. Worldbuilding often has posts about worldbuilding tips, as well as original short stories. For a putative Astronomy Stack Exchange blog, I'm thinking of a couple different types of possible posts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reviews of interesting papers (as I write this, I realize that &lt;a href=&quot;https://astrobites.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Astrobites&lt;/a&gt; does this, aimed at an undergrad audience, although we could target broader or other niche sets of readers)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discussions of specialized and maybe esoteric terminology (e.g. a post on &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speckle_imaging&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;speckle imaging&lt;/a&gt;, although I guess that's not so esoteric)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talking about a user's own active research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Information about outreach and public events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The level the post is written at would be up to the author's discretion, and would likely vary based on the topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;But why should we do it?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well . . . I think it would be a decent method of community building and community promotion. We're not a huge site - although we're still healthy - and I've been looking for a number of ways in which we could grow and become stronger, and hopefully reach a wider audience. A blog would be an easy enough way to do this, and it could be fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do people think? Should we try this out? If so, are there any changes we should make to the model I've proposed? Any other thoughts?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="6" CreationDate="2018-11-15T16:06:24.040" Id="460" LastActivityDate="2019-01-03T15:26:57.057" LastEditDate="2019-01-03T15:26:57.057" LastEditorUserId="2153" OwnerUserId="2153" PostTypeId="1" Score="6" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;site-promotion&gt;&lt;blog&gt;" Title="Should we have a blog?" ViewCount="125"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="466" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;There seems to be an interest in reviving the topic of the week in some form:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/q/389/6&quot;&gt;Should we revive the Topic of the Week?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My proposal is based on the top upvoted &quot;topic of the month&quot; idea there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each month we could highlight a tag on meta with a title like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h3&gt;This Month's Focus Tag: &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/the-moon&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;the-moon&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;the-moon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The focus tag would be the centerpiece for several efforts. We could:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature clear questions under the tag with one or more excellent answers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;encourage asking follow-up questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;engage in editing of posts under the tag&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;take the opportunity to make sure the tag description is appropriate and update the tag wiki&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/q/460/6&quot;&gt;blog posts&lt;/a&gt; related to the topic, if the blog idea catches on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer space of the meta post would be used to coordinate efforts like assembling lists of posts in need of editing or brainstorming ideas to add to the tag wiki or blog. If desired, it could even be used for sandboxing questions related to the focus tag to have the community review before posting in main to prevent poor reception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you think of this idea?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2018-11-28T18:37:22.823" Id="465" LastActivityDate="2018-11-29T14:19:14.337" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="5" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;tags&gt;" Title="Monthly focus tag" ViewCount="68"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Since this idea seems popular, I have some suggestions for the first focus tag:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/tidal-forces&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;tidal-forces&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;tidal-forces&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/photometry&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;photometry&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;photometry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/meteorite&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;meteorite&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;meteorite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/dust&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;dust&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;dust&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are all high use tags without descriptions that seemed potentially eye-catching to me. I also have some suggestions for highlighted questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/tidal-forces&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;tidal-forces&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;tidal-forces&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/12269/6&quot;&gt;How did Mars come to have a 24 hour 39 minute day?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/photometry&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;photometry&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;photometry&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/18986/6&quot;&gt;What is the ugriz magnitude system?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/meteorite&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;meteorite&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;meteorite&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/2372/6&quot;&gt;How do scientists know that a rock found on Earth came from Mars?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/dust&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;dust&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;dust&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/3663/6&quot;&gt;What is the difference between gas and dust in astronomy?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please comment with the focus tag you want to see first, and feel free to give your thoughts on the highlighted questions and/or offer alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have other ideas for the focus tag, let us know in another answer.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2018-11-29T14:19:14.337" Id="466" LastActivityDate="2018-11-29T14:19:14.337" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="465" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;Welcome to our new series of monthly focus tags! This month's focus tag is &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/dust&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;dust&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;dust&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Featured Question:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/3663/6&quot;&gt;What is the difference between gas and dust in astronomy?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This question is great to start off with because it covers the definition of dust in astronomy, so if you're not sure what this tag is all about you should check it out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The monthly focus tag is an opportunity for us to learn more about a topic and improve the site by taking a look at a particular area. Please take this opportunity to look at the questions and answers in &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/dust&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;dust&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;dust&lt;/a&gt;. If you see anything that could be improved, take the opportunity to edit. If you have follow-up questions, go ahead and ask them (with the appropriate tag, of course). If you happen to know the answer to an unanswered question, we'd appreciate your input!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, this is a good chance to take a look at the tag excerpt and wiki. If it is empty or could be improved, perhaps you could help us out?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to use the answer space below to make community wiki lists of posts in need of editing, or to brainstorm ideas of what to add to the tag excerpt and wiki. Not sure about a particular &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/dust&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;dust&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;dust&lt;/a&gt; question you have? Go ahead and share your concerns below, so we can help guide you to framing the question on the site.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2018-12-03T13:44:35.657" Id="467" LastActivityDate="2019-02-18T21:26:56.637" LastEditDate="2019-02-18T21:26:56.637" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="6" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;focus-tag&gt;" Title="This month's focus tag: dust" ViewCount="125"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Definition of &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/dust&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;dust&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;dust&lt;/a&gt; resulted in the need for the tag &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/dust-storm&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;dust-storm&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;dust-storm&lt;/a&gt;. Check it out and feel free to revise it as well. If you see any questions which need this tag or other questions under &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/dust&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;dust&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;dust&lt;/a&gt; that don't fit the new definition, you can discuss here.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2018-12-10T14:42:10.033" Id="468" LastActivityDate="2018-12-10T14:42:10.033" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="467" PostTypeId="2" Score="1"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I think we have a big enough positive response that it is time to secure commitments from prospective writers. As Jan mentions in the comments, perhaps another meta question would be the best way to do that. Really, we only need one or two writers to make it work as long as they can post regularly enough.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2018-12-11T16:25:45.070" Id="469" LastActivityDate="2018-12-11T16:25:45.070" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="460" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row AnswerCount="6" Body="&lt;p&gt;About a month ago, &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/q/460/2153&quot;&gt;I set forth the idea for an unofficial blog&lt;/a&gt; for Astronomy Stack Exchange. It's garnered &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; support so far for the idea, but we need to know that people are actually willing to contribute content to it. I don't know what we &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; put out, but maybe a post a week might be sustainable. If we were to get, say, four or five people working on it, then one post per person per month would be all that's needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you think you'll be able to contribute, please write an answer below, ideally listing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What topics you think you might want to write about.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;em&gt;conservative&lt;/em&gt; estimate of how often you might be able to write. Don't feel pressured to commit to anything yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anything else you feel is relevant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's also fine if you don't write an answer and later end up contributing, but if you &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; think you'll contribute - well, that would be useful data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll leave this featured for a week or so, then see where we're at.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="7" CreationDate="2018-12-11T19:22:29.600" FavoriteCount="1" Id="470" LastActivityDate="2019-02-13T01:42:33.130" LastEditDate="2019-01-03T15:26:37.570" LastEditorUserId="2153" OwnerUserId="2153" PostTypeId="1" Score="6" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;site-promotion&gt;&lt;blog&gt;" Title="Do you want to write for our blog?" ViewCount="221"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I would be willing to write about exoplanets, stellar imaging, and planetary formation. Most of what I would write would be derivative (I would read papers and compile/summarize), but I would provide a little perspective from my point of view as an aerospace software engineer and long-time astronomy fan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could probably only write maybe every few months, or maybe every other month.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2018-12-11T19:37:28.310" Id="471" LastActivityDate="2018-12-11T19:37:28.310" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="470" PostTypeId="2" Score="5"/>
  <row AnswerCount="0" Body="&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year! Last month we took a close look at the topic of &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/q/467/6&quot;&gt;dust&lt;/a&gt;. This month's focus tag is &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/tidal-forces&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;tidal-forces&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;tidal-forces&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Featured Question:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/12269/6&quot;&gt;How did Mars come to have a 24 hour 39 minute day?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This question covers the impact of tidal forces on the rotation of planets, giving us a good look at the topic at hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The monthly focus tag is an opportunity for us to learn more about a topic and improve the site by taking a look at a particular area. Please take this opportunity to look at the questions and answers in &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/tidal-forces&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;tidal-forces&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;tidal-forces&lt;/a&gt;. If you see anything that could be improved, take the opportunity to edit. If you have follow-up questions, go ahead and ask them (with the appropriate tag, of course). If you happen to know the answer to an unanswered question, we'd appreciate your input!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, this is a good chance to take a look at the tag excerpt and wiki. If it is empty or could be improved, perhaps you could help us out?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to use the answer space below to make community wiki lists of posts in need of editing, or to brainstorm ideas of what to add to the tag excerpt and wiki. Not sure about a particular &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/tidal-forces&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;tidal-forces&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;tidal-forces&lt;/a&gt; question you have? Go ahead and share your concerns below, so we can help guide you to framing the question on the site.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2019-01-02T13:42:04.633" FavoriteCount="1" Id="480" LastActivityDate="2019-02-18T21:26:41.927" LastEditDate="2019-02-18T21:26:41.927" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;focus-tag&gt;" Title="This month's focus tag: tidal-forces" ViewCount="89"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="488" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/observation&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;observation&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;observation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/observational-astronomy&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;observational-astronomy&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;observational-astronomy&lt;/a&gt; seem to more or less mean the same thing. Should these tags be merged? Which name should be favored?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2019-01-17T15:54:52.777" Id="486" LastActivityDate="2019-01-31T18:18:35.113" LastEditDate="2019-01-31T18:18:35.113" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="4" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;status-completed&gt;&lt;tags&gt;&lt;merge-request&gt;" Title="Should [observation] and [observational-astronomy] be merged?" ViewCount="55"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="489" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;I think the &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/science&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;science&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;science&lt;/a&gt; tag should be removed, and maybe even blacklisted from the site. The way it is currently used it does not really mean anything, and I don't really see it being that fruitful of a tag on a site focused on a scientific discipline--everything could be said to be science-related.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thoughts?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2019-01-18T19:29:00.950" Id="487" LastActivityDate="2019-01-31T18:19:00.533" LastEditDate="2019-01-31T18:19:00.533" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="8" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;status-completed&gt;&lt;tags&gt;" Title="Destroy the [science] tag" ViewCount="88"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The only difference seems to be that observation discusses a singular object, and observational-astronomy discusses multiple. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looks to me that these tags could be merged since basically observational-astronomy encompasses observation and questions could be altered to define if the question is about a singular object or multiple.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2019-01-18T21:34:47.620" Id="488" LastActivityDate="2019-01-18T21:34:47.620" OwnerUserId="25592" ParentId="486" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;To the best of my understanding, the kind of vague, high-level &quot;meta&quot; tag that &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/science&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;science&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;science&lt;/a&gt; represents is generally discouraged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I agree - kill it with malice.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2019-01-22T15:07:55.363" Id="489" LastActivityDate="2019-01-22T15:07:55.363" OwnerUserId="38" ParentId="487" PostTypeId="2" Score="9"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="493" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;I question the need for having separate &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/time&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;time&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;time&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/date-time&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;date-time&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;date-time&lt;/a&gt; tags. I think those concepts will rarely be distinct in terms of the questions we have here. What do you think? My inclination would be to merge &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/date-time&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;date-time&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;date-time&lt;/a&gt; into &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/time&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;time&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;time&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2019-02-08T15:58:47.903" FavoriteCount="1" Id="492" LastActivityDate="2019-08-30T18:20:18.217" LastEditDate="2019-08-30T18:20:18.217" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="5" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;status-completed&gt;&lt;tags&gt;" Title="Is there really a use to having separate [time] and [date-time] tags?" ViewCount="61"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/time&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;time&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;time&lt;/a&gt; tag currently has 17 questions, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/date-time&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;date-time&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;date-time&lt;/a&gt; currently has 58. Neither of them have a tag wiki. They seem to be used for exactly the same purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think we should 1) make &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/date-time&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;date-time&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;date-time&lt;/a&gt; a synonym of &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/time&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;time&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;time&lt;/a&gt;, 2) add a tag wiki for &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/time&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;time&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;time&lt;/a&gt;, 3) retag questions that don't follow the new tag wiki.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2019-02-13T01:38:51.063" Id="493" LastActivityDate="2019-02-13T01:38:51.063" OwnerUserId="24758" ParentId="492" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row AnswerCount="0" Body="&lt;p&gt;Sorry for the delay in the focus tag this month! Last month we took a close look at the topic of &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/q/480/6&quot;&gt;tidal forces&lt;/a&gt;. This month's focus tag is &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/white-dwarf&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;white-dwarf&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;white-dwarf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Featured Question:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/25900/6&quot;&gt;Is there a possibility that a white dwarf can turn into a neutron star or a black hole?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nature of white dwarfs is covered in some detail in order to answer the title question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This month we also have a blog post related to the topic: &lt;a href=&quot;https://aneyeontheuniverse.wordpress.com/2019/02/18/can-merging-white-dwarfs-form-variable-stars/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Can merging white dwarfs form variable stars?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The monthly focus tag is an opportunity for us to learn more about a topic and improve the site by taking a look at a particular area. Please take this opportunity to look at the questions and answers in &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/white-dwarf&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;white-dwarf&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;white-dwarf&lt;/a&gt;. If you see anything that could be improved, take the opportunity to edit. If you have follow-up questions, go ahead and ask them (with the appropriate tag, of course). If you happen to know the answer to an unanswered question, we'd appreciate your input!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, this is a good chance to take a look at the tag excerpt and wiki. If it is empty or could be improved, perhaps you could help us out? Don't forget to follow the guidelines for writing good &lt;a href=&quot;https://meta.stackexchange.com/q/214337/274942&quot;&gt;tag wikis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to use the answer space below to make community wiki lists of posts in need of editing, or to brainstorm ideas of what to add to the tag excerpt and wiki. Not sure about a particular &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/white-dwarf&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;white-dwarf&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;white-dwarf&lt;/a&gt; question you have? Go ahead and share your concerns below, so we can help guide you to framing the question on the site.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="11" CreationDate="2019-02-18T21:26:34.187" Id="494" LastActivityDate="2019-02-21T14:47:50.370" LastEditDate="2019-02-21T14:47:50.370" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="9" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;focus-tag&gt;" Title="This month's focus tag: white-dwarf" ViewCount="107"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="504" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;Both the &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/chemistry&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;chemistry&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;chemistry&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/astrochemistry&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;astrochemistry&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;astrochemistry&lt;/a&gt; tags have over a dozen questions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However there are only four questions that have both tags, and three of those are mine, probably in anticipation that they might be merged in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do we need both as tags?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If so, what is the difference?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If not, should they be merged?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are questions that are tagged &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/chemistry&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;chemistry&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;chemistry&lt;/a&gt;, categorized by how well I estimate that &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/astrochemistry&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;astrochemistry&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;astrochemistry&lt;/a&gt; would suffice and a separate &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/chemistry&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;chemistry&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;chemistry&lt;/a&gt; tag would not be needed. I'm wondering if &quot;chemistry&quot; is even the proper tag or something like &quot;geochemistry&quot; or &quot;planetary-chemistry&quot; might be a better name for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/astrochemistry&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;astrochemistry&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;astrochemistry&lt;/a&gt; tag will probably suffice:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/31649/7982&quot;&gt;Have caged molecules ever been observed in space?&lt;/a&gt; unless Rob Jeffries’ “clathrates” end up being on/inside planets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/30533/7982&quot;&gt;Why was helium hydride (HeH+) the universe's first molecule?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/30091/7982&quot;&gt;What is the organic material in Saturn's rings?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/16380/7982&quot;&gt;Is the composition of stars in future made of more and more heavy elements?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/14170/7982&quot;&gt;What is the distribution of organic compounds in the Milky Way Galaxy?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/12381/7982&quot;&gt;What happens to oxygen produced on the Sun (or other stars)?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/10510/7982&quot;&gt;Why are there no green stars?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/10091/7982&quot;&gt;Why is there so much methane in space?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/10016/7982&quot;&gt;Internal heat and planetary differentiation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not sure, depends on what &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/astrochemistry&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;astrochemistry&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;astrochemistry&lt;/a&gt; means:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/26287/7982&quot;&gt;Is there any difference among exoplanets in composition due to host star?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/21378/7982&quot;&gt;What is germane doing in the atmosphere of Jupiter?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/20081/7982&quot;&gt;What aliphatic compounds were found on Ceres, and how where they identified?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/19129/7982&quot;&gt;What factors influence the Widmanstätten pattern in iron meteorites?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/astrochemistry&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;astrochemistry&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;astrochemistry&lt;/a&gt; probably not the proper tag:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/19440/7982&quot;&gt;What could be the possible origin of boron found in the Martian soil if not from ancient groundwater?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/18976/7982&quot;&gt;Massive degraded impact crater on Mercury - chemical evidence?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/10097/7982&quot;&gt;Statistics of elements abundance in exoplanets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/19627/7982&quot;&gt;Can a planet with a hydrogen atmosphere have a water ocean with dissolved oxygen? (closed)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2019-04-27T00:21:56.787" Id="503" LastActivityDate="2019-08-30T18:24:13.657" LastEditDate="2019-08-30T18:24:13.657" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="7982" PostTypeId="1" Score="2" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;status-completed&gt;&lt;tags&gt;&lt;tag-synonyms&gt;" Title="What is the difference between the &quot;chemistry&quot; and &quot;astrochemistry&quot; tags?" ViewCount="44"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I don't think we need both tags. I suggest merging the &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/chemistry&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;chemistry&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;chemistry&lt;/a&gt; questions into &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/astrochemistry&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;astrochemistry&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;astrochemistry&lt;/a&gt;, as we have &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/astrobiology&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;astrobiology&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;astrobiology&lt;/a&gt; but no biology tag. I don't think we should create a synonym between chemistry and astrochemistry though. &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/chemistry&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;chemistry&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;chemistry&lt;/a&gt; only has four uses this year, so I don't think it will be a big deal to retag manually in the future. That said, we should keep our eyes out for questions that use &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/chemistry&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;chemistry&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;chemistry&lt;/a&gt; for questions that are not related to astrochemistry (e.g. planetary geochemistry). If we have any of those, we should keep the chemistry tag and add a tag wiki to clarify its use.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="8" CreationDate="2019-04-28T15:47:48.000" Id="504" LastActivityDate="2019-04-28T15:47:48.000" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="503" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="516" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;The well-received and hot network question &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/32059/7982&quot;&gt;If a massive object like Jupiter flew past the Earth how close would it need to come to pull people off of the surface?&lt;/a&gt; includes the phrase&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I understand this is a silly hypothetical but I'm asking for a 7 year old so please  with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently there is a pending edit replacing the emoticon with the word &lt;em&gt;bear&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The emoji/emoticon shown is a representation of a bear, and bear (noun) is a homophone for bear (verb) which according to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.queens-english-society.com/bear-with-me-or-bare-with-me&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Queen's English Society&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup&gt;†&lt;/sup&gt; can be understood as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bear with me definition:&lt;/strong&gt; Bear with me is an expression that means hear me out or be patient. A convention speaker might say bear with me if his or her slideshow isn’t working, or a minister might use the phrase while turning to the correct scriptural passage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it too early to have a discussion about the use of emoji to replace written English in situations where the written text would already be concise and clear?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;note:&lt;/strong&gt; This question is not about the use of an occasional humorous or decorative instance as a tiny aside to an otherwise clear passage written in English as demonstrated in the footnote below. It's only about &lt;em&gt;replacing or substituting&lt;/em&gt; clear English by homophonic emoticons or similar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;†&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Queens, NY&lt;/strong&gt; English Society; not what you thought! ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2019-05-28T05:41:43.930" Id="515" LastActivityDate="2019-05-28T17:20:50.893" LastEditDate="2019-05-28T13:45:26.453" LastEditorUserId="7982" OwnerUserId="7982" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;emoji&gt;" Title="Can we  to have emoji in posts?" ViewCount="68"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I would not substitute emojis for actual speech, as that provides an additional obstacle for non-native English speakers and could potentially cause the question to be misunderstood in any case. If an emoji is used in this way, please edit out the emojis and replace with the appropriate words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would not recommend casual use of emojis, like smiles, etc. either because that invokes a chatty tone that we try to avoid here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is an acceptable use of emojis: when it is actually relevant to the question. This may not happen often here, but if an emoji got used in astronomical discourse (e.g. a Twitter post by a professional astronomer) in such a way that its use was actually relevant to astronomy then the emoji should be included in the post asking about that here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E.g. &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/18324/why-is-the-symbol-of-vernal-equinox&quot;&gt;Why is the symbol of Vernal Equinox ♈?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You originally asked this on Space Exploration, though it seems you intended to ask it here after all, but that also brings to mind a situation where Elon Musk or someone like that might use an emoji in a rocketry post in a context having to do with the rocket--the emoji might be suited to a Space Exploration question in that case.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2019-05-28T12:24:36.303" Id="516" LastActivityDate="2019-05-28T17:20:50.893" LastEditDate="2019-05-28T17:20:50.893" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="515" PostTypeId="2" Score="5"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="519" AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;I've asked a question for which I feel a zero score to be appropriate, and I have no objections to any of the comments posted about it, but it has content, and has received comments, which I feel may remain useful to others asking similar questions for a long time.  A couple of keywords (the surname of a major physicist [Poplawski] and a two-word phrase representing a fairly common concept [&quot;galactic rotation&quot;]) that are in it currently appear at the top of more than 400 results in a google search, so I feel that its preservation may save considerable time for persons who are students or researchers in the future, in a way similar to the way in which the marking of questions as duplicates may save them time.  Consequently, I'm wondering how long it would be left accessible on the site after its closure.  &lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2019-06-18T18:17:06.047" FavoriteCount="0" Id="518" LastActivityDate="2019-07-04T23:19:43.763" OwnerUserId="22115" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;support&gt;" Title="How long, under current policy (as of 6/18/2019), do closed questions remain visible?" ViewCount="44"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Duplicate questions are never deleted automatically, and rarely (if ever) deleted manually. They stick around to help direct people to the appropriate question. Often duplicates come up because there is more than one way to ask a question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For non-duplicate closed questions, they are only auto-deleted in certain situations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ol start=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The system will automatically delete any post flagged six times as offensive or spam (3 times on English Language &amp;amp; Usage and The Workplace).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The system will automatically delete closed, unlocked questions with zero or negative score having no positively scored or accepted answers or pending reopen votes, that were closed for any reason other than duplicate nine or more days ago and haven't been edited in the past nine days. (RemoveAbandonedClosed)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The system will automatically delete rejected migrations (questions created as a result of a question from another site being migrated there, and later closed for any reason other than duplicate) that are at least 30 days old. (RemoveRejectedMigrations)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The system will automatically delete negatively-scored, unlocked, and unanswered questions (both open and closed, including as duplicates) that are older than 30 days. (RemoveDeadQuestions)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The system will automatically delete unlocked, unanswered questions older than 365 days on main (non-meta) sites with score of zero (or one, if the owner's account is deleted), fewer than 1.5 views per day on average, and fewer than two comments. (RemoveAbandonedQuestions)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The system will automatically delete any post with a negative score when its owner's account is deleted, unless the post is a question that has at least one positively-scored answer. (This doesn't apply on meta sites.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The system will automatically delete any post, regardless of score or answers to questions, when its owner's account is destroyed (only done for spammers and blatant trolls).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The system will automatically delete migration stubs (original site copies of questions migrated to other sites, which haven't been rejected by the destination site) that are at least 30 days old. Questions deleted under this criterion still have their revision histories visible to everyone, and links to them redirect to the new question instead of showing an error page. (RemoveMigrationStubs)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Posts with zero or negative score that receive six recommend deletion reviews (four on Stack Overflow) in the low-quality-posts review queue are automatically deleted &quot;from review&quot;. Posts can be kicked into this queue either automatically or with very low quality and not an answer flags, and can be removed from the queue if enough Looks OK reviews are cast against them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(From &lt;a href=&quot;https://meta.stackexchange.com/a/5222/228367&quot;&gt;How does deleting work? What can cause a post to be deleted, and what does that actually mean? What are the criteria for deletion?&lt;/a&gt; on Meta Stack Exchange)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that except in special circumstances, closed questions with positive scores and/or positively scored or accepted answers and/or pending reopen votes are not auto-deleted.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2019-06-19T13:37:57.530" Id="519" LastActivityDate="2019-06-19T13:37:57.530" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="518" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="523" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;The question &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/32410/7982&quot;&gt;If two black hole event horizons overlap (touch) can they ever separate again?&lt;/a&gt; is well received with +32 upvotes currently and has two well received answers with +32 and +24 votes as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are now two votes to close as duplicate of &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/13551/7982&quot;&gt;highspeed black holes or neutron stars on (almost) head-on collision course and kinetic energy&lt;/a&gt; where votes on the question and its two answers added together are +3. +5 and +2 respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new &quot;event horizons overlap&quot; question and its answers have all generated substantial, on-topic high-level discourse in comments as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder if the first vtc as duplicate simply found something that sounded related &lt;em&gt;and was older&lt;/em&gt; without attention to the relative quality. Based on votes alone, if one felt to dupe anything one might chose to vtc &lt;em&gt;in the opposite direction&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The topic is sophisticated and I can't judge the degree of overlap to make any call about the necessity of closing either question as duplicate of the other, but I think the current vote is unproductive and will steer attention away from some very well received posts.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2019-06-26T01:57:15.980" Id="522" LastActivityDate="2019-06-26T13:28:46.087" LastEditDate="2019-06-26T08:49:37.300" LastEditorUserId="7982" OwnerUserId="7982" PostTypeId="1" Score="1" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;specific-question&gt;&lt;vote-to-close&gt;&lt;exact-duplicates&gt;" Title="Should this question about touching event horizons really be closed as duplicate?" ViewCount="33"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The questions and answers are extremely correlated to the degree I would feel uncomfortable unilaterally reversing a close action, but I agree both discussions seem helpful. Just keep tabs on it, and it if gets closed cast a reopen vote. Duplicates don't go away anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2019-06-26T13:28:46.087" Id="523" LastActivityDate="2019-06-26T13:28:46.087" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="522" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="529" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;I'd left a &quot;lead by example&quot; comment addressed to the user who wrote an &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/32654/what-would-happen-if-a-sun-like-star-were-to-consume-a-jupiter-like-planet#comment60259_32654&quot;&gt;extended comment&lt;/a&gt; about why they'd chosen to immediately close &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/32654/7982&quot;&gt;What would happen if a Sun-like star were to consume a Jupiter-like planet?&lt;/a&gt; rather than ask for clarification or propose an edit, and a comment to another user who &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/32654/what-would-happen-if-a-sun-like-star-were-to-consume-a-jupiter-like-planet#comment60262_32654&quot;&gt;suggests&lt;/a&gt; the question &quot;falls under the hypothetical scenarios rule&quot;. (There is no such &quot;rule&quot;, we only have suggested guidelines for on-topic-ness which is subjective and needs to be addressed on a case-by-case basis)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I see it, on a site with a low question rate, there's no benefit at all to insta-closing a good question that simply needs a bit of work. &quot;Leading by example&quot; means showing a new user, posting their first question, the best way to improve it by making an edit. Having an example is likely much easier for a new Stack Exchange user to understand than to simply close and point to help. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, that was the old way, but it's far less welcoming than being helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question:&lt;/strong&gt; Why was my comment deleted, and this this replacement comment okay?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My new comment is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I've voted to leave this question open. Rather than voting to close, I've made an edit to improve the question. Closing would have blocked anyone from answering further. There were 4 vtc votes; one more vote would have instantly blocked &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/a/32695/7982&quot;&gt;this excellent, thorough and authoritative answer&lt;/a&gt; from being posted!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily at least one of the vtc were retracted, possibly in response to my two (now deleted) requests for vtc retraction. This likely facilitated @RobJeffries opportunity to post the answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm pretty sure my way is better in these cases (helpful comments and exemplary edits versus insta-closing) and I think facilitating the linked answer is evidence of this, &lt;em&gt;so I'm interested to understand what was delete-worthy in my comment, and how could I have composed it differently to encourage keeping good questions open.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2019-07-18T03:03:30.137" Id="528" LastActivityDate="2019-07-18T15:08:06.580" LastEditDate="2019-07-18T03:16:18.350" LastEditorUserId="7982" OwnerUserId="7982" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;specific-question&gt;&lt;close-reasons&gt;&lt;vote-to-close&gt;" Title="Why was my comment deleted, and this this replacement comment okay?" ViewCount="48"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The original comment was seen as being too confrontational, and I could see where they were coming from. The new one looks fine.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2019-07-18T15:08:06.580" Id="529" LastActivityDate="2019-07-18T15:08:06.580" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="528" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;Here are four related tags and their current question count:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/spectroscopy&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;spectroscopy&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;spectroscopy&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;s&gt;(100)&lt;/s&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/32750/7982&quot;&gt;101&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/spectra&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;spectra&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;spectra&lt;/a&gt;  (60)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/spectrum&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;spectrum&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;spectrum&lt;/a&gt;  (13)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/spectrometry&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;spectrometry&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;spectrometry&lt;/a&gt;  (10)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are three related questions about them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As terms and as techniques, &lt;strong&gt;spectrometry&lt;/strong&gt; is distinct from &lt;strong&gt;spectroscopy&lt;/strong&gt;, but I am not sure we need both tags to distribute questions between. Would there be any harm in consolidating them under spectroscopy?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any harm in consolidating &lt;strong&gt;spectrum&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;spectra&lt;/strong&gt; under the plural form? (&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/q/520/7982&quot;&gt;singular/plural issue&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any benefits or harm to then (eventually) consolidating &lt;strong&gt;spectroscopy&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;spectra&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that synonymization might be the thing to do, but honestly I don't understand the options and tradeoffs to propose anything with confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is some fairly obvious re-tagging that could be done right away (I'll put a list here in a while) but I didn't want to start doing that until some discussion here first.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2019-07-22T00:42:44.530" Id="530" LastActivityDate="2019-08-13T20:17:08.460" LastEditDate="2019-08-13T20:17:08.460" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="7982" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;status-completed&gt;&lt;tags&gt;&lt;tag-synonyms&gt;&lt;retagging&gt;" Title="Spectroscopy Spectrometry Spectra and Spectrum tags; is there room for some consolidation?" ViewCount="20"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;All of them have a substantial number of questions, but you are right that spectrum should be consolidated under spectra. Otherwise, I think we should probably leave them be, but spectrometry needs a tag excerpt.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2019-07-22T12:33:03.293" Id="531" LastActivityDate="2019-07-22T12:33:03.293" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="530" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row AnswerCount="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;Indian Astrology has mentioned about the basics of modern astrology. Apart from Varaha Samhita any other texts available on Indian Astrology/ Jyotish?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2019-10-05T13:23:43.937" Id="536" LastActivityDate="2019-10-15T23:07:48.840" OwnerDisplayName="sri tulasi" OwnerUserId="30582" PostTypeId="1" Score="4" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;" Title="Can we consider Indian Astrology as astronomy?" ViewCount="72"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;We have ruled in this community that astrology of any sort, despite its historical entanglement with astronomy, is off-topic because of the pseudoscience mentioned by Anders. That said, if the questions are motivated by astrological sources but concern only astronomical phenomena, then they are on topic. Also, we have allowed questions about devices (such as symbols) that are in use in astronomy where the answer lies in the history of astrology.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2019-10-07T14:03:53.900" Id="538" LastActivityDate="2019-10-07T14:03:53.900" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="536" PostTypeId="2" Score="6"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="540" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;My question &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/33606/7982&quot;&gt;Who is Sifter, and what is “the so-called Sifter flare”&lt;/a&gt; exists only because the linked BBC news item wrote &quot;Sifter flare&quot; where it should have written &lt;strong&gt;Seyfert flare&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BBC News article has since been fixed, so &quot;Sifter&quot; no longer appears anywhere, which makes me wonder if I should just update my question to read&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Who is Seyfert, and what is “the so-called Seyfert flare”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The change might make the question and its authoritative answer appear in more searches which is a good thing, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/search?q=+Seyfert+flare&quot;&gt;a search for &quot; Seyfert flare&quot;&lt;/a&gt; shows no other posts that it could end up being duped to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can't think of any reasons not to update the question, except that it makes my &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/33606/who-is-sifter-and-what-is-the-so-called-sifter-flare#comment63735_33608&quot;&gt;reference to&lt;/a&gt; a previous BBC error &lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/q/454554/83380&quot;&gt;about the colliding of &quot;large hadrons&quot;&lt;/a&gt; less obvious. (They edited once but there are still two references to the collision of large hadrons with other things).&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2019-10-08T12:24:05.097" Id="539" LastActivityDate="2019-10-08T14:52:18.437" LastEditDate="2019-10-08T12:30:08.280" LastEditorUserId="7982" OwnerUserId="7982" PostTypeId="1" Score="2" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;specific-question&gt;" Title="Should I change the title of my question to make the results more searchable?" ViewCount="21"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;My opinion is yes, change the title, but don't remove Sifter from the text post. Just add some language that it was originally phrased that way.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2019-10-08T14:52:18.437" Id="540" LastActivityDate="2019-10-08T14:52:18.437" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="539" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row AnswerCount="0" Body="&lt;p&gt;To hopefully alleviate concerns regarding the new &lt;a href=&quot;https://space.stackexchange.com/conduct&quot;&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;, I want to explain how I intend to moderate regarding pronoun use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When speaking generically, posts should use gender neutral language (which per the Code of Conduct means, for example, &quot;they&quot; not &quot;he or she&quot;). If a post doesn't, I will not be removing it on sight. If flagged, I will comment asking the user to make an edit. If they refuse, I will point them to the Code of Conduct and inform them of behavior expected on this site. If they cannot agree to abide by the Code of Conduct, I will remove their post. If a user is not active, I may elect to edit the post for them while waiting for their reply. I will not be seeking out posts to see if they comply. As usual, I will rely on flagging or whatever I happen to come across in my normal perusal of the site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number 1 does not apply to quotes. I will not require anyone to make editorial mark-ups of quotes to ensure they comply.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When referring to other users on the site, posts should use gender neutral language until asked otherwise. If you want to check someone's bio to see if they've specified, you're welcome to, but I won't expect you to. Once asked to use a certain set of pronouns, per the Code of Conduct, you should use that set. If you don't and the post is flagged, I will edit the post or remove the comment and leave a comment explaining why. I am letting you know this now so that if you are not comfortable with me putting words in your mouth you will be aware. The reason I will be doing this instead of waiting for users to edit on their own is that leaving unaffirming pronouns around while waiting for edits would make the site unfriendly, per the Code of Conduct. If there is push back or an edit war, I will then handle according to how I would normally handle someone who refuses to follow the rules. I don't really see this coming up, but if a quote of some external source happens to refer to a known user of this site and uses the wrong pronouns, then you should use appropriate editorial conventions (brackets to replace incorrect words and a footnote to explain the edit) to rectify the problem. If you slip up and accidentally use the wrong pronouns, it's fine, we'll edit it and move on. There's no reason for moderator action over a mistake.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When referring to specific people not on this site, posts should use whatever pronouns Wikipedia does. You don't have to check in advance if you think you know their pronouns, but if someone edits in or requests a correction and points to the Wikipedia article, you should comply. If there is reason to believe the Wikipedia article is wrong, please leave a comment pointing to the source for the person's pronouns. When a person doesn't have a Wikipedia page, use whatever information you have (e.g. if a news article uses a pronoun, use that). Again, if you think you know their pronouns, you don't have to check in advance, but if someone requests a correction and points to a source (or if by chance the actual person joins the site and requests a correction) then you should oblige.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Obviously, I will use moderator discretion when handling these issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please do not go around editing other people's posts &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; to update their language. If you feel it needs to be updated, comment and/or flag. However, if you are editing for another reason and you also see an opportunity to make something gender neutral that should be, you may edit it, but please leave a comment explaining why.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know this is a lot to process, but really I don't see this coming up very often. As described above, I don't see this really changing the way most of you write 90% of the time. If something I said is unclear or if you have further questions, let me know. If you disagree with the new Code of Conduct, please take that commentary to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://meta.stackexchange.com/q/336366/228367&quot;&gt;official Meta post&lt;/a&gt;. For this discussion, assume we are following the Code of Conduct as directed.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="12" CreationDate="2019-10-10T20:06:10.983" FavoriteCount="1" Id="541" LastActivityDate="2019-11-02T13:56:42.127" LastEditDate="2019-11-02T13:56:42.127" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="9" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;moderation&gt;&lt;editing&gt;" Title="Regarding moderating the new Code of Conduct" ViewCount="275"/>
</posts>