<?xml version="1.0" ?><posts>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="33243" AnswerCount="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;My organization is seeking to replace all &quot;manpower&quot; terminology with gender neutral terms. There are some instances where the conventional abbreviation &quot;EQM&quot;, which stands for &quot;Equivalent Manpower&quot; is used. Is there a commonly accepted substitute for this abbreviation which is gender neutral?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; This is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; a question seeking general answers for terms, and it is thus not a purely opinion based question. This is a question of standards and conventions. If I asked if there is a conventional term in physics for &quot;influence which tends to change the motion of an object&quot; that is not an EL&amp;amp;U question. EL&amp;amp;U could have many answers for a word which means &quot;influence which tends to change the motion of an object&quot;, but in physics there is one standard: &quot;Force&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="6" CreationDate="2014-09-03T14:11:06.563" FavoriteCount="1" Id="33238" LastActivityDate="2014-09-12T17:31:03.613" LastEditDate="2014-09-03T14:43:58.267" LastEditorUserId="9936" OwnerUserId="9936" PostTypeId="1" Score="5" Tags="&lt;management&gt;&lt;terminology&gt;" Title="Is there a commonly accepted gender neutral convention to replace the abbreviation EQM (Equivalent Manpower)?" ViewCount="7742"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Unless someone else can bring any other insights to this, I have discovered the term &lt;strong&gt;equivalent workforce&lt;/strong&gt;, which seems to have replaced &quot;equivalent manpower&quot; (supported by &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/ngrams/graph?content=equivalent+manpower%2Cequivalent+workforce&amp;amp;year_start=1800&amp;amp;year_end=2012&amp;amp;corpus=15&amp;amp;smoothing=3&amp;amp;share=&amp;amp;direct_url=t1%3B%2Cequivalent%20manpower%3B%2Cc0%3B.t1%3B%2Cequivalent%20workforce%3B%2Cc0&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Google Ngrams&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As suggested by Garrison Neely in the comments, there does not appear to be an abbreviation for &quot;equivalent workforce&quot;, but the full term is used instead.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2014-09-03T14:55:10.610" Id="33242" LastActivityDate="2014-09-03T14:55:10.610" OwnerUserId="9936" ParentId="33238" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row Body="&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Is there a commonly accepted substitute for this abbreviation which is
  gender neutral?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My current company (and several others where I have worked) uses the term FTE - Full-time Equivalent. We use that for project planning and staffing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No gender is stated or implied by that term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've heard it used at many companies in my part of the world, but I don't know how to define &quot;commonly accepted substitute&quot; in this context.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="9" CreationDate="2014-09-03T14:58:39.270" Id="33243" LastActivityDate="2014-09-12T17:31:03.613" LastEditDate="2014-09-12T17:31:03.613" LastEditorUserId="7777" OwnerUserId="7777" ParentId="33238" PostTypeId="2" Score="43"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Well, let's leave aside for the moment that &quot;Manpower&quot; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;IS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; gender-neutral (&quot;Man&quot; meaning Mankind, and not males.  Woman is actually a subset/specialization of Man, if you want to break the language down to brass tacks).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ref:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Woman#Etymology&quot;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Woman#Etymology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, I've seen this ridiculous exercise played out a few times, and in all but one, sanity returned when people realized what &quot;Manpower&quot; actually meant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Terms I've seen that you may wish to consider:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workforce Equivalent - WFE  (Oddly enough, was balked at because it &quot;looked like&quot; Wife)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Effective Labor Output - ELO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Equivalent Labor - EQL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, it almost always reverted back to EQM once people understood what the word &quot;Man&quot; actually means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You're being asked to solve a problem that doesn't exist.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="5" CreationDate="2014-09-03T16:43:22.680" Id="33256" LastActivityDate="2014-09-03T16:58:53.820" LastEditDate="2014-09-03T16:58:53.820" LastEditorUserId="9264" OwnerUserId="9264" ParentId="33238" PostTypeId="2" Score="47"/>
  <row AnswerCount="17" Body="&lt;p&gt;I work in a fairly small department, I have 8 coworkers. 7 of them are great, we're good friends, and I love spending time with them - we hang out outside of work often, but usually in groups of 3-4. The other guy has sexually harassed me and my wife separately (my wife doesn't work here), gets really drunk and says racist things, and has to dominate every conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've recently moved to a new house, and I'd like to have my work friends over for a dinner party. I know it would be a ton of fun with the coworkers I'm close with, and this guy would absolutely ruin it. Would it be inappropriate to purposely exclude this guy?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="14" CreationDate="2019-01-15T22:06:12.087" FavoriteCount="10" Id="126543" LastActivityDate="2019-01-21T12:54:06.653" LastEditDate="2019-01-16T22:33:03.190" LastEditorUserId="18654" OwnerUserId="97966" PostTypeId="1" Score="154" Tags="&lt;colleagues&gt;&lt;relationships&gt;" Title="Is it inappropriate to invite all my coworkers except for one person to a private event?" ViewCount="35482"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;There's one potential hole left here by the other answers. If it is a personal party with your friends (whether they are coworkers or not), who you invite is up to you and not a concern of the workplace. However, if the event becomes a venue of discussion related to accomplishing tasks in the workplace, &lt;em&gt;especially if such events recur&lt;/em&gt;, it could become an issue of concern to HR. It depends on whether or not the excluded person has a legitimate case to make that their lack of information obstructed their ability to perform their job at the same level as everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2019-01-17T21:51:07.307" Id="126747" LastActivityDate="2019-01-17T21:51:07.307" OwnerUserId="9936" ParentId="126543" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
</posts>