<?xml version="1.0" ?><posts>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="879" AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;Suppose I would like to calculate the inclination of a satellite from the &lt;strong&gt;ecliptic&lt;/strong&gt;. Would it be possible to do this with an amateur telescope? How would I go about doing so?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: A good answer should tell what kind of telescope an amateur would need, what measurements they would need to make, then what calculations they would have to perform to get the inclination (or the &quot;instantaneous angular measurement from the ecliptic at the time of measurement&quot;).&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-09-24T18:51:54.593" FavoriteCount="3" Id="1" LastActivityDate="2014-02-03T16:49:55.200" LastEditDate="2013-11-01T11:23:02.907" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="31" Tags="&lt;inclination&gt;&lt;amateur-observing&gt;" Title="How do I calculate the inclination of an object with an amateur telescope?" ViewCount="1003"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="45" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;How are exoplanetary atmosphere compositional spectra distinguished from those of the parent star(s), from the composition of the planetary surface or any other factor?  Is it actually possible to determine the atmospheric composition precisely using this method?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are there any specific examples of such an analysis having been performed on an exoplanet?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2013-09-24T18:53:25.647" Id="2" LastActivityDate="2013-09-24T20:44:49.320" OwnerDisplayName="user8" PostTypeId="1" Score="18" Tags="&lt;exoplanet&gt;&lt;atmosphere&gt;" Title="How are the compositional components of exoplanet atmospheres differentiated?" ViewCount="187"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;In theory one should just be able to determine the difference between the spectra during the exoplanet's eclipse of the star and the spectra of the star alone, but in reality equipment is not precise enough for this. To remedy this problem, the analysis is integrated over many eclipses. Some other calibrations are made as well which you can read more about in the paper &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/pdf/astro-ph/0702494.pdf&quot;&gt;A &lt;em&gt;Spitzer&lt;/em&gt; Spectrum of the Exoplanet HD 189733b&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2013-09-24T20:44:49.320" Id="45" LastActivityDate="2013-09-24T20:44:49.320" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="2" PostTypeId="2" Score="9"/>
  <row AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;In a museum in Lviv, I saw a pocket cellular clock. I don't have a photo, but it was a small disc that had 2 or 3 filaments in it which were pointed at the stars (one of them was Andromeda, I think). Through analyzing the position of the stars it was possible to determine the time of the night. I'm not sure if knowing the day of the year was promised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I couldn't find the information about the way the clock was used. Does anyone know how such device was used?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-09-24T21:10:06.683" Id="47" LastActivityDate="2015-01-19T14:16:59.647" LastEditDate="2015-01-19T14:16:59.647" LastEditorUserId="2153" OwnerUserId="42" PostTypeId="1" Score="13" Tags="&lt;star&gt;&lt;constellations&gt;&lt;clock&gt;" Title="How would the pocket cellular clock work?" ViewCount="125"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The device that you saw is called a nocturnal. It calculates the local time based on the month of the year and the position of Polaris and one or more other stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since stars change position throughout the night, they can be used to determine time; but the positions of stars change throughout the year, so the input of the month of the year is needed. Polaris is used as a relatively fixed reference point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More information&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nocturnal_%28instrument%29&quot;&gt;Nocturnal (instrument) - Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-09-24T21:59:32.217" Id="54" LastActivityDate="2013-09-24T21:59:32.217" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="47" PostTypeId="2" Score="10"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="243" AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;For a time, I thought Azimuth is always direction in degrees, 0 for local, geographic north, 90 for east etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, trying to observe moonrise I downloaded an app that gave azimuth in values between (if I recall correctly) -180 and 180, and I think &quot;0&quot; corresponded to south. I tried to read up on that and found very little fragmented information. I found other resources that frustrated me with numbers greater than 360, or provided values commonly associated with &quot;West&quot; for azimuth of moonrise and generally it took a bit of searching to find something with plain &quot;degrees from north&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could someone either post or provide a link to a comprehensive guide to various azimuth angle systems, when and where they are in use, and how to recognize which one is used?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2013-09-26T13:37:48.340" FavoriteCount="2" Id="237" LastActivityDate="2013-10-14T22:02:27.207" OwnerUserId="83" PostTypeId="1" Score="13" Tags="&lt;navigation&gt;&lt;azimuth&gt;" Title="What azimuth description systems are in use?" ViewCount="158"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Azimuth is conventionally calculated as a degree value between 0 (inclusive) and 360 (exclusive). &lt;strong&gt;North&lt;/strong&gt; is assigned 0 (also by convention), which puts &lt;strong&gt;East&lt;/strong&gt; at 90, &lt;strong&gt;South&lt;/strong&gt; at 180, and &lt;strong&gt;West&lt;/strong&gt; at 270.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes 0 is set to &lt;strong&gt;South&lt;/strong&gt; intead of &lt;strong&gt;North&lt;/strong&gt;. This is the traditional means of measuring solar azimuth, even though &lt;strong&gt;North&lt;/strong&gt; is the most accepted convention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Positive azimuths are noted when measuring east of 0, whether 0 is &lt;strong&gt;South&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;North&lt;/strong&gt;. Negative azimuths are noted when measuring west of 0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.susdesign.com/popups/sunangle/azimuth.php&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Azimuth Angle - Sustainable by Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Solar_azimuth_angle&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Solar azimuth angle - Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.astro.cornell.edu/academics/courses/astro201/alt_az.htm&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Altitude and Azimuth - Martha Haynes, Cornell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-09-26T14:30:39.233" Id="244" LastActivityDate="2013-10-14T22:02:27.207" LastEditDate="2013-10-14T22:02:27.207" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="237" PostTypeId="2" Score="5"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="8685" AnswerCount="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;The Oort cloud is a hypothetical structure based on our observation of long-period comets. There are currently proposals to design probes to confirm the existence of the Oort cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/0/03/Kuiper_oort.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Oort cloud&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, sending a probe would have other benefits, but why can't we observe the Oort cloud with a telescope?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2013-09-26T18:15:26.707" FavoriteCount="2" Id="254" LastActivityDate="2015-04-02T00:29:39.477" LastEditDate="2017-03-10T09:42:47.007" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="18" Tags="&lt;observational-astronomy&gt;&lt;oort-cloud&gt;" Title="Why can't we observe the Oort cloud with a telescope?" ViewCount="1885"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="708" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;A lot of pop science articles (for example, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.space.com/20330-cosmic-microwave-background-explained-infographic.html&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;this Space.com article&lt;/a&gt;) discuss the cold spots on the WMAP data of Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB) radiation, but have any studies been done on the large mass of hot spots on the right of the image below?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/KUwaF.png&quot; alt=&quot;CMB data from WMAP&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this a side-effect of our observation methods or does it represent some actual feature of the early history of the Universe?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-10-02T18:52:26.703" FavoriteCount="4" Id="475" LastActivityDate="2013-10-19T17:13:05.177" LastEditDate="2013-10-18T12:29:01.820" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="12" Tags="&lt;cosmology&gt;&lt;cmb&gt;" Title="What is the mass of hotspots in the Cosmic Microwave Background radiation?" ViewCount="486"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="527" AnswerCount="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;This effect is frequently discussed in the context of solar time series. In particular, it a relationship between soft x-ray (thermal emission) and hard x-ray (nonthermal emission) from the Sun.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-10-08T13:52:36.570" Id="526" LastActivityDate="2018-12-26T16:35:36.367" OwnerUserId="117" PostTypeId="1" Score="14" Tags="&lt;the-sun&gt;" Title="What is the Neupert Effect?" ViewCount="292"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The Neupert Effect describes the commonly observed phenomenon that hard X-rays occur predominantly during the rise phase of soft X-rays during a solar flare, as illustrated by the graph below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/4tw1y.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Neupert Effect during a flare observed by Yohkoh&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the graph, the first peak is that of the hard X-rays, which you can see occurs during the rise of the other line which represents the soft X-rays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://solar.physics.montana.edu/nuggets/1998/981016/981016.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;The Neupert Effect - Solar Physics at Montana State University&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-10-08T13:58:50.323" Id="527" LastActivityDate="2018-12-26T12:19:30.293" LastEditDate="2018-12-26T12:19:30.293" LastEditorUserId="7472" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="526" PostTypeId="2" Score="14"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="530" AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;I've read once a popular science book, in which the author calculated how long would it take for the most massive black holes to evaporate because of Hawking radiation. He claimed that after that time the Universe will be the soup filled only with elementary particles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, what would happen with celestial bodies that aren't black holes? For example, a rogue planet of the size of Earth, drifting somewhere in deep space, in an extremely cold Universe? What known effects would cause that planet to evaporate? How long would it take?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2013-10-08T20:06:04.260" FavoriteCount="1" Id="529" LastActivityDate="2016-04-18T20:20:10.140" LastEditDate="2015-11-06T17:12:56.923" LastEditorUserId="2365" OwnerUserId="42" PostTypeId="1" Score="11" Tags="&lt;cosmology&gt;" Title="How long would it take for a rogue planet to evaporate in the late stages of the Universe?" ViewCount="499"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Before the evaporation of black holes that you mention, our universe will enter what is known as the &lt;strong&gt;Black Hole Era&lt;/strong&gt;. About $10^{40}$ years from now, all the protons and neutrons in the universe will have decayed into positrons and neutrinos. This is how the last of the planets will pass away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Black Hole Era is so named because at this point only black holes and elementary particles will remain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be noted that there is currently no evidence for proton decay, and so this phase of the Universe is strictly theoretical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.deepastronomy.com/the-decay-of-heaven.html&quot;&gt;The Decay of Heaven - DeepAstronomy.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-10-08T20:22:36.780" Id="530" LastActivityDate="2016-04-14T19:03:09.143" LastEditDate="2016-04-14T19:03:09.143" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="529" PostTypeId="2" Score="13"/>
  <row AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Summa_Technologiae&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Summa Technologiae&lt;/a&gt;, a book by a Polish author &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stanis%C5%82aw_Lem&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Stanisław Lem&lt;/a&gt; that based his science fiction novels on scientific research of the era, the Earth crossed in the moment of forming of life the arms of the Galaxy, with high supernovae activity, which triggered life creation. Afterwards, it moved to regions with low supernovae activity, which enabled the preservation of existing life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd like to test the validity of this claim against current research. How often does the Earth cross regions with higher concentrations of stars (and therefore, much greater chance of gamma burst wipe)? Additionally, how many times the probability of nearby supernova explosion is higher in that regions?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2013-10-08T20:39:08.893" Id="531" LastActivityDate="2014-01-14T17:27:42.957" LastEditDate="2013-10-12T07:26:50.137" LastEditorUserId="13" OwnerUserId="42" PostTypeId="1" Score="11" Tags="&lt;earth&gt;&lt;galaxy&gt;&lt;milky-way&gt;&lt;supernova&gt;" Title="How often does Earth cross the galaxy regions with higher supernovae activity?" ViewCount="225"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="584" AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;I have &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nbcnews.com/science/space-radiation-concerns-holding-back-female-astronauts-8C11043076&quot;&gt;recently been reading&lt;/a&gt; that space travel is strongly influenced by &quot;space radiation&quot; and how it poses a threat to human space exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does this radiation originate from stars like our Sun, or is it an omnipresent — let's just call it — &lt;em&gt;&quot;force&quot;&lt;/em&gt; in space (such as cosmic noise) that doesn't have any specific source?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, can an amateur astronomer visualize this radiation in some way so as to be able to observe it?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-10-09T08:43:31.667" Id="579" LastActivityDate="2013-12-12T17:24:26.317" LastEditDate="2013-10-09T11:35:34.480" LastEditorUserId="181" OwnerUserId="181" PostTypeId="1" Score="12" Tags="&lt;space&gt;&lt;radiation&gt;" Title="Where does the radiation in space come from and can we observe it?" ViewCount="1508"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;All energized matter emits radiation. Radiation may consist of electromagnetic energy or particles, as covered in another answer. There are two types of radiation--ionizing and non-ionizing. Ionizing radiation is the type that we are predominantly concerned with danger of, because it can turn atoms that it passes through into ions--which is hazardous to human health. Non-ionizing radiation can still be dangerous if it generates enough heat to cause thermal ionization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ionizing radiation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ultraviolet (of 10 to 125 nm wavelength) - electromagnetic radiation that is absorbed by the Earth's atmosphere but is present in space&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;X-ray - relatively harmless in the small doses that we get for medical work, but harmful in greater exposure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gamma radiation - extremely small wavelength electromagnetic radiation emitted during nuclear processes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alpha radiation - two protons and two neutrons bound as a single particle (helium-4 nucleus), cannot penetrate the skin at slow speeds, but high energy alpha particles can pose a danger to human health (cannot penetrate the atmosphere, but present in space)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beta radiation - may be electrons (Beta-minus) or positrons (Beta-plus), do not typically penetrate the atmosphere but can readily penetrate unshielded human tissue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neutron radiation - neutrons emitted by nuclear fission, highly dangerous, readily ionizes and can even make other materials radioactive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Non-ionizing radiation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ultraviolet (lower part of the spectrum) - nonionizing but still high enough energy that it can have some dangerous effects on the human body&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visible light - the electromagnetic energy that we see, about 380-750 nm wavelength&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Infrared - electromagnetic energy emitted by most objects at temperatures that we deal with on a daily basis, about 700 nm to 1 mm wavelength&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microwave - electromagnetic energy of wavelengths from 1 mm to 1 meter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Radio waves - electomagnetic energy of wavelengths greater than infrared&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt; Used &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Radiation&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; as a reference to organize and bolster information &lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In space we have numerous sources of radiation, since all energized matter emits radiation. Stars are a big factor emitting most types of radiation. Supernovae and black holes also emit radiation. Finally, some radiation has been propagating through the universe since the Big Bang. The Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB) radiation gives us a glimpse of the early universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many ways to observe radiation. Traditional telescopes make use of our natural ability to take in visible light and amplify it with lenses. Radio telescopes are also relatively easy for an amateur to get a hold of. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.radiotelescopebuilder.com/How_To_Build_Your_Own_Radio_Telescope_sample.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Here's&lt;/a&gt; some instructions on how to build a simple radio telescope. Near-infrared light can be observed easily by an amateur with a regular telescope and infrared film, but this doesn't give us a lot more detail than visible light. Most infrared from space is absorbed by our atmosphere (&lt;a href=&quot;http://coolcosmos.ipac.caltech.edu/cosmic_classroom/ask_astronomer/faq/obs.shtml&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;more on infrared telescopes&lt;/a&gt;). UV and higher radiation would also be difficult to detect by an amateur since our atmosphere shields us from it, as well as particle radiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As one clever answerer posted, we &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; observe the stunning light effects that occur when particle radiation ionizes the upper atmosphere. Particle radiation is usually deflected by Earth's magnetic field, but sometimes travels along field lines toward the poles which is why the light effects of particle radiation are only observed in the arctic regions as the Northern and Southern lights.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-10-09T13:47:27.637" Id="588" LastActivityDate="2013-12-12T17:24:26.317" LastEditDate="2013-12-12T17:24:26.317" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="579" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="635" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;There are several articles out saying that a Warwick/Cambridge study of ultraviolet spectroscopy data from the Cosmic Origins Spectrograph on the Hubble Space Telescope found a large amount of oxygen in rocky debris around the white dwarf GD 61. They say that this amount of oxygen is indicative of a larger mass (asteroid), that was once composed of the rocky debris, which was 26% water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/4yYg7.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/4yYg7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Asteroid around GD 61&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sub&gt;(source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://images.sciencedaily.com/2013/10/131010142739-large.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;sciencedaily.com&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/sub&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;Image credit: copyright Mark A. Garlick, space-art.co.uk, University of Warwick and University of Cambridge&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I cannot seem to find is how much oxygen the spectroscopic examination found. Also, what methods did they use to determine how much water there would have been based on the level of oxygen?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-10-11T16:38:54.387" FavoriteCount="1" Id="625" LastActivityDate="2019-07-13T11:19:25.173" LastEditDate="2019-07-13T11:19:25.173" LastEditorUserId="7472" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="10" Tags="&lt;water&gt;&lt;spectrometry&gt;" Title="How much oxygen did the Warwick/Cambridge study find in the rocky debris around white dwarf GD 61?" ViewCount="93"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/342/6155/218.full&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Farihi et al. (2013)&lt;/a&gt; (it's a &lt;em&gt;Science&lt;/em&gt; paper, unfortunately I'm not sure its content is freely accessible), they actually measured metal excess in the white dwarf GD 61 (for an astronomer, everything that is nor hydrogen neither helium is a metal). Due to high surface gravity in white dwarfs, any heavy element should sink rapidely in its atmosphere; therefore, they infer that, if you find traces of metals, it means that it comes from accreted material, &quot;polluting&quot; its atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you find oxygen in a white dwarf spectrum, you know that it has to come from somewhere else, and if the white dwarf has a circumstellar disk, it has to come from planetesimals that are accreted from the disk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, what they did was to measure abundances (or upper limit for their abundance) for a bunch of chemical elements (O, Mg, Al, Si, Ca, Fe) and carbon. Then, they could infer different things to determine the total oxygen budget:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a carbon deficiency, that means that carbon abundance has no impact on the total oxygen budget;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elements Mg, Al, Si, Ca, are assumed to be carried as MgO, Al2O3, SiO2, and CaO at their maximum abundance, so once they had these abundances, they could substract it to the total oxygen budget;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The remaining oxygen excess, found in FeO and debris, is interpreted as water-rich (if you want to form FeO, you need water somehow).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's how they were able to determine this water abundance in debris around the white dwarf GD 61.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not sure the oxygen abundance would be very meaningful here, but since you asked for it, it is of -5.95+/-0.13 dex.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2013-10-14T09:43:40.637" Id="635" LastActivityDate="2013-10-14T09:43:40.637" OwnerUserId="88" ParentId="625" PostTypeId="2" Score="4"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="640" AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&quot;https://space.stackexchange.com/a/635/58&quot;&gt;answer&lt;/a&gt; on Space Exploration to a question about Mars says that one reason Mars has such a thin atmosphere is because it lacks a magnetic field to protect it from the effect of double solar winds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/a/636/6&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; MBR explains that Venus does not have a magnetic field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.newscientist.com/data/images/ns/cms/dn8066/dn8066-1_600.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Venus-atmopshere&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;Image credit: ESA&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this is the case, then why has Venus's atmosphere not been stripped away by solar wind like that of Mars?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-10-14T14:30:22.200" FavoriteCount="6" Id="639" LastActivityDate="2016-09-15T01:31:09.703" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:07.017" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="41" Tags="&lt;atmosphere&gt;&lt;magnetic-field&gt;&lt;venus&gt;&lt;solar-wind&gt;" Title="Why has Venus's atmosphere not been stripped away by solar wind?" ViewCount="2753"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Venus has a strong ionosphere that protects it against violent solar winds. So, even though Venus has no intrisic magnetic field, it has an effective, induced magnetic field due to the interaction between the solar winds and the atmosphere, that protects it against solar winds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Venus atmosphere is thick enough to have a consequent ionosphere, that would be the difference between Mars and Venus (and Venus was able to keep a thicker atmosphere due to its greater mass, contrary to Mars).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www-ssc.igpp.ucla.edu/personnel/russell/papers/venus_mag/&quot;&gt;Luhmann &amp;amp; Russell (1997)&lt;/a&gt;,  on Venus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www-ssc.igpp.ucla.edu/personnel/russell/papers/mars_mag/&quot;&gt;Luhmann &amp;amp; Russell (1997)&lt;/a&gt;,  on Mars&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2013-10-14T14:56:26.140" Id="640" LastActivityDate="2013-10-14T14:56:26.140" OwnerUserId="88" ParentId="639" PostTypeId="2" Score="31"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;You just need a telescope with a &quot;wedge&quot; mount, (ie one for polar coordinates,) and not one which is simply a pan-and-tilt mount like commonly used for cameras. (BUT, it might be more fun to do it with a sextant -- see below.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a telescope that has a polar mount, you just need to set it up correctly. That means orienting the base of the mount in the correct north/south direction, and then setting the &quot;wedge&quot; angle to account for your geographic latitude. (Any amateur level scope with a polar mount will have instructions.) When you pan the scope it will sweep celestial lines of equal latitude, and when you tilt the scope it will sweep celestial lines of equal longitude. Point the scope at your target, and read the declination from the scope's mount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hardest part is going to be that the satellite will be moving pretty fast, and its orbit is going to have a continuously varying declination. (Unless you target a satellite in a circular, equatorial orbit. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fun with a sextant&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might be easier to &quot;shoot&quot; the satellite with a simple (search for &quot;Davis Mark 15&quot; on ebay) sextant and something called an &quot;artificial horizon.&quot; You need any liquid reflecting surface... a swimming pool or kiddie pool might work for shooting a moving satellite. (You can buy a small &quot;artificial horizon&quot; that's a few inches square, but you'll never catch the satellite's reflection in that.) Using the sextant you measure the angle between the satellite and its reflection, also noting the compass direction. Then you crunch a bunch of trigonometry. But this is exactly how you practice astronomical navigation star sighting on land.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2013-10-15T14:33:22.527" Id="652" LastActivityDate="2013-10-15T14:33:22.527" OwnerUserId="7" ParentId="1" PostTypeId="2" Score="7"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="691" AnswerCount="4" Body="&lt;p&gt;I have heard that the only planets able to be seen outside the Solar system are Jovian-sized planets with the occasional detection of planets three times the Earth's size. But, as far as I know, we haven't seen any Earth-sized (due to the range of our telescopes?) extrasolar planets. When will we be able to detect them?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-10-17T16:58:32.890" FavoriteCount="1" Id="687" LastActivityDate="2016-05-23T17:57:23.737" LastEditDate="2016-05-23T17:57:23.737" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="160" PostTypeId="1" Score="13" Tags="&lt;exoplanet&gt;&lt;earth-like-planet&gt;&lt;planetary-systems&gt;" Title="When will we be able to detect Earth-sized exoplanets?" ViewCount="405"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;In 2013, the smallest detected exoplanet was Kepler-37-b, which is actually smaller in mass and size than Earth, so we already had a limited ability to detect these size exoplanets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is worth noting that there wasn't any new technology that allowed this advance, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v494/n7438/full/nature11914.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;the paper&lt;/a&gt; linked to by NASA indicates that the same methods were used as they would usually use. Making it remarkable that they were even able to discover something this small.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, even more Earth-sized planets have been detected. One method used to aid in their detection is described as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We account for Kepler's imperfect detectability of such planets by injecting synthetic planet-caused dimmings into the Kepler brightness measurements and recording the fraction detected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://kepler.nasa.gov/Mission/discoveries/kepler37/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Kepler-37 - NASA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/abs/1311.6806&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Prevalence of Earth-size planets orbiting Sun-like stars - Petigura, Howard, and Marcy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2013-10-17T17:18:32.340" Id="691" LastActivityDate="2015-06-18T12:11:59.803" LastEditDate="2015-06-18T12:11:59.803" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="687" PostTypeId="2" Score="14"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="787" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;Some astronomers in Ukraine have estimated that there is a small likelihood (1 in 63,000) that the asteroid &lt;strong&gt;2013 TV&lt;sub&gt;135&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; will strike Earth in 2032. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.spaceanswers.com/news/3673/asteroid-may-impact-in-2032/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don Yeoman of NASA JPL says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;with more observations, I fully expect we will be able to significantly reduce, or rule out entirely, any impact probability for the foreseeable future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can we improve our estimation of the potential threat posed by 2013 TV&lt;sub&gt;135&lt;/sub&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is, what process and techniques are used to calculate and increase the accuracy of our collision threat estimation?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2013-10-18T13:26:42.543" FavoriteCount="1" Id="702" LastActivityDate="2016-05-23T19:15:50.533" LastEditDate="2016-05-23T19:15:50.533" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="6" Tags="&lt;asteroids&gt;&lt;impact&gt;" Title="How can we tell if the asteroid 2013 TV135 will hit Earth in 2032?" ViewCount="412"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I don't remember reading any paper title specifically about the hot spots you refer to, so I guess that they are not as &quot;strange&quot; as the cold spot. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming that the temperature fluctuations are well described by a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gaussian_function&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Gaussian distribution&lt;/a&gt; with mean 2.72548 and variance 0.00057 &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/abs/0911.1955&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;, the probability of having the cold spot of the observed size and temperature is very low. According to &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/pdf/1303.5083v1.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;a recent Planck paper&lt;/a&gt; this probability is of order of 1% or smaller. The probability of the hot spots is larger (1.5 to 5%), making them more &quot;normal&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This probably explains while the cold spot got more attention that the hot ones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Is this a side-effect of our observation methods or does it represent some actual feature of the early history of the Universe?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is tricky. A few scenarios:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The CMB map in the question shows fluctuations of order 10^-4 K. But extracting this signal from observations is very complicated by the fact that on top of the CMB radiation is &quot;polluted&quot; by foreground objects (mostly our own Galaxy, but also extragalactic point and extended sources) that create spurious fluctuations orders of magnitude larger than the CMB ones. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5QvQp5j1hjs&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;This video&lt;/a&gt; is great to have an idea of this. If any of the above foreground components is not well understood or some is not accounted for, we could be left with some residuals that we wrongly interpret as CMB anomalies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The physics we know is the correct one and the cold spot is simply there. But we physicists don't like that in the Universe there are special places&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The cold spot is a signal of new/unknown physics or that our standard model is not correct. For instance could be that the assumption that the CMB is Gaussian could be just wrong and we have to re-think our theories about the early universe&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2013-10-19T17:13:05.177" Id="708" LastActivityDate="2013-10-19T17:13:05.177" OwnerUserId="86" ParentId="475" PostTypeId="2" Score="6"/>
  <row AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;In other terms, did galaxies grow around black holes at their center? &lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-10-20T18:33:24.970" FavoriteCount="1" Id="716" LastActivityDate="2013-10-21T21:35:18.237" LastEditDate="2013-10-21T18:02:27.057" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="159" PostTypeId="1" Score="13" Tags="&lt;black-hole&gt;&lt;cosmology&gt;" Title="Which came first: black holes or galaxies?" ViewCount="256"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="803" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;I would like to see the orionids sometime this week (October 20-26, 2013). What is the best way for me to observe them by naked eye?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, would I be benefitted by trying to look at them with a telescope or or are they too fast and spontaneous for most amateurs to capture?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-10-21T14:46:01.750" Id="720" LastActivityDate="2013-10-30T19:41:35.620" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="5" Tags="&lt;amateur-observing&gt;&lt;meteor&gt;" Title="How can I observe the Orionid Meteor Shower?" ViewCount="66"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;Note: I am not an astrophysicist. If someone with the relevant expertise finds my analysis of the source paper to be invalid, I would appreciate your help with correcting my answer here.&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a somewhat complicated question to answer. Black holes do precede galaxies in the form of primordial black holes which arose in the early Universe from quantum fluctuations. Supermassive black holes (that you find at the center of galaxies) may not come from these, however. There are a few possible ways that supermassive black holes may have formed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Molecular cloud / dwarf galaxies collapsing to form supermassive stars (SMS) which later further collapsed into supermassive black holes (SMBH)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dwarf galaxies forming massive stars which collapse into massive black holes, which later coalesce into SMBHs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Primordial black holes accreting sufficient matter to become massive black holes, which later coalesce into SMBHs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on how strictly you define &quot;galaxy&quot; it does seem most likely that the supermassive black holes formed inside early galaxies, but a type of black hole (primordial black holes) did precede galaxies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://iopscience.iop.org/0004-637X/596/1/34/pdf/0004-637X_596_1_34.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Formation of the First Supermassive Black Holes - Bromm and Loeb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE 10/21/2013&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This just in, recent observations have ruled out the possibility that SMBHs gain mass only through merging with other black holes. For more, see this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.astronomy.com/news/2013/10/gravitational-waves-know-how-black-holes-grow&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Astronomy.com article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-10-21T17:59:19.230" Id="725" LastActivityDate="2013-10-21T21:35:18.237" LastEditDate="2013-10-21T21:35:18.237" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="716" PostTypeId="2" Score="5"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The answer to the first question is: more observations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;That is, what process and techniques are used to calculate and increase the accuracy of our collision threat estimation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You just have to know the orbit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the orbit of asteroids is very complicated to predict, because they are influenced, sometimes dramatically, by the planets and by smaller bodies, like other asteroids, that we might not be able to see. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of this we cannot measure directly the orbital speed of an asteroid. We can only observe changes in the angular position. &lt;strong&gt;If&lt;/strong&gt; we know the distance (which might not be easily measurable) we can at least put a lower limit to the speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic steps to study the orbit of an asteroids are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;find it and try to get a first guess about the position and velocity (this requires multiple observations far enough in time to be able to measure an angular movement)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;plug the position and velocity info (and likely their errors) into a computer simulation that simulate the solar system dynamics. Fast forward the simulation to predict the future orbit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;observe again the asteroid and compare its position with the simulation. Re-estimate position and velocity. Go to point 2.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the orbit can change significantly a continuous interplay between 2. and 3. is necessary. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have an orbit you can estimate the probability for the asteroid to pass near enough to the Moon or Earth to be deflected and hit us. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But thankfully the solar system is huge, we are tiny and moving between the much much larger Sun and Jupiter :D&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-10-25T20:53:00.023" Id="787" LastActivityDate="2014-10-28T14:31:37.193" LastEditDate="2014-10-28T14:31:37.193" LastEditorUserId="86" OwnerUserId="86" ParentId="702" PostTypeId="2" Score="7"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;While this shower is now largely over, the way to best observe meteors is the same for all showers in principle (including coming showers like the Leonids around November 17 and Geminids around December 14).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The name of most showers reference the name of the constellation their radiant (point in the sky the meteors seem to be coming from) lies in. In the case of the Orionids, this is the constellation of Orion, so look in the general direction of (and around) Orion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you suggest, meteors appear unexpectedly and move too fast to be caught with a telescope.  The best way to observe them is to lie down comfortably and use the naked eye.  The key word is &quot;comfortably&quot;: find a comfortable reclining garden chair or lilo and lie down.  That's one half of the comfort; the other is to stay warm.  Even when watching the Perseids in summer you're lying still under an open sky, and for the fall/winter showers mentioned here you'll really want to bundle up and perhaps take a thermos with a hot drink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The comfort is important - there may be several minutes between two meteors and hence lying down is a good way to relax while watching, which will allow you to stay out longer and see more.  It is definitely more relaxed than standing up with your head in your neck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One other tip for &quot;comfort&quot;: many people will enjoy this more in the company of other enthousiasts, and if you're one of them you should consider going out with a few other people.  It will allow you to discuss the meteors just sighted to pass the time between events, or even to help each other to see one (if they're not too fast).&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-10-27T19:26:42.353" Id="803" LastActivityDate="2013-10-30T19:41:35.620" LastEditDate="2013-10-30T19:41:35.620" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="286" ParentId="720" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Any telescope can be made to give you the information that you are looking for.  The first thing that you will need to know is the location of the ecliptic which varies throughout the year.  Or are you looking to find in relation to the the celestial equator?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Celestial_equator&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Celestial_equator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, you would start of the same by find the Declination (D) and Right Ascension (R.A) of the object in question.  You do not need a telescope to find this, unless you are unable to see the object with the naked eye.  If the telescope has a polar mount and is properly set up.  You can read the R.A. and D off of the mount.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otherwise it will require some trigonometry and knowing where you are (at least your latitude)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will need to determine the Altitude and Azimuth of the object.  Which is really just the direction from North and the angle from horizontal that your telescope is pointing.  You could do this with a compass and protractor or even an &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Astrolab&quot;&gt;astrolabe&lt;/a&gt;.  Knowing this you can then convert to R.A and D with the following formulas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$RA = \arctan(\frac{- sin(Az) \times \cos(Alt)}{\cos(Lat) \times \sin(Alt) - \sin(Lat) \times \cos(Az) \times \cos(Alt)})$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$Dec = \arcsin(\sin(Lat) \times \sin(Alt) + \cos(Lat) \times \cos(Alt) \times \cos(Az))$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are looking for the inclination to the ecliptic, so you are mostly concerned with the declination.  The ecliptic changes in declination throughout the year from 0 at the equinox to +/- 23.5 at the solstice.  So your inclination from the ecliptic would be the Declination of your object +/- the Declination of the ecliptic. &lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-11-05T23:46:37.250" Id="879" LastActivityDate="2014-02-03T16:49:55.200" LastEditDate="2014-02-03T16:49:55.200" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="281" ParentId="1" PostTypeId="2" Score="14"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="927" AnswerCount="10" Body="&lt;p&gt;Some asteroids and comets are non-spherical. But is the nature of big things and gravity so that large things in the universe are always spherical? What is the biggest astronomical object in terms of volume out there that's not spherical?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: Astronomical object is a defined term. See &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Astronomical_object&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Astronomical object - Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="7" CreationDate="2013-11-14T18:16:15.383" FavoriteCount="1" Id="925" LastActivityDate="2019-06-06T11:30:03.393" LastEditDate="2013-12-13T15:19:06.770" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="36" PostTypeId="1" Score="11" Tags="&lt;universe&gt;" Title="What's the largest non-spherical astronomical object in the universe?" ViewCount="3479"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The largest sub-galactic astronomical object (in volume) that we know of is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://astropixels.com/diffusenebulae/NGC3372-03.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Carina Nebula&lt;/a&gt;, which is a non-spherical &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Diffuse_nebula#Diffuse_nebulae&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;diffuse nebula&lt;/a&gt;. The Carina Nebula has a radius of about 100 parsecs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/e/ea/Carina_Nebula.jpg/800px-Carina_Nebula.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Carina Nebula&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;Image credit: ESA&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you consider astronomical objects of the galactic scale, then the galaxy &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IC_1101&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;IC 1101&lt;/a&gt; is the largest astronomical object (in volume) that we know of. From Wikipedia:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The galaxy has a diameter of approximately 6 million light years, which makes it currently (as of 2013) the largest known galaxy in terms of breadth. It is the central galaxy of a massive cluster containing a mass (mostly dark matter) of roughly 100 trillion stars. Being more than 50 times the size of the Milky Way and 2000 times as massive&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IC 1101 is on the left in the image below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/c/cf/Abell_2029.png/800px-Abell_2029.png&quot; alt=&quot;IC 1101&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is an image from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey (SDSS) of IC 1101:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/oXRpD.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SDSS IC 1101&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll leave it to you to decide if an elliptical galaxy counts as &quot;spherical&quot; or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don't count elliptical galaxies, the largest spiral galaxy is &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NGC_262&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;NGC 262&lt;/a&gt;, pictured below. It has a diameter of 1.3 million light years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/Dlkuc.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;NGC 262&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-11-14T21:15:32.230" Id="927" LastActivityDate="2014-01-09T20:02:04.507" LastEditDate="2017-03-10T09:42:47.053" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="925" PostTypeId="2" Score="13"/>
  <row AnswerCount="0" Body="&lt;p&gt;I've been reading up on plate tectonics and found that there are several different driving forces involved. One of the main categories of driving force mentioned on Wikipedia is forces related to the Earth's rotation. The section on driving forces related to Earth rotation presents the information as a sort of historical dialogue of the scientific process, which is somewhat helpful but has left me confused as to exactly what role the Earth's rotation &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; play in plate tectonics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So how does rotation affect the movement of plates?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" ClosedDate="2013-12-12T14:45:49.933" CommentCount="8" CreationDate="2013-11-15T16:47:23.047" Id="933" LastActivityDate="2013-12-12T14:45:43.010" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;earth&gt;" Title="What effect does the Earth's rotation have on plate tectonics?" ViewCount="1535"/>
  <row AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;As has been pointed out by @Envite in the context of a more general discussion (see &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/987/generalised-planets&quot;&gt;Generalised planets?&lt;/a&gt;), there seems to be a moderate possibility for protoplanetary discs forming main-sequence stars (MS stars).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Main argument here is that Jupiter has mass of about $10^{-3}M_\odot$, while in principle for an object to be a MS star, it would need the mass of at least about $0.07M_\odot$. Also, there is a handful of systems, such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HD_29587&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;HD 29587&lt;/a&gt;, which contain a star and a brown dwarf, possibly forming from a protoplanetary disk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence, a few questions. Can low-mass MS stars form in protoplanetary discs? If no, why? If yes, how often does it happen? If yes, which implications would it have for the subsequent dynamics of the planetary system, if one of the objects became a MS star, as opposed to it being a brown dwarf?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, thanks to @Envite for the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2013-11-24T20:30:47.817" FavoriteCount="2" Id="1005" LastActivityDate="2013-12-12T08:50:45.913" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:06.910" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="115" PostTypeId="1" Score="12" Tags="&lt;planetary-formation&gt;&lt;star-formation&gt;" Title="Can protoplanetary disks form main-sequence stars?" ViewCount="254"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="1019" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;How many of the luminous dots that we see naked are galaxies and not stars from our galaxy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I imagine that the majority of the luminous points that we see naked eye during the night, are actually stars from our galaxy. But how many of them are other objects (other galaxies, nebula, etc.), excluding planets from our Solar System?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2013-11-26T13:55:43.463" FavoriteCount="5" Id="1018" LastActivityDate="2017-04-22T15:18:55.037" LastEditDate="2015-04-12T14:40:52.190" LastEditorUserId="2153" OwnerDisplayName="Mario Stefanutti" OwnerUserId="490" PostTypeId="1" Score="17" Tags="&lt;star&gt;&lt;galaxy&gt;&lt;nebula&gt;&lt;naked-eye&gt;" Title="How many stars and galaxies can be seen by the naked eye?" ViewCount="12271"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;In the best sky conditions, the naked eye (with effort) can see objects with an apparent magnitude of 8.0. This reveals about &lt;strong&gt;43,197 objects&lt;/strong&gt; in the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are &lt;strong&gt;9 galaxies&lt;/strong&gt; visible to the naked eye that you might see when observing the sky, and there are about &lt;strong&gt;13 nebulae&lt;/strong&gt; that you might see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.skyandtelescope.com/resources/darksky/3304011.html&quot;&gt;The Bortle Dark-Sky Scale - John E. Bortle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://spacemath.gsfc.nasa.gov/weekly/6Page103.pdf&quot;&gt;How many stars are in the sky? - NASA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_galaxies#Naked-eye_galaxies&quot;&gt;Naked-eye galaxies - Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_planetary_nebulae&quot;&gt;List of planetary nebulae - Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_diffuse_nebulae&quot;&gt;List of diffuse nebulae - Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2013-11-26T16:02:12.950" Id="1019" LastActivityDate="2013-11-26T16:02:12.950" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="1018" PostTypeId="2" Score="8"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes&lt;/strong&gt;, unless you want to get really particular with the &quot;protoplanetary&quot; part. For example, there are stars forming in the circumstellar disks around Wolf-Rayet stars [&lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/abs/1203.4659&quot;&gt;reference&lt;/a&gt;]. If we were picky, we might not call the circumstellar disk around this Wolf-Rayet star a protoplanetary disk (and instead refer to the planet-forming circumstellar disks of the newly formed stars as such), but there exists no clear line between the disks of gas within and the larger disk of gas around the Wolf-Rayet star of which they are a part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/abs/1203.4659&quot;&gt;Triggered star formation surrounding Wolf-Rayet star HD 211853 - Liu, Wu, Zhang, and Qin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2013-11-26T17:50:12.657" Id="1020" LastActivityDate="2013-11-26T17:50:12.657" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="1005" PostTypeId="2" Score="9"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="1022" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.astro.ex.ac.uk/exoclimes/2010/talks/Forget_exoclimes10.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;These notes from an exoplanet talk&lt;/a&gt; discuss modeling the climate of exoplanets. How would we do that with our current technology? Would data be primarily gathered by spectrum analysis?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.drroyspencer.com/wp-content/uploads/climate-model-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Climate model&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2013-11-26T18:20:48.700" FavoriteCount="2" Id="1021" LastActivityDate="2014-11-06T14:08:40.647" LastEditDate="2017-03-10T09:42:47.067" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="8" Tags="&lt;exoplanet&gt;&lt;climate&gt;" Title="Climate modeling of exoplanets" ViewCount="234"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The presentation linked to seems to primarily  discuss General Circulation Models, solutions to the equations of fluid dynamics which predict the behavior of a planet's atmosphere, a component of more complete Global Climate Models (confusingly, both are GCMs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spectral data on exoplanets is extremely limited to date and poorly constrains the composition, but a lot can be inferred from a planet's orbit and eccentricity (how far from circular the orbit is). At the simplest level, planet temperature depends on how much light it receives from its parent star, and this will vary as a planet goes around a non-circular orbit. Starting from there and making reasonable assumptions about the composition of the planet (usually starting with a solar system analogy) you can test out a GCM model in the various extreme cases we observe (hot Jupiters etc.), to be subjected to future observational constraints. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One exciting new development is looking at a planet's phase curve (the observed brightness of the planet as it orbits its parent star) and using that to infer properties of the atmosphere. One team recently found that Kepler 7b's phase curve  may best be explained by the presence of clouds: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demory, et al. 2013. “Inference of Inhomogeneous Clouds in an Exoplanet Atmosphere.” arXiv:1309.7894 [astro-Ph] (September 30). &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/abs/1309.7894&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://arxiv.org/abs/1309.7894&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2013-11-27T04:34:07.660" Id="1022" LastActivityDate="2014-11-06T14:08:40.647" LastEditDate="2014-11-06T14:08:40.647" LastEditorUserId="457" OwnerUserId="457" ParentId="1021" PostTypeId="2" Score="6"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="1112" AnswerCount="4" Body="&lt;p&gt;With our current technology, or technology available in the near future (up to 2025), how would we detect a planet exactly like our own, and how close would it have to be to be detectable?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which methods thus far have proven the most effective for detecting Earth-like planets and what would they be able to reveal regarding our planet's atmosphere, orbital properties, and our species?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This question is interesting food for thought on both how easily an extraterrestrial civilization with comparable technology might find us, and for how easily we might find them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the purpose of the question we will assume that there is a planet with a civilisation with equivalent technological advancements that could exist anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2013-11-29T21:30:45.270" FavoriteCount="5" Id="1037" LastActivityDate="2015-05-03T15:09:19.783" LastEditDate="2013-12-07T06:15:46.250" LastEditorUserId="500" OwnerUserId="500" PostTypeId="1" Score="14" Tags="&lt;exoplanet&gt;&lt;extra-terrestrial&gt;" Title="How would we detect an Earth doppelganger planet?" ViewCount="626"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Avi Loeb and Edwin Turner have written a paper about the possibility of detecting a civilization similar to our own on another world by looking for city lights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their proposed method suggests observing the dark sides of planets when they transit in front of their parent star. Though they said that this method will require future generations of telescopes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cfa.harvard.edu/news/2011-30&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;City Lights Could Reveal E.T. Civilization - Harvard-Smithsonian Center for Astrophysics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-12-10T14:29:37.677" Id="1112" LastActivityDate="2013-12-10T14:29:37.677" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="1037" PostTypeId="2" Score="4"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The paper &quot;Frequency of nearby supernovae and climatic and biological catastrophes&quot; by Clark, McCrea, and Stephenson published in &lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt; estimates (at 50% probability) that the Solar System passes within 10 parsecs of a supernova every 100 million years. This supernova would be part of a 20-parsec strip in which an estimated 50 supernovae occur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They do speculate that a connection between the Solar System passing through these regions and climatic and biological events (such as ice ages) is possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read the paper yourself for more details. It's only two pages and you can purchase 48 hour access for $5 from Readcube.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v265/n5592/abs/265318a0.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&quot;Frequency of nearby supernovae and climatic and biological catastrophes&quot; - Clark, McCrea, and Stephenson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="5" CreationDate="2014-01-14T17:27:42.957" Id="1442" LastActivityDate="2014-01-14T17:27:42.957" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="531" PostTypeId="2" Score="4"/>
  <row AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;I have one problem:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;On picture below we can see Erigone family asteroids in plane semimajor axis - absolute magnitude. Based on V-type as a consequence of Yarkovsky effect, estimate age of this family bearing in mind that members of this family have spectral of C-type. For average value of change of semimajor axis which belongs to this family take $da=5 \times 10^{-4} \text{AU}$ (for object with diameter $D=1 \,\text{km}$ and time $t=1$ million years). Ignore initial size of family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/rQ6vh.png&quot; alt=&quot;enter image description here&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really don't know how to solve this problem (I am studying math, not astronomy). Professor won't tell us how to do it, and I tried to find the answer in his textbook and in two more books in my language, but there is no similar problem at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could you point me in the right direction?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2014-01-15T12:21:06.143" FavoriteCount="1" Id="1452" LastActivityDate="2014-01-15T17:08:33.417" LastEditDate="2014-01-15T17:08:33.417" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="808" PostTypeId="1" Score="6" Tags="&lt;asteroids&gt;" Title="How to estimate age of asteroid family Erigon" ViewCount="173"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I'm not a professional astronomer, but I'm going to take a stab at this. If anyone sees any problems, feel free to correct them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Yarkovsky effect basically means that spinning asteroids over time will be pushed into a further orbit (more precisely, it increases the semimajor axis of the orbit) due to uneven heating and cooling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently to estimate the age of an asteroid family, using only the Yarkovsky effect, we would start out with this equation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$0.2H = \log(\Delta a / C)$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This equation assumes a fixed geometric albedo for the whole family. $H$ here is the absolute magnitude. $\Delta a$ is equal to $a - a_c$ where $a$ is the semimajor axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$C = \sqrt{p_v} (da/dt)_0 T \cos \epsilon$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$p_v$ is the geometric albedo.  $(da/dt)_0$ is the maximum Yarkovsky drift rate for a body of size $D_0$, where $D_0$ is an arbitrary reference size (we could use your provided $D$ value above). $T$ is the age of the family that we are trying to calculate. $\epsilon$ is the spin axis obliquity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: I've had to remove my example solution because I could not figure out how to correct my errors from accidentally putting $C$ outside the logarithm.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can check out more details in my source below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www-n.oca.eu/morby/papers/YarkoChrono.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&quot;Yarkovsky/YORP chronology of asteroid families&quot; - Vokrouhlickýa, Broža, Bottke, Nesvorný, Morbidelli&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="6" CreationDate="2014-01-15T13:48:41.917" Id="1454" LastActivityDate="2014-01-15T14:24:17.327" LastEditDate="2014-01-15T14:24:17.327" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="1452" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row AnswerCount="0" Body="&lt;p&gt;A lot of you are probably already aware of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.meta.stackexchange.com/&quot;&gt;meta site&lt;/a&gt;, but I wanted to take the time to remind you that it only requires 5 reputation points to participate--and this is a critical part of our site. Meta is where we decide what kinds of questions we like in the community, it is where we pick our topic of the week, it is where we can deal with different issues of site growth. Did you know that we can suggest revisions to the help center? These are the types of things that meta allows us to discuss. In fact, this post would be best suited on meta because it is not about the field of astronomy, but about this site. I have posted it here so that you (especially new users) can see it. Maintaining activity on our meta site is important to the long term health of our site. If we don't have activity there, we could wither and ultimately get shut down. I appreciate the recent surge of questions, but I hope that many of you will stick around and participate in making this site work!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more on Meta, read this &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.stackoverflow.com/2010/07/new-per-site-metas/&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;. Though, note that the link to meta is now located under the Stack Exchange dropdown on the black top bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.stackoverflow.com/2010/07/the-7-essential-meta-questions-of-every-beta/&quot;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt; on the important questions to ask on Meta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for your continued contribution to Astronomy Stack Exchange!&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="10" CreationDate="2014-01-16T15:41:44.723" FavoriteCount="1" Id="1468" LastActivityDate="2017-09-01T16:28:45.240" LastEditDate="2017-09-01T16:28:45.240" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="2" Tags="&lt;fundamental-astronomy&gt;" Title="Please take the time to visit Meta!" ViewCount="108"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="2138" AnswerCount="4" Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Universe&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;em&gt;The Universe is commonly defined as the totality of existence&lt;/em&gt;&quot;&lt;/a&gt; but that is more of a philosophical position. Empirically we know (&lt;em&gt;or believe&lt;/em&gt;) that it is of finite size some believe it is &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Expanding_universe&quot;&gt;expanding&lt;/a&gt; others that is (&lt;em&gt;or will be&lt;/em&gt;) &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_Crunch&quot;&gt;contracting&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we gain knowledge about distant places, our scope of area has expanded from Planet, to Solar system, to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galaxy&quot;&gt;Galaxy&lt;/a&gt;, to Universe. In the same way we continue to find smaller and smaller building blocks, from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Classical_element&quot;&gt;Elements&lt;/a&gt;, to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Atom&quot;&gt;Atoms&lt;/a&gt;, to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quark&quot;&gt;Quarks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is reasonable to assume, that the same gains in knowledge the removed the burden from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Atlas_%28mythology%29&quot;&gt;Atlas&lt;/a&gt;, will find the edge of the Universe, and something that is beyond that edge.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the name of that which exists beyond the Universe? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naysayers, who may claim that there is &quot;nothing&quot; beyond universe, are reminded that their beliefs are no less strong than, those who claimed that &quot;nothing&quot; was supporting the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Turtle&quot;&gt;Turtle&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Elephant&quot;&gt;Elephant&lt;/a&gt; who like Atlas also supported the world.  Lack of knowledge does not mean lack of existence. &lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="7" CreationDate="2014-04-09T22:34:31.330" FavoriteCount="2" Id="2137" LastActivityDate="2018-02-10T11:48:37.130" OwnerDisplayName="James Jenkins" OwnerUserId="513" PostTypeId="1" Score="11" Tags="&lt;terminology&gt;" Title="What is the name of that which exists beyond the Universe?" ViewCount="4083"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;It is far from empirically known that the universe is finite in size. The observable universe is certainly of finite size, but that is just a product of the constraints of our observation. We don't know for sure whether the universe is finite or infinite, bounded or unbounded. &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.public.iastate.edu/~astro/courses/a120/workb32.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;[Source]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; What we do know is that right now the universe looks &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; flat as far as we can measure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in other answers, the Universe has traditionally been defined as &quot;all that is&quot;, though in practice in astronomy it is &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; particular &quot;field&quot; of space-time that we exist in. New theories in physics have brought with them the possibility that there may be other universes in this sense. The word we use to encompass all possible universes is &quot;the Multiverse&quot;. There are different types of universes proposed, and you can read a good summary of them in the Wikipedia &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multiverse&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Multiverse&lt;/a&gt; article. From there you might read of Brian Greene and others that you might want to pursue further. For example, Brian Greene has a book titled &lt;em&gt;The Hidden Reality: Parallel Universes and the Deep Laws of the Cosmos&lt;/em&gt; which might be of interest to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;Note: There is a sense in which we can say the universe is unbounded in 3D as mentioned in the linked source, but there are other senses in which the bounded/unbounded nature of the universe is questioned but which cannot be adequately discussed in this space.&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2014-04-10T13:11:07.617" Id="2139" LastActivityDate="2014-04-11T15:02:26.777" LastEditDate="2014-04-11T15:02:26.777" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="2137" PostTypeId="2" Score="8"/>
  <row AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;I understand that Kerr Black Holes are purely theoretical and have not been found anywhere in the Universe. However, they are theorized for possible means of time travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am attempting to prove in a research paper that controlled time travel is statistically improbable for the human species. Therefore if scientists have evidence that there does not exist a black hole within a distance of X from Earth, and it is statistically improbable for the human species to ever be able to travel a distance of X, I can rule out time travel by means of kerr black holes with a significant degree of certainty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I cannot find this &quot;X&quot; threshold, which is why I am asking this question. Have scientists verified that there are no kerr black holes within a distance of X from earth for some X?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2014-04-14T19:49:32.333" Id="2159" LastActivityDate="2014-04-14T20:28:16.443" OwnerDisplayName="user1380792" OwnerUserId="1408" PostTypeId="1" Score="2" Tags="&lt;black-hole&gt;" Title="Finding a Kerr Black Holes" ViewCount="173"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rotating_black_hole&quot;&gt;1) Nearly all black holes are Kerr black holes.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://hubblesite.org/explore_astronomy/black_holes/encyc_mod3_q7.html&quot;&gt;2) There are roughly 100 million black holes estimated in our galaxy.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.space.com/7678-black-hole-closer-earth-thought.html&quot;&gt;3) There is a confirmed black hole about 7800 light years away.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://io9.com/5949616/is-earths-closest-black-hole-hiding-inside-this-nebula&quot;&gt;4) There is a potential black hole about 1500 light years away.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://io9.com/5949616/is-earths-closest-black-hole-hiding-inside-this-nebula&quot;&gt;5) It is very likely that there are black holes even closer than that, but they are difficult to detect.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of your assumptions are wrong, but for now the closest known potential black hole is still a pretty good distance away. Traveling that far with our current technology is impossible, and overcoming that hurdle is not trivial. Regardless, using a Kerr black hole for time travel &lt;a href=&quot;http://imagine.gsfc.nasa.gov/docs/ask_astro/answers/041130a.html&quot;&gt;may not be feasible anyway&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2014-04-14T20:28:16.443" Id="2160" LastActivityDate="2014-04-14T20:28:16.443" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="2159" PostTypeId="2" Score="5"/>
  <row AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;I'm trying to imagine what a hypothetical observer on the surface of Alpha Centauri Bb would see in the daytime sky. I know it would vary depending on the orbit of &lt;strong&gt;b&lt;/strong&gt; around &lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt;, as well as the position of B and A in relation to each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What would the &quot;sun&quot; in the sky look like at different times on Bb? I know that at times B and A would overlap and appear as a single sun, but what about when they don't?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2014-05-01T16:14:12.030" Id="2332" LastActivityDate="2014-05-01T18:53:58.263" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="5" Tags="&lt;exoplanet&gt;&lt;observational-astronomy&gt;" Title="How would Alpha Centauri A appear from the surface of Alpha Centauri Bb?" ViewCount="313"/>
  <row Body="&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I'm trying to imagine what a hypothetical observer on the surface of
  Alpha Centauri Bb would see in the daytime sky. I know it would vary
  depending on the orbit of b around B, as well as the position of B and
  A in relation to each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My calculations are based on data from these wiki pages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alpha_Centauri&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alpha_Centauri&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alpha_Centauri_Bb&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alpha_Centauri_Bb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The planet Alpha Centauri Bb orbits the star Alpha Centauri B on an orbit with a semi-major axis of 0.04 AU. That's 25x closer to its star than Earth is to the Sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alpha Centauri B has 86% the diameter of the Sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, ACB would appear in the sky of ACBb as a huge, extremely bright and hot disk, about 21x bigger than the Sun as seen from Earth (25 x 0.86). The heat would destroy and melt many materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ACB looks a bit more orange than the Sun, but the color difference is small.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ACA and ACB orbit each other, being separated by as little as 11 AU, or as much as 35 AU. ACA is about 22% bigger in diameter than the Sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, ACA as seen from ACBb would appear as a very small &quot;sun&quot; (about 1/10 the size of the Sun as seen from Earth) when at the closest approach, or basically an extremely bright dot, with no apparent size, so shiny it would hurt the eye, when at the maximal distance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ACA would provide essentially no heat, and very little light, when compared to ACB (or even when compared to what we get from the Sun here on Earth). But it would be very similar in color to the Sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the closest approach, ACA would look very similar to the Sun as seen from Saturn. At the maximal distance, it would look like the Sun seen from Neptune.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ACB is a huge fireball of doom, 20x bigger than how we see the Sun, a bit of an orange hue, scorching hot, melting and igniting everything. ACA is a tiny disk, or even just a dot, yellow-white, very bright, providing essentially no heat and much less light than ACB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ACA would grow bigger, then smaller again, following a cycle of 80 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ACA and ACB would get closer together in the sky, then drift further apart, on a cycle following ACBb's &quot;year&quot; - which is only 3.2 days in our terms. A very, very short &quot;year&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not unlikely, although this is speculative, that ACBb is tidally locked to ACB, because they are so close together. If that's the case, ACB would only be visible from one side of ACBb, and would appear to remain &quot;fixed&quot; in the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's an artist's impression. Keep in mind that ACB is a giant fireball, so this is more like a fisheye lens image (horizon to horizon in one snapshot). The size of ACA is overestimated. The Sun as seen from Earth would be the size of the letter B in that image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/9u3hb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;enter image description here&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I know that at times B and A would overlap and appear as a single sun,
  but what about when they don't?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, do they? Do we know that for sure? For the overlap to happen, the orbit of Bb would have to be relatively coplanar to the mutual orbits of A and B. This seems likely, but I'm not sure if it has been established as a fact.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2014-05-01T18:39:02.523" Id="2338" LastActivityDate="2014-05-01T18:53:58.263" LastEditDate="2014-05-01T18:53:58.263" LastEditorUserId="1378" OwnerUserId="1378" ParentId="2332" PostTypeId="2" Score="8"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I had a chat with a European PhD student who plans to make an attempt to find Oort cloud objects in data from the Gaia space telescope. This could be possible thanks to microlensing events when an Oort object transits (near) a background star and relativistically magnifies the star's light for a moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best case is that in a few years we will have a map of a statistically useful number of Oort cloud objects. Enough to claim that we have &quot;seen&quot; it.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2014-05-14T09:19:54.323" Id="2433" LastActivityDate="2014-05-14T09:19:54.323" OwnerUserId="1030" ParentId="254" PostTypeId="2" Score="11"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="5904" AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;If two comets come together in space, will they bounce apart, merge into a single body, or could they travel together through space, either touching or orbiting a shared center of gravity? &lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2014-07-16T14:18:02.717" Id="5903" LastActivityDate="2014-07-16T15:43:33.453" LastEditDate="2014-07-16T14:34:14.213" LastEditorUserId="513" OwnerDisplayName="James Jenkins" OwnerUserId="513" PostTypeId="1" Score="10" Tags="&lt;comets&gt;" Title="Can two comets travel together as one?" ViewCount="1096"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Yes, binary comets do exist; 8P/Tuttle is an example of one. This is an area that is still being heavily researched, but it is suspected that binary comets can &quot;form from collision, mutual capture, or fission.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent news, the comet 67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko has also been revealed to be a contact-binary by the European Space Agency's &lt;em&gt;Rosetta&lt;/em&gt; spacecraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://echo.jpl.nasa.gov/asteroids/harmon.etal.comet.tuttle.pdf&quot;&gt;Radar observations of 8P/Tuttle: A contact-binary comet - Harmon, Nolan, Giorgini, Howell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-27110882&quot;&gt;Rosetta's target is 'double' comet - BBC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2014-07-16T14:40:23.183" Id="5904" LastActivityDate="2014-07-16T14:50:14.477" LastEditDate="2014-07-16T14:50:14.477" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="5903" PostTypeId="2" Score="14"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="5911" AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;How was it decided which hemisphere was North and which hemisphere was South on Mars? Clearly, the designations &quot;North&quot; and &quot;South&quot; apply only to the hemispheres which contain the axis of rotation at their center, but what determined whether a hemisphere received &quot;North&quot; or &quot;South&quot; as its designation?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2014-07-16T16:35:44.007" Id="5907" LastActivityDate="2014-07-17T13:34:34.707" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="9" Tags="&lt;mars&gt;&lt;naming&gt;" Title="How were the designations of &quot;North&quot; and &quot;South&quot; applied to the hemispheres of Mars?" ViewCount="192"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;North and south are defined according to the planet's rotation about its axis. A &quot;right hand&quot; rule is used: If you make a fist with your right hand, and orient your curled fingers in the direction the planet rotates, your thumb points north. Alternatively: Standing on the equator, facing the direction the planet rotates, North is to your left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Axial_tilt&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Axial Tilt&lt;/a&gt; on wikipedia has this information (and more.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;update&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hey! Don't up vote this answer; It's wrong... see the comments where the OP has actually researched and discovered the real answer. (I don't want to delete this answer because we'll lose the comments too!)&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="12" CreationDate="2014-07-16T18:00:50.863" Id="5908" LastActivityDate="2014-07-17T12:51:17.130" LastEditDate="2014-07-17T12:51:17.130" LastEditorUserId="7" OwnerUserId="7" ParentId="5907" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The research in other answers helped me come across the actual International Astronomical Union (IAU) standard:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The north pole is that pole of rotation that lies on the north side of the invariable plane of the solar system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The north of the invariable plane is the side that Earth's North pole points to. In fact, one of our other users has observed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The North Pole of any system being the pole on the same side as earth's north is indeed the correct definition. This applies to the Milky Way galaxy as well, in which case the North Galactic Pole is the pole towards the hemisphere of the galactic sphere which also contains the celestial north pole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dwarf planets, minor planets, their satellites, and comets do follow the right-hand rule mentioned in other answers (see &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Axial_tilt&quot;&gt;Axial tilt&lt;/a&gt; on Wikipedia).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://download.springer.com/static/pdf/49/art%253A10.1007%252Fs10569-007-9072-y.pdf?auth66=1405707429_bc7c5277c4389320d62d623be73d0bf0&amp;amp;ext=.pdf&quot;&gt;Report of the IAU/IAG Working Group on cartographic
coordinates and rotational elements: 2006 - P. Kenneth Seidelmann, B. A. Archinal,
M. F. A’hearn, et al.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poles_of_astronomical_bodies&quot;&gt;Poles of astronomical bodies - Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2014-07-17T13:34:34.707" Id="5911" LastActivityDate="2014-07-17T13:34:34.707" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="5907" PostTypeId="2" Score="7"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The angular resolution of the telescope &lt;em&gt;really has no direct bearing on our ability to detect Oort cloud objects&lt;/em&gt; beyond how that angular resolution affects the depth to which one can detect the light from faint objects. Any telescope can detect stars, even though their actual discs are way beyond the angular resolution of the telescope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The detection of Oort cloud objects is simply a question of detecting the (unresolved) reflected light in exactly the same way that one detects a faint (unresolved) star. Confirmation of the Oort cloud nature of the object would then come by observing at intervals over a year or so and obtaining a very large ($&amp;gt;2$ arcseconds) parallax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question amounts to how deep do you need to go? We can do this in two ways (i) a back of the envelope calculation assuming the object reflects light from the Sun with some albedo. (ii) Scale the brightness of comets when they are distant from the Sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(i) The luminosity of the Sun is $L=3.83\times10^{26}\ W$. Let the distance to the Oort cloud be $D$ and the radius of the (assumed spherical) Oort object be $R$.
The light from the Sun incident on the object is $\pi R^2 L/4\pi D^2$.
If we now assume that a fraction $f$ of this is reflected uniformly into a $2\pi$ solid angle. This latter point is an approximation, the light will not be reflected isotropically, but it will represent some average over any viewing angle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To a good approximation, as $D \gg 1$ au, we can assume that the distance from the Oort object to the Earth is also $D$. Hence the flux of light received at the Earth is
$$F_{E} = f \frac{\pi R^2 L}{4\pi D^2}\frac{1}{2\pi D^2} = f \frac{R^2 L}{8\pi D^4}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putting some numbers in, let $R=10$ km and let $D= 10,000$ au. Cometary material has a very low albedo, but let's be generous and assume $f=0.1$.
$$ F_E = 3\times10^{-29}\left(\frac{f}{0.1}\right) \left(\frac{R}{10\ km}\right)^2 \left(\frac{D}{10^4 au}\right)^{-4}\ Wm^{-2}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To convert this to a magnitude, assume the reflected light has the same spectrum as sunlight. The Sun has an apparent visual magnitude of -26.74, corresponding to a flux at the Earth of $1.4\times10^{3}\ Wm^{-2}$. Converting the flux ratio to a magnitude difference, we find that the apparent magnitude of our fiducial Oort object is &lt;strong&gt;52.4&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(ii) Halley's comet is similar (10 km radius, low albedo) to the fiducial Oort object considered above. Halley's comet was observed by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eso.org/~ohainaut/nice/phot-27-03.html&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;VLT in 2003&lt;/a&gt; with a magnitude of 28.2 and at a distance of 28 au from the Sun. We can now just scale this magnitude, but it scales as distance to the power of &lt;em&gt;four&lt;/em&gt;, because the light must be received and then we see it reflected.
Thus at 10,000 au, Halley would have a magnitude of $28.2 - 2.5 \log (28/10^{4})= 53.7$, in reasonable agreement with my other estimate. (Incidentally my crude formula in (i) above suggests a $f=0.1$, $R=10\ km$ comet at 28 au would have a magnitude of 26.9. Given that Halley probably has a smaller $f$ this is excellent consistency.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The observation of Halley by the VLT represents the pinnacle of what is possible with today's telescopes. Even the Hubble deep ultra deep field only reached visual magnitudes of about 29. Thus a big Oort cloud object remains &lt;strong&gt;more than 20 magnitudes below&lt;/strong&gt; this detection threshold!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most feasible way of detecting Oort objects is when they occult background stars. The possibilities for this are discussed by &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/abs/0912.0948&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Ofek &amp;amp; Naker 2010&lt;/a&gt; in the context of the photometric precision provided by Kepler. The rate of occultations (which are of course single events and unrepeatable) was calculated to be between zero and 100 in the whole Kepler mission, dependent on the size and distance distribution of the Oort objects. As far as I am aware, nothing has come of this (yet).&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2015-01-26T12:53:07.383" Id="8685" LastActivityDate="2015-02-21T18:39:56.010" LastEditDate="2015-02-21T18:39:56.010" LastEditorUserId="2531" OwnerUserId="2531" ParentId="254" PostTypeId="2" Score="12"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Put simply, it is because the objects that make up the Oort Cloud, remnants from the formation of our sun, are both too small and too faint for us to detect. They are faint because of their vast distance away. There is minimal absorption of the sun's light and even less is reflected back. So little light is reflected back that there is nothing for even our most advanced telescopes to see. &lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2015-04-02T00:29:39.477" Id="10352" LastActivityDate="2015-04-02T00:29:39.477" OwnerUserId="2025" ParentId="254" PostTypeId="2" Score="0"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="11135" AnswerCount="4" Body="&lt;p&gt;First do we have anyway to even estimate the mass of the entire observable universe?  And then is there any data that shows mass being gained or lost?  Would we ever know if someone was playing with the til.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also I want to be clear that I am not talking about small masses on the outskirts of the &quot;universe&quot; or small discrepancies in measurement or anything of the sort.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt;  I would like to add that maybe we should define the observable universe as NOW (x-date) so that we aren't calculating a moving target.  &lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="10" CreationDate="2015-04-04T06:25:44.723" Id="10374" LastActivityDate="2016-12-28T17:39:40.010" LastEditDate="2015-11-03T21:00:27.580" LastEditorUserId="2506" OwnerUserId="2506" PostTypeId="1" Score="8" Tags="&lt;universe&gt;&lt;mass&gt;" Title="Does the mass of the observable universe ever change?" ViewCount="1954"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="11122" AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;I know that a &lt;strong&gt;day&lt;/strong&gt; represent the time for the earth to make a full rotation around its own axis and a &lt;strong&gt;year&lt;/strong&gt; is the time for the earth to make a full rotation around the sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But &lt;strong&gt;does a week represent something?&lt;/strong&gt; And a month?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ps: Not sure what tags I need to use, feel free to add/remove them&lt;/p&gt;
" ClosedDate="2015-06-30T11:14:27.390" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2015-06-29T19:14:19.423" Id="11121" LastActivityDate="2015-06-30T13:16:17.757" OwnerUserId="7571" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;earth&gt;&lt;fundamental-astronomy&gt;" Title="Does a week represent something in astronomy?" ViewCount="623"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The concept of a month derived from the amount of time it takes for the moon to cycle from new moon to new moon (which is roughly 29.5 days). The modern month has experienced changes from this original concept due to trying to fit a standard number of months within a solar year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you divide the lunar month into quarters, each quarter is approximately 7 days long. This is believed to be the origin of the seven-day week.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2015-06-29T20:35:39.120" Id="11122" LastActivityDate="2015-06-30T13:16:17.757" LastEditDate="2015-06-30T13:16:17.757" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="11121" PostTypeId="2" Score="5"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The mass of the observable universe can be derived from its density.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Dr. Jagadheep D. Pandian:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The density of matter in the universe can be measured by various means, which are too technical to go into at this point: people measure the density by studying the fluctuations in the Cosmic Microwave Background, superclusters, Big Bang nucleosynthesis, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the density and the size of the observable universe, the mass can be derived to be 3 x 10&lt;sup&gt;55&lt;/sup&gt; g. This figure includes both dark matter and traditional matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I imagine that a historical deviation in mass might be detectable if it were significant, but I can't imagine what might cause a deviation that would be detectable on the scale we're talking about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://curious.astro.cornell.edu/our-solar-system/101-the-universe/cosmology-and-the-big-bang/general-questions/579-what-is-the-mass-of-the-universe-intermediate&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;What is the mass of the Universe? (Intermediate) - Cornell University, Ask an Astronomer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2015-06-30T19:32:52.180" Id="11127" LastActivityDate="2015-06-30T19:32:52.180" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="10374" PostTypeId="2" Score="1"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="11796" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;The James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) which is slated to launch in 2018 will bring us a better view of exoplanets, but will it be sufficient to detect signs of life on at least some of those worlds?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good answer will provide an estimate of the James Webb Space Telescope's capabilities to detect atmospheric data relevant to the presence of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The preferred answer would also include an analysis of what it would take to say with a decent level of confidence that life was present on an exoplanet and whether or not JWST will be capable of this.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2015-07-06T13:42:50.567" FavoriteCount="2" Id="11186" LastActivityDate="2015-09-13T21:35:50.073" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="8" Tags="&lt;exoplanet&gt;&lt;astrobiology&gt;" Title="Could the James Webb Space Telescope detect biosignals on exoplanets?" ViewCount="129"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;From what I understand, James Webb, if used in conjunction with a successful starshade (being developed at MIT), should be able to detect close in planets orbiting nearby stars. However, getting good atmospheric spectra of these planets directly (from planet's blackbody IR emission) is unlikely. What we must hope for is that TESS, which should be going up in 2017, will find a few nearby stars with transiting planets. Then, James Webb will be able to look for atmospheric absorption lines from stellar light passing through a planet's atmosphere during transit. This method may still be limited to large (Jupiter size) planets.
In an ideal situation (say looking at absorption lines of a super-earth) there are many &quot;bio-signatures&quot;, but one of the easiest to detect would be an ozone line in the infrared. By itself, this would not be proof, even though there would need to be a constant replenishing source of O2 in the atmosphere to maintain the O3. If methane could also be found we could rightly get VERY excited since methane and oxygen don't co-exist very well.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2015-09-13T21:35:50.073" Id="11796" LastActivityDate="2015-09-13T21:35:50.073" OwnerUserId="7997" ParentId="11186" PostTypeId="2" Score="4"/>
  <row AnswerCount="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;Couldn't it be just a relatively large object, anywhere in the interstellar space between the star and Earth? I mean, look out the window at a far away car or a tree, then stretch out your hand and you can block it entirely with your thumb. What if the 'thumb' is that object (a planet, a star, a comet, some space debri, etc.) that's between Earth and the star, and it's just the right size to only block that star, and no other stars. Why has this very simple explanation been ruled out (if it has been)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know that the debri next to the star explanation has been ruled out because of the lack of IR that would come from that debri being heated up if it was close to the star. But this is not a problem here, if the blocking object is far away from the star.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="5" CreationDate="2015-10-21T07:03:40.167" Id="12198" LastActivityDate="2017-04-12T12:47:25.570" OwnerUserId="9548" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;star&gt;&lt;universe&gt;&lt;exoplanet&gt;&lt;extra-terrestrial&gt;" Title="Why can't this be the simple (and obvious) explanation for the dimming of KIC 8462852?" ViewCount="208"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The simplest reason why your proposed explanation is not really that obvious, and thus was not considered is that the dimming of KIC 8462852 was not an isolated event. The dimming is a pattern that has been observed over years. There is no known phenomenon in interstellar space that would cause a repeated obstruction of that star, so it doesn't make any sense to consider that possibility when there are other phenomena (such as those captured in Boyajian's paper) that are more likely to be the source of the dimming.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2015-10-21T20:12:17.423" Id="12216" LastActivityDate="2015-10-21T20:12:17.423" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="12198" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row AnswerCount="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;I need to know the definition of deep space.  I am an amateur astronomer, and am experiencing some difficulty understanding this.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2016-04-02T02:34:23.220" Id="14391" LastActivityDate="2016-04-03T04:06:22.543" OwnerUserId="11421" PostTypeId="1" Score="0" Tags="&lt;distances&gt;" Title="What is the definition of &quot;deep space&quot;?" ViewCount="835"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;It's not in any sort of academic context, but in relation to space exploration &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nasa.gov/exploration/systems&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;NASA&lt;/a&gt; defines deep space as such:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Deep space is the vast region of space that extends beyond our Moon, to Mars and across our solar system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, not exactly an academic context, but &lt;a href=&quot;http://rads.stackoverflow.com/amzn/click/1579129781&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Govert Schiling&lt;/a&gt; (the author of &lt;em&gt;Deep Space: Beyond the Solar System to the End of the Universe and the Beginning of Time&lt;/em&gt;) in relation to astronomy defines deep space differently:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In a sense, everything beyond Earth’s atmosphere is deep space. But more typically it’s a phrase that has been used by observational and amateur astronomers alike for extended objects beyond the Solar System. I decided to provide a brief introductory section on the Sun and the planets, but the emphasis is really on the objects in our Galaxy and the wider Universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this more or less echoes what some others have contributed, but provides additional context.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2016-04-03T04:06:22.543" Id="14402" LastActivityDate="2016-04-03T04:06:22.543" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="14391" PostTypeId="2" Score="1"/>
  <row AnswerCount="6" Body="&lt;p&gt;The density of the Sun is $1410~\frac{\text{kg}}{\text{m}^{3}}$ and Mercury's is $5430~\frac{\text{kg}}{\text{m}^{3}}$, but shouldn't the Sun be denser? Because when the Solar System was forming, there was a big disk of debris, and depending on the density of the debris it went closer or further from the centre, which then formed the planets, but the Sun is in the centre, and it's less dense than Mercury, why?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2016-05-16T15:02:43.743" FavoriteCount="3" Id="14889" LastActivityDate="2017-04-24T14:56:58.383" LastEditDate="2016-05-17T13:54:04.587" LastEditorUserId="1929" OwnerUserId="11830" PostTypeId="1" Score="30" Tags="&lt;solar-system&gt;&lt;the-sun&gt;&lt;mercury&gt;&lt;density&gt;" Title="Why is the Sun's density less than the inner planets?" ViewCount="9532"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Fusion inside of a star affects the sun's density (which does not happen with a planet). It produces an outward pressure that balances against the attraction of gravity, thereby reducing the density as long as the star is burning. Once a star the mass of the sun is no longer able to sustain fusion, what is left is a white dwarf which is in fact much denser than Mercury.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2016-05-16T15:10:24.827" Id="14890" LastActivityDate="2016-05-19T14:40:01.203" LastEditDate="2016-05-19T14:40:01.203" LastEditorUserId="1569" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="14889" PostTypeId="2" Score="29"/>
  <row AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://what-if.xkcd.com/150/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;This XKCD what-if&lt;/a&gt; talks about rainbows on planets in a binary star system.   It points out that there are two types:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;circumbinary&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; planets, where the planet orbits far from and around both stars &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;[the other kind of planet]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, where the planet orbits one of the stars and the other star is distant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/gSX15.png&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/gSX15.png&quot; alt=&quot;enter image description here&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;What is the proper name for [the other kind of planet] ?&lt;/h1&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2016-05-24T20:52:59.290" Id="14996" LastActivityDate="2016-05-25T17:44:24.660" LastEditDate="2016-05-25T16:02:44.290" LastEditorUserId="1106" OwnerUserId="1106" PostTypeId="1" Score="6" Tags="&lt;planet&gt;&lt;exoplanet&gt;&lt;binary-star&gt;&lt;terminology&gt;" Title="What's the name for [the other kind of planet] in a binary star system?" ViewCount="371"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Astronomy currently only gives us the names circumbinary (left picture) and Trojan planet (unpictured, planet is around a Lagrange point), but from circumbinary we can extrapolate other names:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;circumunary - revolves around one star&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;circumtrinary/circumternary - revolves around a trinary/ternary star system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technically, there is another term that actually has some use: circumsystem. This is used for objects that revolve around a multiple star system regardless of the number of stars within the system.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2016-05-25T17:44:24.660" Id="15003" LastActivityDate="2016-05-25T17:44:24.660" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="14996" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;Gravity is related to mass, and gravity is an attracting force on every body. Then what happens when bodies only attract each other..without repulsion they may strike the sun. I think there must be a repulsive force. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another question arises, if only attraction is there, then why does the moon rotate elliptically around the earth?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Mars comes closer to earth after 3 years?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2016-06-15T19:13:52.107" Id="16250" LastActivityDate="2016-10-26T18:33:20.027" LastEditDate="2016-06-15T19:22:18.353" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="13154" PostTypeId="1" Score="1" Tags="&lt;planet&gt;&lt;solar-system&gt;" Title="If the planets only attract, then how can they stay in their orbit?" ViewCount="578"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/8254/do-planets-repel&quot;&gt;Gravity does not repel&lt;/a&gt;, but there is another &quot;force&quot; at work here. The angular momentum of the original protoplanetary disk is conserved. In other words, just because the cloud condensed into planets doesn't mean it is going to stop spinning. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we orbit artificial objects, we speed them up until they reach a velocity that sustains orbit--so again there is another force at work, just not gravity. Gravity keeps objects in orbit (rather than letting them fly off into space). Imagine if you spin a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yo-yo&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;yo-yo&lt;/a&gt; around in the air. The tension of the string is like gravity, keeping the yo-yo in orbit, but if you let go of the string then the other &quot;force&quot; (its momentum) will cause it to fly off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Technically, momentum is not a force. It is the product of the mass and velocity of the system--a conserved quantity, but the object required a force to bring it up to that velocity. In the case of a planet, it is the astronomical forces that acted on the protoplanetary disk. In the case of the yo-yo, it was your applied force to spin it.)&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2016-06-15T19:32:36.390" Id="16251" LastActivityDate="2016-06-15T19:32:36.390" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:07.017" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="16250" PostTypeId="2" Score="8"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="16555" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;Since about 1990 astronomers been able to detect planets around other stars, using a couple different techniques, which is amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By this point, do we know whether planets form &lt;strong&gt;only around single systems, only around multiple systems, or both&lt;/strong&gt;??&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Surprisingly you can't find this general issue explained in popular writing. I think it's &quot;obvious background knowledge&quot; to experts, hence just doesn't get outlined explicitly in popular writing.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, as of mid 2016:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(i) About how many exoplanets do we know of (say, with good certainty),&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(ii) In fact, how many (if any) of these are around single-star systems?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(iii) How many (if any) are around multiple-star systems?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If indeed it is possible to have planets in multiple systems: is it just a planet going around one of the stars, or is &quot;all the way around both&quot; known?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="11" CreationDate="2016-07-12T18:53:18.090" Id="16552" LastActivityDate="2016-09-25T01:58:56.657" LastEditDate="2016-07-13T17:36:13.237" LastEditorUserId="13071" OwnerUserId="13071" PostTypeId="1" Score="4" Tags="&lt;exoplanet&gt;&lt;binary-star&gt;" Title="Do planets form around lone stars, multiple stars, or both? Do we know this yet?" ViewCount="160"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;There are currently 3424 planets identified (including those in the Solar System and unconfirmed exoplanets). Of these, 3310 are confirmed exoplanets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of the 3424, 180 are in binary (or multiple) star systems. Of those, 28 are circumbinary. I am not certain if any circumternary planets have been identified, though I know some circumternary disks have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is more difficult to identify circum-&lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;-ary planets than those that only revolve around one star, so these numbers might not precisely represent the actual proportions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openexoplanetcatalogue.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Open Exoplanet Catalogue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="7" CreationDate="2016-07-13T15:29:07.537" Id="16555" LastActivityDate="2016-07-13T15:29:07.537" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="16552" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;I know that there is plenty of theory to predict the size of a neutron star:  my question is whether or not there are any reliable size estimates based on observation. Please note that, to be reliable, such an observation would need to have also a good estimate for the neutron star's distance from us, which must necessarily be reckoned from some independent source, i.e., it must &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; be reckoned from the apparent size of the object, or from theory, otherwise one is guilty of circular reasoning!&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="5" CreationDate="2016-07-13T19:46:44.773" Id="16559" LastActivityDate="2016-07-15T14:28:50.627" LastEditDate="2016-07-13T21:22:44.677" LastEditorUserId="2153" OwnerUserId="13290" PostTypeId="1" Score="2" Tags="&lt;observational-astronomy&gt;&lt;neutron-star&gt;" Title="Are there any reliable optical measurements of the radius of a neutron star?" ViewCount="96"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Yes, the neutron star &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RX_J1856.5-3754&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;RX J1856.5-3754&lt;/a&gt; has an observed* radius of 17 km. After accounting for general relativity, its actual radius is calculated as 14 km. It is not the only &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Category:Neutron_stars&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;neutron star&lt;/a&gt; whose radius is known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* It's worth mentioning how astronomers arrived at this radius. Technically, fitting the X-ray data to a blackbody arrives at a calculation of a 5 km radius, which seems unusually small, so for a time it was believed that this star may be something more exotic, like a quark star. However, after atmospheric modeling based on temperature, a more accurate estimate of the emission radius was derived to be 17 km. Once gravitational redshift was accounted for, the value of 14 km was yielded. See &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/pdf/astro-ph/0612145v1.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Magnetic Hydrogen Atmosphere Models and the Neutron Star RX J1856.5−3754 - Wynn C. G. Ho, et al.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="5" CreationDate="2016-07-13T21:15:05.480" Id="16562" LastActivityDate="2016-07-15T14:28:50.627" LastEditDate="2016-07-15T14:28:50.627" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="16559" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;The other night, while playing Elite: Dangerous, I came across a rather strange celestial body - one I never imagined possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a Brown Dwarf star with a &lt;em&gt;very large&lt;/em&gt; ring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/67Pqd.png&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/67Pqd.png&quot; alt=&quot;enter image description here&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is something like this even remotely possible? Have such objects actually been seen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was also quite interesting that this star wasn't even the primary star in the system. It was orbiting a larger star (blue-white, I think), along with several planets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/mnzf8.png&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/mnzf8.png&quot; alt=&quot;enter image description here&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="6" CreationDate="2016-08-04T19:56:25.623" Id="17814" LastActivityDate="2016-08-11T05:05:14.593" LastEditDate="2016-08-11T05:05:14.593" LastEditorUserId="550" OwnerUserId="550" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;star&gt;&lt;planetary-ring&gt;" Title="Do/Can Ringed Stars Exist?" ViewCount="820"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Yes, in a sense, that is what a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Circumstellar_disc&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;circumstellar disk&lt;/a&gt; is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/gTiCB.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/gTiCB.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;HL Tauri disk&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eso.org/public/archives/images/large/eso1436a.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;European Southern Observatory (ESO)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are usually most noticeable around young stars as protoplanetary disks, disks that form planets. In the picture above, the gaps in the rings likely represent forming planets, similar to how the gaps in Saturn's rings indicate the presence of moons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our own star has a few rings, though likely not as visually impressive: the asteroid belt, the Kupier belt, the scattered disk, and the Hills cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="12" CreationDate="2016-08-04T20:41:09.920" Id="17815" LastActivityDate="2016-08-04T20:41:09.920" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="17814" PostTypeId="2" Score="6"/>
  <row AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Related: &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/q/17814/550&quot;&gt;Do/Can Ringed Stars Exist?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there any particular difference, in behavior or properties, between a planetary ring system and a circumstellar disk? Or is the only real difference a matter of what's in the middle?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This question came up as a matter in the related discussion, particularly because the (game-simulated) object that inspired the question is a brown dwarf - something between a star and a gas giant. What I observed in-game appeared to be more similar to the rings around Saturn, than to the description and image provided of a circumstellar disk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, are there properties of the rings/disks themselves which can differentiate one type from another? Or is the type of central body the only thing that defines them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the central body is the only factor, what should we call a ring around a brown dwarf, assuming one could exist in nature?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2016-08-08T16:52:07.270" Id="17845" LastActivityDate="2016-08-11T15:20:57.857" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:06.910" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="550" PostTypeId="1" Score="2" Tags="&lt;planetary-ring&gt;&lt;terminology&gt;&lt;disk&gt;" Title="Difference between &quot;planetary ring&quot; and &quot;circumstellar disk&quot;?" ViewCount="137"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/a/197897/28199&quot;&gt;Physics SE&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A circumstellar disk is a set of objects that orbit about a star-like object and that collectively look disk-like in some way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ring_system&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A ring system is a disc or ring orbiting an astronomical object that is composed of solid material&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, a circumstellar disk may have gas, dust, asteroids, etc., but it must orbit a star-like object. A ring system &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; have something solid--dust or moonlets--but it may orbit any astronomical object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than that, you specifically asked about a &lt;em&gt;planetary&lt;/em&gt; ring. That would mean a ring system that specifically had a planemo as the central body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, a disk around a brown dwarf could be described as a circumstellar disk (a brown dwarf is a star-like object) &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; a ring system (as long as the disk contained solid material). It could not be called a planetary ring, because a brown dwarf is not a planet.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2016-08-11T15:17:17.447" Id="17885" LastActivityDate="2016-08-11T15:20:57.857" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:40:15.377" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="17845" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="18168" AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;This was done with the moon: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.space.com/25884-radar-telescopes-moon-subsurface-features.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Radio Dishes Peer Beneath Moon's Surface&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/KPAtE.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/KPAtE.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;enter image description here&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2016-08-31T16:28:47.823" Id="18166" LastActivityDate="2016-09-01T16:37:37.527" LastEditDate="2016-08-31T20:27:29.150" LastEditorUserId="11143" OwnerUserId="13718" PostTypeId="1" Score="4" Tags="&lt;the-moon&gt;&lt;radio-astronomy&gt;&lt;radio-telescope&gt;" Title="Can radio telescopes such as arecibo image the subsurface of asteroids or planets?" ViewCount="180"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Yes, but not Earth-based ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mars.nasa.gov/mro/mission/instruments/sharad/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;SHARAD&lt;/a&gt; (Shallow Radar) is an instrument on the Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter which performs subsurface imaging of Mars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is an image from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Polar_Cap_SHARAD_PIA13164.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; of deposit layers on Mars's north pole, taken by SHARAD:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/Gvib1.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/Gvib1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mars north pole deposit layers&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2016-09-01T16:37:37.527" Id="18177" LastActivityDate="2016-09-01T16:37:37.527" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="18166" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="18325" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;Since the direction of Vernal Equinox lies in the Pisces constellation, why is its symbol Aries? Shouldn't it be ♓ ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this a historical anachronism, only invalidated by axial precession of Earth?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="5" CreationDate="2016-09-12T13:08:04.467" FavoriteCount="1" Id="18324" LastActivityDate="2016-09-12T15:31:02.730" OwnerUserId="83" PostTypeId="1" Score="6" Tags="&lt;coordinate&gt;&lt;history&gt;&lt;symbols&gt;" Title="Why is the symbol of Vernal Equinox ♈?" ViewCount="751"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;As Wikipedia explains in the article on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zodiac#Precession_of_the_equinoxes&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Zodiac&lt;/a&gt;, the Zodiac was originally developed with the assumption of fixed equinoxes. It is assumed this is because the Babylonians who developed the Zodiac were unaware of the precession of the equinoxes. At that time, about 2500 years ago, the vernal equinox did in fact lie in Aries. For this reason, in astrology, that time is referred to as &quot;the Age of Aries&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, in modern times these astrological concepts are scarcely important to astronomy, and in the few cases where the astronomical symbol for the vernal equinox is used, it is more practical to have a fixed symbol than a changing one.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2016-09-12T15:31:02.730" Id="18325" LastActivityDate="2016-09-12T15:31:02.730" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="18324" PostTypeId="2" Score="8"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;A major factor, is that Venus' volcanoes are still active. Mars's died millions of years ago. If they were still erupting, then Mars' atmosphere would be much thicker today.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2016-09-15T01:31:09.703" Id="18355" LastActivityDate="2016-09-15T01:31:09.703" OwnerUserId="14242" ParentId="639" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="18445" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;Or are seismic phenomenon named differently when they happen on other celestial bodies? If so, what are they called?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="8" CreationDate="2016-09-22T13:52:22.447" FavoriteCount="2" Id="18443" LastActivityDate="2016-09-22T14:44:00.340" OwnerUserId="9803" PostTypeId="1" Score="4" Tags="&lt;planet&gt;&lt;terminology&gt;" Title="If an earthquake happens on Mars, is it still an earthquake?" ViewCount="406"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;As pointed out in the comments, some do prefer to use different terms for &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quake_%28natural_phenomenon%29&quot;&gt;quakes&lt;/a&gt; on other bodies, and you can see &lt;a href=&quot;https://scholar.google.com/scholar?hl=en&amp;amp;q=marsquake&amp;amp;btnG=&amp;amp;as_sdt=1%2C44&amp;amp;as_sdtp=&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; that &quot;marsquake&quot; does have scholarly usage. That said, there is also scholarly usage for &lt;a href=&quot;https://scholar.google.com/scholar?q=%22earthquake+on+mars%22&amp;amp;btnG=&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;as_sdt=0%2C44&quot;&gt;&quot;earthquake&quot;&lt;/a&gt; in this context. If you think about it, this makes sense given that one definition of &quot;earth&quot; is &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.oxforddictionaries.com/definition/earth&quot;&gt;&quot;the substance of the land surface&quot;&lt;/a&gt;, i.e. the ground. This definition of &quot;earth&quot; is agnostic to which terrestrial planet the land surface is on.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2016-09-22T14:44:00.340" Id="18445" LastActivityDate="2016-09-22T14:44:00.340" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="18443" PostTypeId="2" Score="7"/>
  <row AnswerCount="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;I'm well aware of the celestial bodies considered as the oldest visible in our galaxy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My question might feel a bit odd: What is the oldest thing in the universe? I am puzzled with this question as the only answer that I have found by myself sounds weird.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the notion of &quot;old&quot; only makes sense in an observable and ellapsing timeline, the most obvious answer to me would be &quot;Time is the oldest thing&quot;. There is no such thing as a measurement of &quot;old&quot; until there is actually mass to allow time, so which predates which? I'm pretty sure the answer will tightly be linked to Planck's constant, but how?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What am I doing wrong? How could I find relief in an answer that wouldn't be just philosophical, but also logical? :)&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="11" CreationDate="2016-10-12T13:21:17.280" Id="18680" LastActivityDate="2016-10-12T23:04:52.447" LastEditDate="2016-10-12T13:56:05.453" LastEditorUserId="14550" OwnerUserId="14550" PostTypeId="1" Score="2" Tags="&lt;space-time&gt;&lt;time-dilation&gt;" Title="What is the oldest thing?" ViewCount="181"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;If &quot;time&quot; is considered to be a valid answer, I would like to propose a more fundamental principle: the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wave_function&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;wave function&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since a wave function is a description of the quantum state of any physical system, there must necessarily have been a wave function as soon as quantum physics applied to the Universe. Since we generally assume &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uniformitarianism&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;uniformity in nature&lt;/a&gt;, there is no reason to consider any sort of &quot;pre-quantum&quot; era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All right, I can hear some of you complaining already that it says right in the paragraph above that a wave function is a &lt;em&gt;description&lt;/em&gt;, but isn't that what time is after all? It is just a description of a change in the state of the Universe. If you really want to split hairs, you can say it's actually a quantum state--but wait that's just a condition of a quantum system--but wait that's just saying that the first thing is a thing. What is a thing, really?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2016-10-12T20:14:03.127" Id="18684" LastActivityDate="2016-10-12T20:14:03.127" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="18680" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;From my basic understating, &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Momentum is being transfered from the Earth's rotation to the Moon's orbit by tidal friction. The Earth's rotation slows down and the Moon receedes from the Earth as it moves into a higher orbit. This will continue until the Earth's rotational period is equal to the orbital period of the Moon, i.e the Earth is tidally locked to the Moon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming I have the above correct - and please correct me if I don't - will there, realistically, be enough time for tidal locking to  occur before the sun expands and engulfs the Earth? Or is there another reason the Earth will never be locked towards the Moon?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2016-10-20T13:18:26.970" FavoriteCount="4" Id="18794" LastActivityDate="2016-10-21T15:31:42.233" OwnerUserId="14633" PostTypeId="1" Score="9" Tags="&lt;earth&gt;&lt;tidal-forces&gt;&lt;the-moon&gt;&lt;tidal-locking&gt;" Title="Will the Earth ever be tidally locked to the Moon?" ViewCount="2259"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;As the moon orbits Earth, tidal forces slow down the Earth's rotation by 2 milliseconds per century. Eventually, in tens of billions of years, the Earth and Moon would achieve a double tidal lock, where both are stuck with one side facing the other as they orbit the Earth-Moon barycenter. In 7.5 billion years, the Sun will expand past the Earth's current orbit, but the Earth may drift out further, preventing it from being vaporized. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this is beside the point, because in about one billion years, all of Earth's water will have boiled away, meaning that there would be no more ocean tides, and thus the Earth-Moon system will likely never achieve a double tidal lock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spaceanswers.com/solar-system/will-the-moon-ever-leave-earths-orbit/&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Will the Moon ever leave Earth’s orbit? - Giles Sparrow, Space Answers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://barnyard.syr.edu/eccentric.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Harvesting Lunar Eccentricity? - Terry R. McConnell, Syracuse University&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.universetoday.com/128350/will-earth-lock-moon/&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;When Will Earth Lock to the Moon? - Fraser Cain, Universe Today&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-sun-will-eventually-engulf-earth-maybe/&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;The Sun Will Eventually Engulf Earth--Maybe - David Appell, Scientific American&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mnras.oxfordjournals.org/content/386/1/155.full&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Distant future of the Sun and Earth revisited - K.-P. Schröder and Robert Connon Smith, MNRAS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2013/12/131216142310.htm&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;When will Earth lose its oceans? - CNRS, Science Daily&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="7" CreationDate="2016-10-20T13:39:23.853" Id="18795" LastActivityDate="2016-10-21T15:31:42.233" LastEditDate="2016-10-21T15:31:42.233" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="18794" PostTypeId="2" Score="13"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="19334" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;I want to make clock that shows current time on different solar bodies. For that I need to know how to count time on those planets. Is there any official definition of times on other planets in our solar system? Brief google search did not help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am capable of implementing library for this myself but I wonder about current &lt;em&gt;state of the art&lt;/em&gt; of time telling on other planets. So basically I want to know these things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is there any official time standard?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If so, where can I find it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If not, how should I approach this problem? Should I make something like Unix epoch at some time in the past for every planet?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for any tips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EDIT: Ok, so on Mars, seconds, minutes and hours were made longer to keep 24-hour day. Is this viable to other planets as well? Venus aside for now :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was also thinking about keeping the hours the same, having days as long as many whole hours fits in them plus smaller compensation hours which would have length of (total_minutes_in_solar_day % 60). This concept is from David Weber novels, if you are familiar with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EDIT2: Based on discussion in the comments, I'll try to make some basic model that would be if possible applicable to any planetary body (thinking ahead :)). This is obviously not going to have any serious real world application but I would still like it to have some sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for your input, I will leave the question open for some more time if anyone wants to add their opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="19" CreationDate="2016-12-07T21:40:18.487" FavoriteCount="1" Id="19333" LastActivityDate="2019-07-22T03:11:05.853" LastEditDate="2016-12-07T22:26:26.067" LastEditorUserId="15089" OwnerUserId="15089" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;planet&gt;&lt;solar-system&gt;&lt;time&gt;" Title="&quot;Official&quot; time for other planets" ViewCount="458"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Time on Mars is measured in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Timekeeping_on_Mars&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;sols&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://space.stackexchange.com/q/18655/58&quot;&gt;Venus&lt;/a&gt; could be a little trickier, depending on your application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not aware of any timekeeping system for any other planets. There hasn't been a need for one yet. So, again depending on your application, you could come up with various different possible schemes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speculation (based on the OP's input regarding application):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mercury - because of the length of the day, I doubt would-be colonists would measure time in days. They would probably use Earth time (because of communications) and also keep track of Mercury years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus, Neptune - no colonization, no timekeeping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2016-12-07T21:49:39.973" Id="19334" LastActivityDate="2016-12-07T22:21:05.810" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:58:55.210" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="19333" PostTypeId="2" Score="5"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="19382" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;If I look at the night sky, which easily identifiable stars have known exoplanets, and what are the names of those planets?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the recent discovery of so many exoplanets, it is a nice idea to look at the stars with this new knowledge. They will no longer seem like a bunch of anonymous white dots. &lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2016-12-12T21:23:47.213" Id="19381" LastActivityDate="2016-12-12T22:00:06.663" LastEditDate="2016-12-12T22:00:06.663" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="15141" PostTypeId="1" Score="5" Tags="&lt;exoplanet&gt;&lt;constellations&gt;&lt;star-gazing&gt;" Title="Which stars, identifiable with the naked eye, have exoplanets?" ViewCount="212"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Stars with an apparent magnitude of 7.0 or greater are typically not visible to the naked eye. So if you take a list of exoplanetary host stars, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_exoplanetary_host_stars&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;, and you sort by apparent magnitude, in ascending order, then you will see a list of identifiable stars known to have exoplanets, until you reach an apparent magnitude of 7.0 on the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding the star can be trickier, but Wikipedia will usually show you what constellation you can find the star in. With a little work, and maybe the help of some other posts on this site, you could probably identify which stars are visible in your area and time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most exoplanets have not been given formal names themselves, but instead a lowercase letter is appended to the end of the name or designation of the star, for example &quot;Beta Geminorum b (abbreviated β Geminorum b, β Gem b) and HD 62509 b&quot; for Pollux b, the first planet discovered around Pollux. Incidentally in 2014, the International Astronomical Union did release a process for giving proper names to exoplanets, and Pollux b was given the name Thestias. If you look up other exoplanets on Wikipedia, you can find out whether they have been given proper names as well.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2016-12-12T21:42:54.737" Id="19382" LastActivityDate="2016-12-12T21:42:54.737" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="19381" PostTypeId="2" Score="5"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="19685" AnswerCount="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;Why does the traslation movement of the earth last the same time as the four seasons? The seasons could take 100 days or 200 or 20 years (aprox. like in GoT)... but exactly (exactly???) 1 year. Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit: I think that I need to redefine the question.&lt;br&gt;
I define a year as the full traslation movement of the earth around the sun.&lt;br&gt;
And the four seasons as the full movement of the perpendicular axis from 0 to 23.5 to 0 again to -23.5 to 0 again.&lt;br&gt;
Why do these two movements take the same time?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="5" CreationDate="2017-01-09T16:25:25.877" Id="19683" LastActivityDate="2017-01-10T15:30:14.163" LastEditDate="2017-01-10T15:30:14.163" LastEditorUserId="15451" OwnerUserId="15451" PostTypeId="1" Score="-2" Tags="&lt;earth&gt;" Title="Why does the traslation movement of the earth last the same time as the four seasons?" ViewCount="460"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I suspect that this question may get closed as too trivial, but to put it simply a year is more or less defined as the time that it takes for the Earth to complete an orbit around the Sun. Because the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Axial_tilt#Earth&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Earth rotates on an axis that is tilted relative to its orbit around the Sun&lt;/a&gt;, rather than perpendicular, the Northern and Southern hemispheres alternate being inclined toward or away from the Sun. The hemisphere that is facing the Sun experiences Summer and the hemisphere that is facing away from the Sun experiences Winter. So a cycle of seasons is roughly equivalent to the time it takes for the Earth to complete its orbit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/qbxdb.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/qbxdb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Earth&amp;#39;s orbit plus axial tilt creates seasons&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;Image Credit: &lt;a href=&quot;http://scijinks.jpl.nasa.gov/review/solstice/seasons-earth-orbit_large.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;NASA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2017-01-09T16:42:53.523" Id="19685" LastActivityDate="2017-01-09T16:42:53.523" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="19683" PostTypeId="2" Score="6"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="19936" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;I saw a very bright star in the night sky on Monday (Jan 30, 2017). The star was in the Western sky and was directly above the crescent moon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My location is Toronto, Ontario. Canada. It was about 8pm at night, but by 10pm the star had disappeared over the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm sure this was a planet as it shined brighter then any of the other stars, but I couldn't guess which one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you identify this planet for me?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2017-02-02T01:27:38.390" Id="19919" LastActivityDate="2017-02-03T22:11:47.413" OwnerUserId="695" PostTypeId="1" Score="1" Tags="&lt;star&gt;&lt;planet&gt;" Title="Can you identify this planet seen in the night sky?" ViewCount="176"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;This Community Wiki answer was created to preserve knowledge while other answer(s) are under review.&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/users/11822/dr-chuck&quot;&gt;Dr Chuck&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It was Venus. It should have been 10 - 15 degrees above the moon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/users/2031/wayfaring-stranger&quot;&gt;Wayfaring Stranger&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Venus is whiter than Jupiter, Saturn, or Mars, which have yellowish, yellow, and reddish tints instead. It's also usually much brighter than the other planets, including Mercury. Mercury always hangs closer to the sun than did Venus in early Feb 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CommunityOwnedDate="2017-02-03T22:11:47.413" CreationDate="2017-02-03T22:11:47.413" Id="19936" LastActivityDate="2017-02-03T22:11:47.413" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:06.910" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="19919" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://exoplanets.nasa.gov/news/1419/nasa-telescope-reveals-largest-batch-of-earth-size-habitable-zone-planets-around-single-star/&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;TRAPPIST-1 system&lt;/a&gt; is around an ultra-cool dwarf star. I went looking for more information on that kind of star, and found very little. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ultra-cool_dwarf&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Wikipedia article&lt;/a&gt; on it lengthened from a minimal stub to one paragraph in the 15 minutes from when I began the search, after the press conference on the discovery of 7 Earth-sized planets in orbit around TRAPPIST-1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What kind of star is this?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2017-02-22T19:18:15.963" FavoriteCount="3" Id="20127" LastActivityDate="2017-02-24T20:09:00.337" LastEditDate="2017-02-23T14:33:17.903" LastEditorUserId="2153" OwnerUserId="2810" PostTypeId="1" Score="20" Tags="&lt;star&gt;&lt;terminology&gt;&lt;dwarf-star&gt;&lt;trappist-1&gt;" Title="So, what exactly is an 'ultra-cool' dwarf star?" ViewCount="4022"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;http://adsabs.harvard.edu/full/1998ASPC..134..405K&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Spectroscopic Properties of Ultra-cool Dwarfs and Brown Dwarf&lt;/a&gt; by J.D. Kirkpatrick, the working definition of ultra-cool dwarf is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;dwarfs having classifications of M7 or later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is referring to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stellar_classification&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;stellar classification&lt;/a&gt; system which categorizes stars by their spectral characteristics. Class M stars have a surface temperature less than 4000 K, and &quot;M7 or later&quot; means surface temperature less than 2500 K. Though it should be noted that this is a working definition, and the Wikipedia article identifies ultra-cool dwarfs as objects with surface temperature less than 2700 K. It is possible that the term is still used somewhat loosely in scientific papers.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2017-02-22T19:30:37.797" Id="20128" LastActivityDate="2017-02-22T19:30:37.797" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="20127" PostTypeId="2" Score="8"/>
  <row AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;I have problems to understand the point of &quot;mean sun&quot; and &quot;true sun&quot;.
As I understood the mean sun is set in the center of the earth orbit (which is a circle). So Ptolemy, Copernicus and Brahe used the &quot;mean sun&quot;, however they knew that this isn't the real position of the sun? Did they do that due to the reason it would fit with the mars oppositions?*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(*Three of them used circles to describe orbits of planets. But if they want to link that together with the observations it wouldn't fit.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is that right? So even Ptolemy knew that the sun isn't in the middle of the orbit of the earth?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a website which I think describes it: &lt;a href=&quot;http://science.larouchepac.com/kepler/newastronomy/part1/5/index.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;http://science.larouchepac.com/kepler/newastronomy/part1/5/index.html&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://science.larouchepac.com/kepler/newastronomy/part1/6/index.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;http://science.larouchepac.com/kepler/newastronomy/part1/6/index.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to my first language is not English it might be possible that I didn't understand some important aspects of the given links.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2017-03-23T21:30:57.923" FavoriteCount="1" Id="20515" LastActivityDate="2017-05-24T00:04:45.477" OwnerUserId="15474" PostTypeId="1" Score="2" Tags="&lt;the-sun&gt;&lt;orbit&gt;&lt;amateur-observing&gt;&lt;mars&gt;&lt;kepler&gt;" Title="Mean and true Sun" ViewCount="679"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Yes, Ptolemy adopted Hipparchus's idea that epicycles and eccentric orbits could explain the irregular motion of the Sun. From David McClung's biography of Hipparchus:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hipparchus also created the first reasonably accurate model of the motion of the sun and moon. Using the idea of epicycles, probably introduced by the mathematician Apollonius of Perga, he was able to create a model that accurately predicted some key positions of the moon's motion. He created a similar model to predict the position of the sun. (See the Ptolemy page for more information on epicycles and its subsequent use in the planetary models.) His model didn't work for all cases, but it marked the real beginning of trying to create a predictive model that matched data.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Even though the orbits are circular and going around the earth, the earth is not at the exact center of the orbits of the sun and moon. (They were eccentric orbits.) Hipparchus needed to use the epicycles and eccentric orbits because the observed motion of the sun around the ecliptic was not at a constant rate - in the winter the sun moved a little bit faster and in the summer the sun moved a little bit slower. Using an eccentric orbit for the sun and moon, and using small epicycles, Hipparchus gives the foundations of the classic Greek model of the solar system that approximately predicts the positions of the moon and sun that matched positions and predicted key dates and events pretty well. &lt;strong&gt;Eventually, Ptolemy takes this Hipparchan model and fully applies it to the motion of the planets - and eventually produces a full, working model of the solar system.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;emphasis added&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An epicycle is like an orbit along an orbit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/P82K2.png&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/P82K2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Epicycle&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An eccentric orbit is an orbit where the inner body does not occupy the center point of the outer body's orbit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.themcclungs.net/astronomy/people/hipparchus.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Historical Astronomy: Ancient Greeks: Hipparchus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2017-03-23T21:48:01.927" Id="20516" LastActivityDate="2017-03-24T22:43:57.043" LastEditDate="2017-03-24T22:43:57.043" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="20515" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row AnswerCount="0" Body="&lt;p&gt;In a recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1803.04716.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; (Cosmic clocks: A Tight Radius - Velocity Relationship for
HI-Selected Galaxies by Meurer, et al.), it was noted in the conclusion that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[This] implies a constant orbital time of ∼1 Gyr at [the outermost] radius [of disc galaxies].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given what we knew about disc galaxies and dark matter up to this point, is this an unexpected conclusion? My sense is that it is strange that all disc galaxies have a constant rotation regardless of their size, but my intuition may be wrong. I know that dark matter speeds up the rotation of the outer parts of disc galaxies, but isn't it strange that they converge on this value?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="11" CreationDate="2018-03-15T18:17:17.473" FavoriteCount="5" Id="25507" LastActivityDate="2018-11-02T18:29:03.563" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="1" Score="16" Tags="&lt;galaxy&gt;&lt;astrophysics&gt;&lt;dark-matter&gt;" Title="Is it &quot;weird&quot; that all disc galaxies rotate once every billion years?" ViewCount="521"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="28644" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;There is a phrase in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2018/07/180703105953.htm&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Science Daily&lt;/a&gt; article which appears to be wrong: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Milky Way has a very high content of carbonaceous dust, which has been shown to be very rare in other galaxies.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there a theory that explains these observations?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="6" CreationDate="2018-07-07T13:51:17.437" Id="26892" LastActivityDate="2018-12-06T14:37:23.537" LastEditDate="2018-07-08T07:47:25.087" LastEditorUserId="1528" OwnerUserId="1528" PostTypeId="1" Score="2" Tags="&lt;interstellar-medium&gt;&lt;dust&gt;&lt;elemental-abundances&gt;" Title="carbonaceous content of galaxies?" ViewCount="94"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="27000" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;I saw multiple news sites reporting that a team discovered 12 new Jupiter's moons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnet.com/videos/twelve-new-jupiter-moons-found-including-one-reckless-one/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;c|net - Twelve new Jupiter moons found, including one reckless one&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/d-brief/2018/07/17/new-jupiter-moons/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Discover - Jupiter’s Got Twelve New Moons — One is a Bit of a Problem Child&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While some other news sites claim that they found only 10 new moons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-018-05725-6&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;nature - Jupiter has 10 more moons we didn't know about — and they're weird&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://earthsky.org/space/10-new-moons-discovered-jupiter-1-oddball&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;EarthSky - Astronomers discover 10 new moons for Jupiter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why does the number of moons differ in the different articles? Did the team now found 10 or 12 moons?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="7" CreationDate="2018-07-19T12:15:48.280" Id="26999" LastActivityDate="2018-07-23T12:46:53.420" LastEditDate="2018-07-23T12:46:53.420" LastEditorUserId="23730" OwnerDisplayName="Yannjoel" OwnerUserId="23730" PostTypeId="1" Score="18" Tags="&lt;jupiter&gt;&lt;natural-satellites&gt;" Title="Did we discover 10 or 12 new moons of Jupiter?" ViewCount="3184"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Per the &lt;a href=&quot;https://carnegiescience.edu/news/dozen-new-moons-jupiter-discovered-including-one-%E2%80%9Coddball%E2%80%9D&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Carnegie Science article&lt;/a&gt; that Magic Octopus Urn linked from NASA in the comments, a Carnegie Science team led by Scott S. Sheppard noticed something new in spring of 2017 (though some observations occurred as early as 2016). It took a year to confirm the discovery of the new moons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ten of the moons orbit in the outer swarm of moons, which is one of the ways to divide the groups of moons. Nine of these follow the pattern of the other moons which orbit Jupiter in retrograde (the opposite direction of the planet's rotation). One they call &quot;oddball&quot; because it orbits prograde (the same direction as the planet's rotation) and has a more inclined orbit than the inner prograde moons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two of the moons orbit in the inner group, which is what brings the total number of discoveries up to twelve, as referenced in the first set of articles in your post. Like the other inner moons, these orbit prograde.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the retrograde moons and the &quot;oddball&quot; were first noticed in 2016. One of the inner group and the rest of the retrograde moons were discovered in 2017. The second inner group moon was discovered in 2018, then most were announced together on July 17, 2018. (Dates collected from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moons_of_Jupiter#List&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The retrograde moon discovered in 2016 and one of the retrograde moons discovered in 2017 were announced in 2017, this means only ten moons were announced on July 17, 2018, which is why the Nature article refers to ten new moons. The EarthSky article talks some about the ten and the twelve, and it does clarify both groups (divided by inner/outer and year of announcement).&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2018-07-19T13:13:45.057" Id="27000" LastActivityDate="2018-07-19T14:30:21.577" LastEditDate="2018-07-19T14:30:21.577" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="26999" PostTypeId="2" Score="20"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="27679" AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;I have read that the Big Bang created space-time, but how could this be possible? The Big Bang was itself a singularity, and a singularity is a point in space-time where the curvature becomes infinite. So how could the Big Bang create something without which its existence would not have been possible?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2018-09-17T15:21:48.963" Id="27676" LastActivityDate="2018-10-01T12:06:31.540" LastEditDate="2018-10-01T12:06:31.540" LastEditorUserId="23940" OwnerUserId="24297" PostTypeId="1" Score="1" Tags="&lt;space-time&gt;" Title="Beginning of space-time" ViewCount="184"/>
  <row Body="&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is impossible to measure anything that happened in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Planck_units#Cosmology&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Planck Era&lt;/a&gt;, so physicists are unsure whether the universe actually began from a singularity or whether the singularity in the Big Bang theory represents an inability to describe the universe at that time. In fact, &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/a/137497/28199&quot;&gt;Most physicists believe that this is a mathematical artefact and does not describe what actually happened.&lt;/a&gt;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It would be more accurate to say that the Big Bang is the beginning of space-time, than that it &quot;created&quot; space-time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Big Bang is a description of how the universe evolved in its earliest stages, not exactly a resolution to why the universe came to be. The latter is really a question for philosophy, not something that can be addressed by science &lt;em&gt;per se&lt;/em&gt;. Science informs our philosophy, but does not make philosophical claims.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2018-09-17T15:51:08.503" Id="27679" LastActivityDate="2018-09-17T17:09:52.973" LastEditDate="2018-09-17T17:09:52.973" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="27676" PostTypeId="2" Score="4"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="27681" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;Is it theoretically possible that the Universe is expanding due to additional Big Bang events that have occurred at the same location that the original Big Bang occurred at?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps there has been an ongoing series of smaller Big Bang events over the past 13.7 billion years, which although were not as massive in scale as the original Big Bang, have created a large amount of new space-time and new matter that has resulted in the Universe expanding.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2018-09-17T19:43:56.760" Id="27680" LastActivityDate="2018-09-17T20:04:59.063" OwnerDisplayName="user23327" PostTypeId="1" Score="1" Tags="&lt;universe&gt;&lt;astrophysics&gt;&lt;cosmology&gt;&lt;big-bang-theory&gt;" Title="Is it possible that the Universe is expanding due to additional Big Bang events?" ViewCount="133"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;You may need to revisit the theory behind the &lt;a href=&quot;https://simple.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_Bang&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Big Bang&lt;/a&gt;. The Big Bang is more or less a description of what the early universe looks like if you view expansion in reverse. The single &quot;Big Bang&quot; at the beginning of our universe is the only &quot;Big Bang&quot; event predicted by expansion. Also, the Big Bang did not happen in a single place, it happened everywhere in the universe. Finally, the Big Bang did not create space-time, and the expansion of the universe is not the creation of new matter. The Big Bang describes a time when the metric of space-time was extremely dense, and expansion is the metric of space-time increasing as below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/y3vMl.png&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/y3vMl.png&quot; alt=&quot;Expansion of space&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The distance between points in space increases, but the same mass-energy is there as before.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2018-09-17T20:04:59.063" Id="27681" LastActivityDate="2018-09-17T20:04:59.063" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="27680" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="28633" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;In the visible universe, we have a lot of matter to energy conversion going on in stars.  Is there an equivalent structure that is converting dark matter to dark energy?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2018-12-05T15:09:28.540" Id="28632" LastActivityDate="2018-12-05T15:28:01.347" OwnerUserId="14085" PostTypeId="1" Score="0" Tags="&lt;dark-matter&gt;&lt;dark-energy&gt;" Title="Are there Dark Stars" ViewCount="101"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Dark matter has different properties than ordinary matter. It cannot collide, and thus it alone cannot coalesce to form a star. Furthermore, dark matter and dark energy are unassociated properties. There is not currently any reason to assume dark matter can be converted to dark energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, there is a &lt;em&gt;strictly hypothetical&lt;/em&gt; entity referred to as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dark_star_(dark_matter)&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;dark star&lt;/a&gt;, which does involve dark matter. While composed mostly of ordinary matter, this entity is hypothesized to include a high concentration of dark matter, generating heat and preventing fusion of the ordinary matter. If dark stars existed, it is likely they existed in the early universe and did not survive to the present. They are modeled to be large clouds--4 to 2000 astronomical units in diameter--of hydrogen and helium, with a surface temperature low enough to make them invisible to the naked eye. &lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2018-12-05T15:28:01.347" Id="28633" LastActivityDate="2018-12-05T15:28:01.347" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="28632" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;From the introduction of the source paper, we can see that what is described is a particular bump in the extinction curve of the galaxy centered at 2175 Ångström (a unit of length used for wavelength). The strength of this bump is large compared to the Large Magellanic Cloud, and is rarer toward the Small Magellanic Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in the comments, the main candidates for the origin of the feature are non-graphitic carbon or polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs). The absence in other environments is attributed to low metallicities or different radiative environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, this is a case where we lose information in science reporting. &quot;Very high content of carbonaceous dust&quot; was a translation of a specific strength at a specific wavelength, and &quot;other galaxies&quot; was a translation of surrounding galaxies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1806.00293&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;The 2175 Å extinction feature in the optical afterglow spectrum of GRB 180325A at z=2.25 - Zafar, et al.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2018-12-06T14:37:23.537" Id="28644" LastActivityDate="2018-12-06T14:37:23.537" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="26892" PostTypeId="2" Score="1"/>
  <row Body="" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2018-12-10T14:25:33.593" Id="28701" LastActivityDate="2018-12-10T14:25:33.593" LastEditDate="2018-12-10T14:25:33.593" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="5" Score="0"/>
  <row Body="Questions about planetary dust storms, such as those on Mars and Titan" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2018-12-10T14:25:33.593" Id="28702" LastActivityDate="2018-12-10T14:25:33.593" LastEditDate="2018-12-10T14:25:33.593" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="4" Score="0"/>
  <row Body="" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2019-01-31T18:25:14.663" Id="29415" LastActivityDate="2019-01-31T18:25:14.663" LastEditDate="2019-01-31T18:25:14.663" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="5" Score="0"/>
  <row Body="Questions about the apparent force stretching a body towards and away from the center of mass of another body due to the variance in acceleration due to gravity" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2019-01-31T18:25:14.663" Id="29416" LastActivityDate="2019-01-31T18:25:14.663" LastEditDate="2019-01-31T18:25:14.663" LastEditorUserId="6" OwnerUserId="6" PostTypeId="4" Score="0"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="33153" AnswerCount="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;I am reading about the accelerating expansion of the universe and something struck me. The observation that things further away were accelerating away faster and that early observations made it look as though we were situated at the center of the universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, it seems as though the universe itself is expanding and not that the things within the universe were moving away from each other. Instead it seems as though the expansion itself is creating more space between the contents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I also saw an amazing video on the eventual death of everything in the universe. This seems weird to me because as I understand it energy and matter don't go away they just change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it got me thinking, what if this eventual heat death of the universe is simply this expansion eventually ripping everything apart until every particle simply is to far apart to interact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, as things progress the expansion will affect the contents of the universe even down to the particle level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this the case? Or am I misunderstanding this subject?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2019-08-26T16:42:02.473" Id="33152" LastActivityDate="2019-11-16T05:30:33.187" OwnerUserId="13339" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;universe&gt;&lt;expansion&gt;&lt;heat&gt;" Title="Is the eventual heat death of the universe due to the expansion of the universe?" ViewCount="131"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;As far as I understand it, the heat death of the universe is a consequence of entropy, not expansion. All processes result in the shifting of some energy to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Waste_heat&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;higher entropy&lt;/a&gt;. Though the observable universe is an open system, the entire universe is an isolated system, so as more and more energy gets shifted to higher entropy over time the universe will eventually reach a state where effectively no work can be done.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2019-08-26T17:06:47.467" Id="33153" LastActivityDate="2019-08-26T17:06:47.467" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="33152" PostTypeId="2" Score="9"/>
  <row AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;In astronomy I usually see Earth designated with a circled plus or cross. NASA &lt;a href=&quot;https://solarsystem.nasa.gov/resources/680/solar-system-symbols/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;says&lt;/a&gt; this is the Earth's astronomical symbol. Wikipedia tends to use it, for example designating the Earth–Moon distance by &lt;span class=&quot;math-container&quot;&gt;$\Delta_{\oplus L}$&lt;/span&gt;. But Wikipedia also &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Earth_symbol&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;says&lt;/a&gt; that the globus cruciger ♁ is used to symbolize Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does the latter find any usage in astronomy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(The actual Unicode code point for the circled plus Earth symbol is U+1F728 but this does not render for me, so I used the graphically similar U+2295 instead.)&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2019-09-09T16:40:13.060" Id="33304" LastActivityDate="2019-09-09T18:10:07.047" OwnerUserId="29305" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;symbols&gt;" Title="When are the symbols ⊕ and ♁ used to designate Earth?" ViewCount="99"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Yes, I don't know how common the globus cruciger is, but it is used at least here for the electron neutrino pp flux at Earth: &lt;a href=&quot;https://lss.fnal.gov/conf/C0606131/Neutrino06-Proceedings.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;NEUTRINO 2006: Proceedings of the XXIIth International Conference on Neutrino Physics and Astrophysics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2019-09-09T18:10:07.047" Id="33306" LastActivityDate="2019-09-09T18:10:07.047" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="33304" PostTypeId="2" Score="1"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="33472" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;I have looked at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.issp.ac.ru/iao/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;official site&lt;/a&gt; but the link for previous papers isn't working.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2019-09-23T16:19:37.130" Id="33471" LastActivityDate="2019-09-23T17:18:13.003" LastEditDate="2019-09-23T17:17:32.240" LastEditorUserId="616" OwnerUserId="9297" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;astrophysics&gt;" Title="Where can I find the previous years' International Astronomy Olympiad question papers?" ViewCount="43"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;A blog called &lt;a href=&quot;https://scienceolympiadsbd.blogspot.com/2014/10/iao-problems-2011-2014.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Science Olympiad Blog&lt;/a&gt; claims to have the problem sheets for 2011-2014.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2019-09-23T17:18:13.003" Id="33472" LastActivityDate="2019-09-23T17:18:13.003" OwnerUserId="6" ParentId="33471" PostTypeId="2" Score="4"/>
</posts>