<?xml version="1.0" ?><posts>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="3417" AnswerCount="14" Body="&lt;p&gt;I work as a researcher in a very abstract field of Mathematics (&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.2178/jsl/1208359058&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;this kind of thing&lt;/a&gt;) It is very pure Mathematics, without any concrete applications. When I meet somebody for the first time, they often ask me about my job and they want to know the details: What are you working right now? OK, you just wrote a paper, but about what? What theorem did you prove?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the abstractness of my field, and since those people usually have at most a vague memory of High School math, the only sincere answer would be: I cannot explain it to you because you would have to know a bunch of stuff you do not know, and I cannot teach you those stuff either, because it would takes years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course such an answer would be rude. So my question is: How could I deal politely in such situations?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTES:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It seems to me that many users have interpreted the question as: &quot;How can I explain my job as a mathematician to the average person?&quot;. I appreciate the efforts, however, that is not my intended question. The question is how can I politely deal in those situation &lt;strong&gt;since&lt;/strong&gt; I cannot explain my job. Note also that my question is about when people ask &lt;strong&gt;details&lt;/strong&gt; about my job. Of course if they just want a short answer, that is not a problem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many answers are of the kind &quot;you should be able to give a vague explanation…&quot;, and some even say &quot;if you cannot explain to everyone then you do not understand it...&quot; I kindly invite those who think so to try to explain the material that I linked to the average Joe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2017-09-03T09:32:13.130" FavoriteCount="24" Id="3213" LastActivityDate="2018-05-31T17:50:33.200" LastEditDate="2018-02-01T11:26:21.983" LastEditorUserId="6144" OwnerUserId="4874" PostTypeId="1" Score="122" Tags="&lt;politeness&gt;&lt;introductions&gt;" Title="How to deal politely with people asking about your job but unable to understand it?" ViewCount="24652"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;My five-year-old son and my non-technical friends have a similar understanding of my career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The general job title:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Software Engineer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I do it for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Aerospace and defense&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My son understands that I tell computers how to fly spaceships. It's not true, but he does seem to grasp that what I do is in support of efforts like that--and that there are a lot of people and jobs in between.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, my friends joke that I am a &quot;rocket scientist&quot;. They know it's not true, but it is a simple way of saying that I work on something complex in support of a larger aim which they understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a mathematician, you work in support of mathematics as a whole. The framework of mathematics has &lt;em&gt;loads&lt;/em&gt; of practical applications--arguably, all of human development hinges on mathematics. You can tell people that as a mathematician, you support the ongoing effort to deepen the understanding of this framework that has done so much for us, so that it can continue to do more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tough part is when they ask for more details. For me, if asked what exactly I'm doing, the answer might be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I'm producing upgrades to the health monitoring suite of the common runtime environment for our laboratories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That might be a bunch of nonsense to most people, so I start with &quot;I support the common software for simulation labs.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For you, maybe you start with &quot;I study the rules of math itself, independent of practical applications.&quot; You can reiterate that this is in support of the whole framework of mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If they press for more still, I just might tell them about that health monitoring suite, at which point the conversation might stop. It's not rude--they just realize they've hit the bounds of what they can relate to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start broad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tell them why the whole enterprise that you support is important&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go deeper if asked until they stop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be ok with them having a knowingly flawed understanding of what you do&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my experience, they will understand that what you do is important, even if they don't understand why. Isn't that all you need?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2017-09-06T15:02:38.960" Id="3401" LastActivityDate="2017-09-06T15:02:38.960" OwnerUserId="5130" ParentId="3213" PostTypeId="2" Score="4"/>
  <row AnswerCount="4" Body="&lt;p&gt;I have a male nurse who comes to my house every so often to give me medication and observe me all day for any reactions. When he is here, he leaves pee puddles on the floor in front of the toilet (this is obviously urine - it is yellow). Due to my medical condition, it isn't easy for me to clean it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to talk to him about this and let him know that I'd like for him to clean up after himself. However, I'm unsure how to tactfully ask him to do this and would like advice on what to say to him. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do really like my nurse other than this problem of his. Requesting a different nurse is not really an option I want to consider. Having a nurse come into your home and stay with you the entire day is pretty awkward and I have been most comfortable with him, so far. He is also very skilled (the best nurse I've had) when it comes to administering my very complicated medication and I'd hate to lose him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit: So, what I ended up saying was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Oh, [person]? Sometimes when you pee, there's a little bit left on the floor in front of the toilet. Could you wipe it up next time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should have told him it was hard for me to clean up, but I neglected to add that part because I was so nervous. He did not really seem surprised by my request, but was apologetic and said he would wipe it up in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2017-11-07T14:10:03.320" FavoriteCount="6" Id="6396" LastActivityDate="2018-12-06T19:16:55.403" LastEditDate="2018-12-06T19:16:55.403" LastEditorUserId="21067" OwnerUserId="8464" PostTypeId="1" Score="47" Tags="&lt;conversations&gt;&lt;conflict-aversion&gt;&lt;requests&gt;" Title="How to ask someone to not leave their pee on the floor when they use my bathroom?" ViewCount="10913"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I think Cronax is right that this may be a situation in which you have to be direct, but as this may be a problem that occurs when others are over as well, and you do have a medical issue that exacerbates the problem, you may consider putting a sign over the toilet reminding guests to tidy up after themselves:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Please ensure the area around the toilet is clean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this may be awkward under normal circumstances, I think your medical condition justifies going the extra mile. If you are comfortable doing so, you may even reference this on the sign:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It is difficult for me to clean the bathroom, so I appreciate the consideration!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2017-11-07T17:21:53.090" Id="6413" LastActivityDate="2017-11-07T17:21:53.090" OwnerUserId="5130" ParentId="6396" PostTypeId="2" Score="15"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="6464" AnswerCount="10" Body="&lt;p&gt;What to do with a friend who slightly improves his chances in the card or board games we play, by, for example, picking another card while we don't look or turning the dice?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The games are played for fun, no money involved,  but it kinda spoils the experience... we're still having fun, and we want this person to participate,  but if possible, with less cheating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to let them know we don't appreciate their sleight of hand?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2017-11-08T13:16:05.780" FavoriteCount="2" Id="6456" LastActivityDate="2019-08-23T13:14:38.920" LastEditDate="2017-11-08T13:34:27.763" LastEditorUserId="1599" OwnerDisplayName="user1617" PostTypeId="1" Score="89" Tags="&lt;conflict-aversion&gt;&lt;friend-groups&gt;" Title="What to do with a friend who cheats in games?" ViewCount="22711"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Some people are just serial game cheaters. My dad is one of them. He is smart and good at board games, but if he can get away with it he will cheat. If he is caught, he will feign innocence and put things back the way they were. What does &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; work for my dad:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calling him out - it solves the immediate cheat but doesn't stop future cheating&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clarity of the rules - he's a master of the rules and will use this to his advantage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Low expectations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Absence of extrinsic motivation - he gains nothing from cheating, sometimes it even spoils the atmosphere of the game playing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The suggestion of making it harder to cheat is a reasonable one, but that is impractical for some games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since your question was what to do with the friend and how to communicate with them, not how to stop the cheating, I am going to take a different approach with my answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the occasional attempt at cheating bothers you too  much, stop playing with them. However, it sounds like you do not want to do this. What works best with my dad is to call him out whenever you notice it, but otherwise not let it work you up that it may occur. In most games, in my experience, it is impossible for them to win by cheating every time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strategies about how to not let it work you up are a bit beyond the scope of the question, but what works best to me is to know who I'm playing with. If I'm playing with certain people, I don't expect to have a chance at winning--I just play to spend time with them. That applies not only to cheaters, but also when I'm playing with people who are well beyond my skill level at a certain game.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2017-11-08T14:31:44.757" Id="6461" LastActivityDate="2017-11-08T14:31:44.757" OwnerUserId="5130" ParentId="6456" PostTypeId="2" Score="9"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="12384" AnswerCount="12" Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Context&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a male in my early 20s. My work requires me to frequently communicate face-to-face with customers that are often strangers to me. Because of this I tend to take good care of my appearance. I neatly trim my beard, put product in my hair and work out a few times a week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I'm in a conversation with a customer I pay attention to looking them in the eyes to show I'm paying attention to the conversation we are having. But lately something else has caught my attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I'm the one talking I notice that the person I'm talking to switches between eye contact and looking at my mouth around every few seconds. While I'm not particularly an insecure person this can make me pretty unsure of whether (for example) I have something between my teeth or I'm distracting the person with the way I talk. While it doesn't particularly seems like it's distracting them, it does distract me from the topic of the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I stop people from looking at my mouth when I talk, or is this happening unconsciously?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extra&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'm sure there is actually nothing between my teeth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have had braces so I think I'm eligible to say my teeth are 'pretty'&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The conversations are always in my mother language (so no 'weird mouth movement')&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="9" CreationDate="2018-03-27T10:03:28.330" FavoriteCount="5" Id="12381" LastActivityDate="2018-03-30T15:29:18.323" LastEditDate="2018-03-27T14:31:40.563" LastEditorUserId="15681" OwnerUserId="15884" PostTypeId="1" Score="31" Tags="&lt;conversations&gt;" Title="How to stop people from looking at my mouth when we're having a conversation?" ViewCount="31228"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;My brother has Asperger's. One of the things that they teach people with Asperger's who have trouble with social norms is that most people's gaze bounces back and forth between the eyes and mouth during a conversation. People with Asperger's have trouble making eye contact and will sometimes overcompensate by forcing eye contact for the whole conversation--this is perceived as unusual by most, like the person is staring at them. In other words, the behavior you see when people are listening to you is perfectly normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There appear to be other behavioral factors that go into how long people tend to maintain eye contact, see Scientific American's &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/eye-contact-how-long-is-too-long/&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Eye Contact: How Long Is Too Long?&lt;/a&gt;. One that I have heard which is concomitant with my experience (though I have no idea if it is backed by study) is that people tend to maintain eye contact more when talking and less when listening.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2018-03-27T14:19:07.667" Id="12399" LastActivityDate="2018-03-27T14:19:07.667" OwnerUserId="5130" ParentId="12381" PostTypeId="2" Score="15"/>
</posts>