<?xml version="1.0" ?><posts>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="2727" AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;Who said this quote?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Patriotism is not a short frenzied burst of emotion, but the long and steady dedication of a lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've seen some sources claiming it was Thomas Jefferson and others claiming it was Adlai Stevenson.  It could be that Stevenson was quoting Jefferson, but I haven't found any credible-looking sources for this being a Jefferson quote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally, I'd like to know who said this, when they said it, and where.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2012-08-01T19:10:17.257" Id="2726" LastActivityDate="2013-08-29T17:43:01.577" OwnerUserId="845" PostTypeId="1" Score="15" Tags="&lt;united-states&gt;&lt;quotes&gt;" Title="Did Jefferson really say this quote about patriotism?" ViewCount="2265"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="10033" AnswerCount="4" Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://uk.answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20080601134907AAk4hjl&quot;&gt;An answer&lt;/a&gt; on this site claims that the first flags were heraldic flags used in battles. But when was this, and for which nations?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="7" CreationDate="2013-01-22T12:59:12.220" FavoriteCount="1" Id="7399" LastActivityDate="2019-02-15T07:08:04.777" LastEditDate="2013-08-25T04:21:33.720" LastEditorDisplayName="user2590" OwnerUserId="1427" PostTypeId="1" Score="17" Tags="&lt;ancient-history&gt;" Title="Who invented the first flag?" ViewCount="18010"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="10098" AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;Inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;https://history.stackexchange.com/questions/7299/when-did-people-start-caring-for-the-handicapped&quot;&gt;a previous question on the historical treatment of the disabled&lt;/a&gt;, I wonder if there are any written sources from Egyptian, Mesopotamian, Babylonian and civilizations from before 1400BCE about the following things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What sorts of people would the early civilizations consider &quot;handicapped&quot;, that is, distinguished from &quot;normal&quot; members of society due to what we would consider a disability today? (&lt;strong&gt;Based on contemporary textual sources, not archaeological inference.&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How were these people treated? (&lt;strong&gt;May use textual sources and archaeology.&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2013-08-26T14:55:46.007" FavoriteCount="1" Id="10023" LastActivityDate="2013-09-13T08:34:10.927" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:47:51.570" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="2732" PostTypeId="1" Score="6" Tags="&lt;ancient-history&gt;" Title="What do written sources say about disability in early civilisations?" ViewCount="863"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The Shahdad Standard is currently the oldest known flag in the world. The squared bronze flag from Shahdad, Iran dates back to about 2400 BC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It bears many of the hallmarks of a modern flag:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A pole (around which the flag could turn)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An eagle with open wings mounted on the top of the pole&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An emblem on the flag (depicting a rain goddess and an irrigation method practiced in Shahdad) to represent the group which bears the standard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The second source describes the emblem a little different:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;two figures facing one another on a rich background of animals, plants, and goddesses&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cais-soas.com/News/2007/May2007/14-05-iran.htm&quot;&gt;Iran's Most Ancient Standard Goes on Display in National Museum - The Circle of Ancient Iranian Studies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.archaeology.org/1111/features/dasht-e_lut_iran_shahr-i-sokta-shahad_tepe_yaha.html&quot;&gt;The World in Between - Archaeology Magazine Archive, Archaeological Institute of America&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="14" CreationDate="2013-08-27T19:16:22.603" Id="10033" LastActivityDate="2013-08-27T19:59:20.117" LastEditDate="2013-08-27T19:59:20.117" LastEditorUserId="2732" OwnerUserId="2732" ParentId="7399" PostTypeId="2" Score="26"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Those words were spoken by Adlai E. Stevenson in one of his campaign speeches for the 1952 U.S. presidential election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full quote is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What do we mean by patriotism in the context of our times? I venture to suggest that what we mean is a sense of national responsibility which will enable America to remain master of her power--to walk with it in serenity and wisdom, with self-respect and the respect of all mankind; a patriotism that puts country ahead of self; a patriotism which is not short, frenzied outbursts of emotion, but the tranquil and steady dedication of a lifetime. The dedication of a lifetime--these are words that are easy to utter, but this is a mighty assignment. For it is often easier to fight for principles than to live up to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adlai_Stevenson_II#1952_presidential_bid&quot;&gt;Adlai Stevenson II - Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;em&gt;just for background info on the election which is well attested&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://books.google.com/books?id=kHt3AAAAMAAJ&amp;amp;q=%22what%20do%20we%20mean%20by%20patriotism%20in%20the%20context%20of%20our%20times?%22&quot;&gt;Major campaign speeches of Adlai E. Stevenson, 1952, page 19 (part 1) - Google Books&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://books.google.com/books?id=kHt3AAAAMAAJ&amp;amp;q=%22patriotism%20which%20is%20not%20short,%20frenzied%20outbursts%20of%20emotion,%20but%20the%20tranquil%20and%20steady%20dedication%20of%20a%20lifetime%22&quot;&gt;Major campaign speeches of Adlai E. Stevenson, 1952, page 19 (part 2) - Google Books&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://books.google.com/books?id=kHt3AAAAMAAJ&amp;amp;q=%22which%20is%20not%20short,%20frenzied%20outbursts%20of%20emotion,%20but%20the%20tranquil%20and%20steady%20dedication%20of%20a%20lifetime%22&quot;&gt;Major campaign speeches of Adlai E. Stevenson, 1952, page 19 (part 3) - Google Books&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2013-08-29T17:43:01.577" Id="10048" LastActivityDate="2013-08-29T17:43:01.577" OwnerUserId="2732" ParentId="2726" PostTypeId="2" Score="11"/>
  <row AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;Did the United States (particularly in the 20th century) ever impose any trade embargoes on the basis of health related concerns? Are there instances where the U.S. said that if Country X doesn't meet particular health standards, it will limit trade with said country? &lt;/p&gt;
" ClosedDate="2013-09-10T23:39:17.113" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2013-09-03T00:41:38.143" Id="10079" LastActivityDate="2013-09-04T18:57:56.047" LastEditDate="2013-09-03T02:05:38.843" LastEditorDisplayName="user2590" OwnerUserId="2806" PostTypeId="1" Score="5" Tags="&lt;20th-century&gt;&lt;trade&gt;" Title="Did the United States ever impose any trade embargoes on the basis of health related concerns?" ViewCount="455"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="10091" AnswerCount="4" Body="&lt;p&gt;In &quot;The French Revolution, A History&quot; Chapter 1.1.II, Thomas Carlyle reports that Louis XIV once proclaimed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&quot;L'État, c'est moi&quot; - The State? I am the State (Carlyle's rendering into English)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carlyle cites no source for this seemingly incredible statement. In Wiki we find: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Louis_xiv#Quotes&quot;&gt;Louis is claimed to have said &quot;L'État, c'est moi&quot; (&quot;I am the state&quot;), though no proof exists that he said this, &lt;/a&gt; but I tend to be skeptical of Wiki's claim: Carlyle engaged in years of research in preparation for writing his History, and read numerous primary sources. It is unlikely that he committed to &quot;the record&quot; a statement from Louis XIV without a source. (But perhaps he did not consider his source sufficiently reliable to cite it formally - it was some sort of &quot;oral tradition&quot; - and so Wiki would be correct in claiming there is no &lt;strong&gt;written proof&lt;/strong&gt;.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless, the story was &quot;out there&quot; or Carlyle wouldn't have mentioned it at all. Perhaps there is another source, one that Carlyle didn't know about at the time? (In all probability, Carlye's source was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.woot.com/blog/post/the-debunker-did-louis-xiv-say-ltat-cest-moi&quot;&gt;Dulaure’s 1834 History of Paris, &lt;/a&gt; and because it appears only so much later in the record than the actual event, he chose not to cite it.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it confirmed from any reliable contemporary sources that Louis XIV actually said such a thing? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More importantly,&lt;/strong&gt; whether or not we have another source (perhaps we'll consider Carlyle a source), is such a statement sustainable? Could Louis have said such a thing and remained within the bounds of the laws of his time? Did the French King represent an embodiment of the State itself? Is it part of the doctrine of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Divine_right_of_kings&quot;&gt;Divine right of kings,&lt;/a&gt; or at least implicit therein? Could Louis perhaps have been speaking metaphorically - i.e.,  as an absolute monarch, his dictates of necessity represented the position of the State on all matters?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If  Louis XIV did indeed say such a thing, what can we make of it? From Carlyle's context it appears that it was not simply haughty bellicosity on the part of Louis XIV. Nor was Louis XIV some sort of eccentric, crazy &quot;one off&quot; sort of monarch: He sat on the French throne for over 72 years, brought France to perhaps its pinnacle of power, and is widely considered one of the great monarchs of History. If he said such a thing, IMO it deserves attention.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="9" CreationDate="2013-09-04T09:29:03.073" FavoriteCount="2" Id="10085" LastActivityDate="2017-09-01T19:10:24.557" LastEditDate="2014-05-14T01:19:19.100" LastEditorDisplayName="user2590" OwnerDisplayName="user2590" PostTypeId="1" Score="23" Tags="&lt;france&gt;&lt;monarchy&gt;&lt;quotes&gt;" Title="Did Louis XIV actually say &quot;The State? I am the State.&quot;? Could he have said it?" ViewCount="32072"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;If you'll take &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.woot.com/blog/post/the-debunker-did-louis-xiv-say-ltat-cest-moi&quot;&gt;Ken Jennings&lt;/a&gt; as a source (as he does seem to know his literature), he not only agrees that there is no evidence that Louis XIV said this, but goes a step further and says that Louis XIV probably wouldn't have said it. He claims not only that it wasn't true that the French monarch was equivalent to the state, but that Louis XIV probably didn't believe this to be true. From Jennings, a more reliably attested statement of Louis XIV (on his deathbed) is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Je m'en vais, mais l'État demeurera toujours”—“I am going away, but the State will always remain.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's what Jennings had to say about the actual authority of the French monarch:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Louis XIV and a small circle of advisors did wield enormous power, including supreme legislative and judicial authority. But that power was also balanced somewhat by the ranks of French nobility, and legally, the difference between the monarch and his nation was well-established. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
" CommentCount="11" CreationDate="2013-09-04T15:57:29.237" Id="10089" LastActivityDate="2013-09-04T15:57:29.237" OwnerUserId="2732" ParentId="10085" PostTypeId="2" Score="15"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes,&lt;/strong&gt; there is at least one example below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of June 21, 2011, the US had partial trade embargoes, issued by the CDC, on the import of birds from the following countries due to the H5N1 virus (bird flu):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;East Asia and the Pacific:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Myanmar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cambodia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hong Kong&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Indonesia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Japan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Laos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Malaysia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;South Korea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thailand&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vietnam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;South Asia:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Afghanistan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bangladesh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;India&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kazakhstan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nepal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pakistan &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Europe &amp;amp; Eurasia:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Albania&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Azerbaijan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Romania&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Russia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turkey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ukraine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Africa:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Benin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Burkina Faso &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cameroon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Djibouti&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Egypt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ghana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ivory Coast (Cote d’Ivoire)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Niger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nigeria&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;South Africa&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sudan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Togo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Near East:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Iran&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Iraq&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Israel &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jordan &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kuwait&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Palestinian Autonomous Territories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saudi Arabia &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These have since been rescinded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Princeton WordNet, a trade embargo is a government order restricting international trade. Wikipedia says that such embargoes can be partial embargoes, such as Princeton WordNet's &lt;a href=&quot;http://wordnetweb.princeton.edu/perl/webwn?o2=&amp;amp;o0=1&amp;amp;o8=1&amp;amp;o1=1&amp;amp;o7=&amp;amp;o5=&amp;amp;o9=&amp;amp;o6=&amp;amp;o3=&amp;amp;o4=&amp;amp;s=import+barrier&quot;&gt;import barrier&lt;/a&gt;. A country may choose what and how many items are excluded in a partial trade embargo. In the above case, the partial trade embargo restricts just the import of birds into the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cdc.gov/flu/avian/outbreaks/embargo.htm&quot;&gt;Embargo of Birds from Specified Southeast Asian Countries - CDC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://wordnetweb.princeton.edu/perl/webwn?s=trade%20embargo&quot;&gt;Trade embargo - Princeton WordNet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Embargo&quot;&gt;Embargo - Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2013-09-04T18:51:40.197" Id="10090" LastActivityDate="2013-09-04T18:57:56.047" LastEditDate="2013-09-04T18:57:56.047" LastEditorUserId="2732" OwnerUserId="2732" ParentId="10079" PostTypeId="2" Score="5"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Prof. Dr. Christian Laes and Dr. Dorien Meulenijzer have put together a web resource for scholarship on this very topic: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.disability-ancientworld.com/index.htm&quot;&gt;Disability History in the Ancient World.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They have a nice bibliography (albeit in .PDF) that can give you an overview on how various ancient cultures defined and dealt with disability, from both primary sources and from archaeology. While many of the articles listed are not online, your friendly neighborhood librarian will be able to help you run down any that catch your eye.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-09-06T12:03:11.113" Id="10098" LastActivityDate="2013-09-06T12:03:11.113" OwnerUserId="892" ParentId="10023" PostTypeId="2" Score="5"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I do not know about all the cultures but I would like to add a point how it was in ancient India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The first reference to disability is in ancient Vedic test 'Rig Veda'. There is a reference to Prosthesis for a queen named &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vishpala&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Vishpala&lt;/a&gt;. She loses her leg in a battle but gets Iron leg so that she could continue the battle. This incident dates earlier to Indus civilization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2013-09-13T08:34:10.927" Id="10164" LastActivityDate="2013-09-13T08:34:10.927" OwnerUserId="2813" ParentId="10023" PostTypeId="2" Score="1"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="12231" AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;I'm wondering what the &quot;symbolic etymology&quot;, so to speak, is for the Lamp in the story of Aladdin and its relation to the Genie. Why would a genie be bound to an object and be made a servant to its finder? Can one assume the genie did something bad once and was punished to subjugation to the lamp, or is it somehow in their nature? Also, why would it seem reasonable for the genie to be bound to a lamp, of all the things it could be bound to?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please don't misunderstand: I'm not asking what had happened in the mythological past that caused this particular genie to be bound to this particular lamp, but about what aspects of ancient Arabic culture might give rise to a myth about a genie bound to a lamp; or what the cultural connotations of an oil lamp might be, which would make the thought of someone or something (whichever category a genie would belong to) being bound to it emerge from the Arabic memeplex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I realize that History.SE isn't for mythological questions, but I thought that this question may be okay in that I'm not asking about things within the mythology, but for the historical cultural circumstances that gave rise to it. I'm reasoning that questions about ancient cultural symbols isn't very far removed from questions about ancient languages, which the FAQ explicitly lists as on-topic, or otherwise about historical cultural evolution. If my reasoning is wrong, feel free to close the question, I guess; in that case, perhaps I can at least serve to set a precedent.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="14" CreationDate="2014-03-26T09:22:50.917" FavoriteCount="3" Id="12222" LastActivityDate="2017-06-01T02:07:38.390" OwnerUserId="4055" PostTypeId="1" Score="8" Tags="&lt;cultural-history&gt;&lt;arabia&gt;" Title="What are the cultural roots of the Lamp of the Genie?" ViewCount="9071"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The basis for binding genies or &lt;em&gt;jinn&lt;/em&gt; to household objects comes from medieval Islamic lore surrounding King Solomon of Israel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;King Solomon used a magic ring to control djinn and protect him from them. The ring was set with a gem, probably a diamond, that had a living force of its own. With the ring, Solomon branded the necks of the djinn as his slaves.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;One story tells that a jealous djinn (sometimes identified as Asmodeus) stole the ring while Solomon bathed in the river Jordan. The djinn seated himself on Solomon's throne at his palace and reigned over his kingdom, forcing Solomon to become a wanderer. God compelled the djinn to throw the ring into the sea. Solomon retrieved it and punished the djinn by imprisoning him in a bottle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt; -- &lt;a href=&quot;http://books.google.com/books?id=NHosWhaeWDQC&amp;amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;amp;dq=Guiley,%20Rosemary.%20The%20Encyclopedia%20of%20Demons%20and%20Demonology&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ei=G_syU5TUPOm4yAGr3YDAAg&amp;amp;ved=0CCsQ6AEwAA#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=djinn&amp;amp;f=false&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Guiley, Rosemary. &lt;em&gt;The Encyclopedia of Demons and Demonology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea that sitting around somewhere on a forgotten shelf was an old, dusty bottle, containing a powerful magical being who was bound to serve human wishes, was an attractive catch for storytellers, as evidenced by the fact that this old legend has been respun several times in tales both ancient and modern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as the lamp itself is concerned, it was yet another household container that one might find anywhere. The connection between lamps and spirits was fairly common in Jewish culture (see &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Revelation+4%3A5&amp;amp;version=NIV&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Revelation 4:5&lt;/a&gt; for one example), so it is possible the signficance of this imagery played a factor in a lamp being chosen for the tale of Aladdin rather than a bottle or a jar.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="16" CreationDate="2014-03-26T16:06:00.353" Id="12231" LastActivityDate="2014-03-26T16:34:57.673" LastEditDate="2014-03-26T16:34:57.673" LastEditorUserId="2732" OwnerUserId="2732" ParentId="12222" PostTypeId="2" Score="10"/>
  <row AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;Recently acquired at an antique store without any information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/ETL4K.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;enter image description here&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full size photo is at my Flickr site: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/photolibrarian/13429182134/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;https://www.flickr.com/photos/photolibrarian/13429182134/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2014-03-26T16:34:16.733" Id="12233" LastActivityDate="2014-11-05T04:49:10.183" LastEditDate="2014-11-05T04:49:10.183" LastEditorUserId="4207" OwnerUserId="4198" PostTypeId="1" Score="7" Tags="&lt;identification&gt;" Title="U.S. biplane Identification" ViewCount="536"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;It appears to be a Douglas BT-2B. Here is an example for comparison:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-zEjMcBOL-hg/UOXWeBviF6I/AAAAAAAAT1k/ghPCKz4QUVE/s640/Douglas%20BT-2B.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Douglas BT-2B&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BT-2B was the first production model of the trainer version of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Douglas_O-2&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Douglas O-2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The specific plane in your picture is USAAC serial number 31-35. You can see the &quot;35&quot; printed on the tail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is what &lt;a href=&quot;http://cgibin.rcn.com/jeremy.k/cgi-bin/gzUsafSearch.pl?target=&amp;amp;content=Douglas%20B&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Joe Baugher's USAF Aircraft Serial Number list&lt;/a&gt; has to say about this plane:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;35 w/o at Bolling Field, DC Feb 28, 1934&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that the plane was written off (as unrepairable) at Bolling Field in Washington D.C. on February 28, 1934.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's possible, as pointed out in the comments, that the serial number is actually 31-85, as the tail number is a little blurry. That airframe was written off at Randolph Field, TX on 9/15/1932. &lt;a href=&quot;http://aviation-safety.net/wikibase/wiki.php?id=105653&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2014-03-26T21:51:47.363" Id="12236" LastActivityDate="2014-03-27T14:17:45.277" LastEditDate="2017-03-10T09:42:46.253" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="2732" ParentId="12233" PostTypeId="2" Score="10"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="26472" AnswerCount="7" Body="&lt;p&gt;Today, it takes gasoline or diesel fuel.  Prior to that and thanks to Mr. Fulton, there was steam.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to learn more about even earlier river transportation systems, focusing on the Ohio and Mississippi Rivers.  However, I would welcome information applicable to the Thames, the Yangtze, the Euphrates, or any major river, anywhere in time from antiquity to 1807. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an example, consider the crew of a  keelboat or a flatboat going from New Orleans to St. Louis (or Shanghai to Wuhan or Um Qasr to Baghdad or ...)  How would they have done this?  Did they sail for any part of it?  Were they able row upstream?  Or would they need to find a mule named Sal (a good ol' worker, a good ol' gal) and tow along the bank the whole way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The articles I have found don't tell me, with one at most saying &quot;the process of moving a keelboat upriver was extremely difficult&quot; with no amplifying details.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2015-11-19T19:24:39.777" Id="26454" LastActivityDate="2015-11-24T15:59:40.073" LastEditDate="2015-11-19T19:31:59.753" LastEditorUserId="15118" OwnerUserId="15118" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;transportation&gt;&lt;industrial-revolution&gt;" Title="River transportation before steam- did it always require beasts of burden?" ViewCount="4515"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Animal power was not limited to being tugged from the shore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were also &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Team_boat&amp;amp;oldid=683463441&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;team boats&lt;/a&gt;, which were generally horse engine powered. While they don't have much of a history in the US prior to steamboats (the earliest documented team boat was built in 1791), animal powered paddle boats have a long history going back to at least the 4th-5th century when the Romans used &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Paddle_steamer&amp;amp;oldid=690216166#History&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;an ox-powered paddle boat&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, of course, you have left out human-powered craft, which other users have pointed out. In addition to rowing, poles, and pulling, there have also been many instances of human-powered paddle boats, particularly among the Chinese.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2015-11-20T18:09:15.803" Id="26472" LastActivityDate="2015-11-20T18:09:15.803" OwnerUserId="2732" ParentId="26454" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="26523" AnswerCount="9" Body="&lt;p&gt;After the &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Norman_conquest_of_England&quot;&gt;Norman conquest of England&lt;/a&gt;&quot;, many things including languages, the ways of life, etc. have changed a lot in Europe. Especially it affected the English language significantly that a lot of French words were borrowed by English. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I would like to know how history describes the period when England was ruled by royal families of France. Also, if it was regarded as a colony, was there any independence war against the French rule in England? When did England became free of the political influence by France and by what event?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="18" CreationDate="2015-11-24T12:06:05.287" FavoriteCount="5" Id="26520" LastActivityDate="2018-07-10T18:12:35.107" LastEditDate="2015-11-24T12:49:38.003" LastEditorUserId="1401" OwnerUserId="15132" PostTypeId="1" Score="32" Tags="&lt;europe&gt;&lt;france&gt;&lt;england&gt;" Title="Was England considered a &quot;colony&quot; of France?" ViewCount="16643"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;At that time, the Duke of Normandy was more or less independent from France, his fealty to the king amounting to more of a mutually beneficial relationship than that of a strict subject. If anything, England could have been viewed as a colony of Normandy, but colony implies ownership by a state. In this case, it was instead that both Normandy and England were controlled by William, both distinct territories under his rulership.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2015-11-24T14:29:27.237" Id="26525" LastActivityDate="2015-11-24T14:29:27.237" OwnerUserId="2732" ParentId="26520" PostTypeId="2" Score="5"/>
  <row AnswerCount="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;Prior to the successful launch of Sputnik 1, there were &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=8dAIa-7YswsC&amp;amp;pg=PA15&amp;amp;dq=%22space+travel+is+impossible%22&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwjVztu2u_3LAhXHm4MKHZEiAbEQ6AEIHTAA#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=%22space%20travel%20is%20impossible%22&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;some&lt;/a&gt; who believed that space travel was impossible. I would like to know how widespread this notion was, particularly &quot;in scientific and engineering circles&quot; (as Goddard said) but also throughout academia and in the public (if record exists).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm primarily interested in three time periods: 1945 (when Goddard said the subject was still to be avoided) to 1957 (the launch of Sputnik 1), 1923 (when Oberth first proposed space travel with rockets) to 1945, and 1865 (the publication of &lt;em&gt;From the Earth to the Moon&lt;/em&gt;) to 1923.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before 1865, I'm pretty sure most people perceived space travel to be a fanciful notion, at best.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="6" CreationDate="2016-04-07T21:33:53.457" FavoriteCount="1" Id="28245" LastActivityDate="2017-02-21T13:22:22.543" OwnerDisplayName="called2voyage" OwnerUserId="2732" PostTypeId="1" Score="15" Tags="&lt;spaceflight&gt;" Title="How widespread was the notion that space travel was impossible prior to the successful launch of Sputnik 1?" ViewCount="1187"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I have serious trouble believing &lt;strong&gt;anyone&lt;/strong&gt; in the physics community actually believed rockets wouldn't work in a vacuum. The principle that allows them to operate there is &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spacecraft_propulsion#Reaction_engines&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Newton's Third Law&lt;/a&gt;, which by the 20th century had been around quite a while. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;True, random people off the street may have believed that, but random people off the street today often have trouble figuring out why jumping in an airplane &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/Why-can-I-jump-in-the-airplane-cabin-without-flying-to-the-back-of-the-plane&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;doesn't ram you against the back wall&lt;/a&gt;. So personally I don't think opinions of the subject-matter ignorant should count that much. The problem comes in when you rely on such people for your funding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do think you are slightly misreading the quotes in your linked article&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;, but you came by it honestly because you were meant to misunderstand in exactly that way. A cynic might argue this is journalists glossing over the minor fact they caused the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two parts here. First off:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Too often the word &quot;impossible&quot; is used by &lt;strong&gt;people who lack&lt;/strong&gt; the imagination or even &lt;strong&gt;the knowledge to understand what is being attempted.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IOW, we are talking my proverbial random people off the street here, not people who actually understand physics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there's this (quoting Goddard):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The subject of projection from the earth, and especially a mention of the moon, must still be avoided in dignified scientific and engineering circles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowhere does it say &quot;because those circles think its impossible&quot;. The article &lt;strong&gt;implies&lt;/strong&gt; that by placing those quotes in proximity (so bad on it), but I don't think that's what Goddard was saying. He was referring to public perception making it tough to get things like funding and publication. He had trouble getting taken seriously because the general public associated his rockets with cheap Sci-Fi. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the early and mid 20th century Science Fiction was largely cheap schlocky paperbacks, and had only slightly more cachet than Romance novels. It was looked down upon by pretty much anyone &quot;serious&quot;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gooddard mentioned the moon in an aside in a large report on his rocketry research. Some ignoramus (obviously not an actual physicist) wrote an anonomous &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_H._Goddard#New_York_Times_editorial&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Op-Ed to the New York Times&lt;/a&gt;, ridiculing the entire research based on this tiny bit, with indeed the claim that somehow Newton's Third Law doesn't work in a vacuum.&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;After the rocket quits our air and really starts on its longer
  journey, its flight would be neither accelerated nor maintained by the
  explosion of the charges it then might have left. To claim that it
  would be is to deny a fundamental law of dynamics, and only Dr.
  Einstein and his chosen dozen, so few and fit, are licensed to do
  that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article had no small effect on history, as the public ridicule caused others in the USA to avoid Goddard and his rocketry research. For what its worth (almost nothing), the Times did eventually publish a retraction ... in 1969.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Further investigation and experimentation have confirmed the &lt;em&gt;findings
  of Isaac Newton in the 17th Century&lt;/em&gt; and it is now definitely
  established that a rocket can function in a vacuum as well as in an
  atmosphere. The Times regrets the error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(emphasis mine)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1 - On the first page of your link. I actually couldn't find any mention of space travel on the other articles under it, but that could be my old eyes.&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2 - I can remember in the mid 80's being specifically told by an English prof I could read and write a report on any book I wanted, but it shouldn't be Romance or Sci-Fi because those weren't &quot;serious literature&quot;. I got ticked off and wrote a 20 page mini-dissertation on the themes in Dune&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3 - Notice this also including a reference to the Urban Legend that almost nobody can understand Relativity. As an indirect result of this letter, it was the Nazis who ended up picking up his research and making the real advancements in this field. Really I can't say anything bad enough about the anonymous coward who penned this.&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2016-04-08T03:37:56.790" Id="28247" LastActivityDate="2016-04-08T04:15:14.817" LastEditDate="2016-04-08T04:15:14.817" LastEditorUserId="771" OwnerUserId="771" ParentId="28245" PostTypeId="2" Score="9"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;According to books like &lt;em&gt;Profiles of the Future&lt;/em&gt; by Arthur C. Clark and &lt;em&gt;Rockets, Missiles and Space Travel&lt;/em&gt; by Wily Ley, many scientists and engineers misunderstood the physics enough to claim that space travel was impossible or impractical in reaction to discussions of the theories of Goddard, Oberth, and other space travel pioneers in the early 20th century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, Clarke mentioned an article denying the practicality of space travel by a Richard V. D. W. Wooley.  Wooley later became Astronomer Royal in the UK in 1956 and told reporters that space travel was &quot;utter bilge&quot;.  After the first Sputnik the next year a famous cartoon showed him being shown around a space center and being told &quot;...and then, Dr. Wooley, the satellite will penetrate utter bilge.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, a newspaper-like publication distributed to American schoolchildren during the International Geophysical Year mentioned that the USA and the USSR planned to launch satellites during it, so the launch of Sputnik should not have been too surprising to kids who read it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In the early and mid 20th century Science Fiction was largely cheap schlocky paperbacks, and had only slightly more cachet than Romance novels. It was looked down upon by pretty much anyone serious2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of serious persons, such as scientists and engineers, wrote science fiction stories themselves in the early and mid 20th century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the early and mid 20th century science fiction was mostly &lt;em&gt;Buck Rogers&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Flash Gordon&lt;/em&gt; type comic strips, stories and novels published in the mainstream &quot;slick&quot; magazines, occasional more or less mainstream science fiction hardback novels, and stories and novels published in the science fiction genre &quot;pulp&quot; magazines.  Mass market genre science fiction paperback novels, story collections, and anthologies did not begin to be published until after World War II -- the earliest in my collection have book copyright dates in the 1950s and so could be considered to be from the later mid 20th century.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="5" CreationDate="2016-04-08T04:40:50.030" Id="28250" LastActivityDate="2016-04-08T04:40:50.030" OwnerUserId="12641" ParentId="28245" PostTypeId="2" Score="12"/>
  <row AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;According to the Wikipedia article on the Abacus, Ettore Carruccio stated in &lt;em&gt;Mathematics and Logic In History and In Contemporary Thought&lt;/em&gt; that the Old Babylonians:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;may have used the abacus for the operations of addition and subtraction; however, this primitive device proved difficult to use for more complex calculations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;translated by Isabel Quigly&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Old Babylonians, however, performed more complex mathematics than basic arithmetic. In the well referenced Wikipedia article on Babylonian mathematics it is stated that there is evidence they solved equations algebraically. Analysis of the Plimpton 322 tablet even seems to indicate they calculated a list of Pythagorean triples &quot;too many and too large to have been obtained by brute force&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What methods then did the Old Babylonians use for solving equations? Were other devices aside from the abacus employed, or were these mostly manual methods on tablets? How did their manual methods differ from those we use today?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not sure how much information we have on their mathematics. If there is a lot available, then this may be a little broad--in that case a summary of the state of research with links to good starting places to read about the research would make a useful answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Referenced Wikipedia articles:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abacus&quot;&gt;Abacus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Babylonian_mathematics&quot;&gt;Babylonian mathematics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt; I have discovered papers such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://rudar.ruc.dk/handle/1800/24432&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;, but I am unable to ascertain whether the paper is reputable (I'm unfamiliar with the scholars in this field) or whether it contains much in the way of an answer to my question. It would be nice to know that before purchasing access to a paper at random. In this case, the paper seems to be freely accessible and at a glance appears scholarly, yet I still cannot verify if it represents the current state of research.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="13" CreationDate="2016-05-12T18:16:42.493" Id="28752" LastActivityDate="2016-06-19T11:40:19.930" OwnerUserId="2732" PostTypeId="1" Score="5" Tags="&lt;mathematics&gt;&lt;ancient-babylon&gt;" Title="What methods did the Old Babylonian society use for solving equations?" ViewCount="270"/>
  <row AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;Usually when I'm trying to find something about the Celts along the Danube and North Italy, I have a hard time. What is their group term (like Gauls, Britons, Celtiberians)? Do they belong to Gaul? Are they simply referred to as &quot;East Celtic&quot;? Or is there no group term?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm looking for a term that was either used by ancient sources or modern historians.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2016-06-09T13:14:32.823" Id="30284" LastActivityDate="2016-06-09T14:27:19.633" OwnerUserId="18951" PostTypeId="1" Score="1" Tags="&lt;celts&gt;&lt;alps&gt;" Title="Group term for the Celts around the Alps?" ViewCount="333"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The catch-all term is &quot;the Alpine Celts&quot;. This is divided into two major groups: the Cisalpine Celts and the Transalpine Celts (which also includes the Celts in what are today France and Belgium). The Cisalpine Celts are those that are on the Italian side of the Alps, including the Lepontic and the Cisalpine Gauls. The Transalpine Celts are those on the other side of the Alps from Italy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Transalpine Celts are predominantly Gauls (Transalpine Gauls). The major tribe in the Swiss plateau at the time of contact with the Roman Republic was the Helvetii tribe.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="8" CreationDate="2016-06-09T14:26:54.320" Id="30285" LastActivityDate="2016-06-09T14:26:54.320" OwnerUserId="2732" ParentId="30284" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;You can see some general survey, like: Victor Katz, &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.it/books?id=h50fAQAAIAAJ&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;A History of Mathematics: An Introduction&lt;/a&gt; (3rd edition, 2008), &lt;strong&gt;Ch.1.2 MESOPOTAMIA&lt;/strong&gt;, page 10-on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are references to &quot;modern classics&quot;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Otto Neugebauer, &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.it/books?id=JVhTtVA2zr8C&amp;amp;pg=PA29&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The Exact Sciences in Antiquity&lt;/a&gt; (2nd ed, 1957), &lt;strong&gt;Ch.2 Babylonian mathematics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;B.L. Van der Waerden, &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.it/books?id=HK3vCAAAQBAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA62&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Science Awakening I&lt;/a&gt; (or.ed, 1954), &lt;strong&gt;Ch.3 Babylonian mathematics&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More recent and &quot;technical&quot;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jens Høyrup, &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.it/books?id=GavTBwAAQBAJ&amp;amp;pg=PP4&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Lengths, Widths, Surfaces: A Portrait of Old Babylonian Algebra and Its Kin&lt;/a&gt; (2002), &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eleanor Robson, &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.it/books?id=5gdVQRDYjYsC&amp;amp;printsec=frontcover&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Mesopotamian Mathematics, 2100–1600 BC: Technical Constants in Bureaucracy and Education&lt;/a&gt; (1999). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2016-06-19T11:40:19.930" Id="30450" LastActivityDate="2016-06-19T11:40:19.930" OwnerUserId="14911" ParentId="28752" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="32269" AnswerCount="6" Body="&lt;p&gt;Recently, I've been searching a lot about Scotland, Ireland, Wales, and England. One after the other, England vassalized its neighbors and became the head of Great Britain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can understand that Wales, which was really decentralized, couldn't really stop the English. But for Scotland and Ireland, how was it done?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In history lessons, we learn that Ireland was effectively separated into many fiefdoms (4 before the British invasion) but supposedly united against invaders. Thus, how could they lose their lands so easily? Was their army too old? Was there no will to keep their lands?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Scotland, they indeed often fought against England and often allied with France for protection. They were nonetheless crushed by the English. Why is that? Was their economy too bad to sustain their army? Supplies trouble?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="16" CreationDate="2016-08-10T13:27:15.813" FavoriteCount="7" Id="32268" LastActivityDate="2019-04-10T20:58:23.110" LastEditDate="2016-08-10T16:29:40.440" LastEditorUserId="4027" OwnerUserId="17544" PostTypeId="1" Score="24" Tags="&lt;england&gt;&lt;united-kingdom&gt;&lt;ireland&gt;&lt;scotland&gt;&lt;great-britain&gt;" Title="What made the English the dominant power of the British Isles?" ViewCount="6513"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;To answer this question, you first have to answer another complex question: Who are the English?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This question turns out to be quite complex indeed because to this day scholars are unsure whether to subscribe to an invasionist/migrationist view or a diffusionist view in regards to the Britons, the Celtic people of Great Britain (excluding Scotland) which are one of the early peoples which preceded the English. To give a rough explanation, the former would mean that the Briton culture came to Great Britain from the continent with its people, whereas the latter would mean that contact with the continent transformed the existing people on the island into the Briton culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, who were these people that were already in Great Britain? Modern humans first reached Britain around 42,000 years ago, but during the last glacial maximum between 25,000 and 15,000 years ago, the island is generally believed to have been unoccupied again. People may have begun occupying the island immediately after the last glacial maximum, but by 9600 BC there was certainly an established population. To give these people some context, some Mesolithic postholes were dug in the Stonehenge area around 8000 BC, so ritual activity had certainly begun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years prior to the Britons, the cultural changes are generally believed to have happened within a more or less consistent population. For example, 4000 BC brought the Neolithic culture, and the Bronze Age culture arrived about 2300 BC. By 800 BC, the Briton Iron Age had begun in Britain, and this population expanded to about three or four million by the first century BC, mostly concentrated in the south.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update 4/23/2018:&lt;/strong&gt; It looks like the Neolithic culture that built Stonehenge may have been replaced by a Bronze Age invasion, after all. See &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/news/ancient-genome-study-finds-bronze-age-beaker-culture-invaded-britain-1.21996&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Ancient-genome study finds Bronze Age ‘Beaker culture’ invaded Britain - Ewen Callaway in &lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One possible argument for the diffusionist theory is that the Briton druids are understood to have made use of Stonehenge, which was built prior to the Britons. It is certainly possible that invaders made use of the existing religious monument, but it is perhaps somewhat more likely that there existed at least a strain of continuity between the Stone Age, Bronze Age, and  Iron Age peoples of the island.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the Iron Age Britons may have been the first to call themselves British, or &lt;em&gt;Pretanoi&lt;/em&gt;. The Greek Pytheas &quot;discovered&quot; Britain in c. 325 BC. This event marked the beginning of the expansion of the Greco-Roman world northward in Europe. Between 200 BC and AD 43, the Germanic-Celtic refugees from Gaul began migrating to Britain, as the Romans expanded into Gaul. The southern tribes started to become more Romanized, and it is this influence of Germanic and Roman culture which began the transition of the Britons into the English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By AD 40, the Roman Empire had conquered southern Britain, and the period known as Roman Britain began. It is the Romano-British culture which gave rise to the early legends which would later be transformed into the Arthur myth. After the Romans withdrew from Britain in about AD 410, the Germanic Anglo-Saxons began their series of invasions of the island. As Wikipedia puts it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Traditionally, it was believed that a mass invasion by various Anglo-Saxon tribes largely displaced the indigenous British population in southern and eastern Great Britain (modern-day England with the exception of Cornwall).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, recent genetic studies show that there was not really a mass displacement at all. Rather, the relatively small groups of Anglo-Saxon invaders had a large cultural impact on the existing British population. The most notable theory to explain why the Anglo-Saxon culture had such a profound effect on the indigenous people is that the political and economic dominance of the Anglo-Saxons made their culture more desirable. Of course, what exactly gave the Anglo-Saxons an advantage is more complex, and I'll leave that up to the reader to pursue further (more information is available in the linked Wikipedia articles).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By 1066, when William the Conqueror took the English throne, the English culture was already well established, and William's advancements--such as new castles and a census--served only to strengthen the fledgling nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer to your question, then, is that the English are likely dominant because they are probably composed of the steadily growing population sprung from the more or less original inhabitants of the island. Wales and Scotland, then, are the exceptions, and they deserve further scrutiny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the Welsh tribes made peace with the Romans, and thus were able to maintain some of their identity through the Roman period. The Anglo-Saxons were not able to penetrate all the way into Wales, possibly because the Romans had not built as much infrastructure there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Romans were never able to invade much of Scotland, possibly because it was hard to fight the tribes in the Highlands. Eventually the Romans gave up their land in southern Scotland, and the territory was dominated by native tribes, such as the Picts in the north. After the Romans withdrew from Britain, the Gaels from Ireland invaded Scotland in the west, and the Picts withdrew to the east. Eventually, gaelicization (the influence of the Gaels), transformed Scotland, and the Gaelic and Pictish crowns merged. The strength of this new kingdom is what kept Scotland independent from the English in the south, and that is another topic that deserves further study by the reader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wikipedia References:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/History_of_the_British_Isles&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;History of the British Isles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_people&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;English people&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anglo-Saxon_settlement_of_Britain&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Anglo-Saxon settlement of Britain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/History_of_Wales&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;History of Wales&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/History_of_Scotland&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;History of Scotland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2016-08-10T15:06:31.717" Id="32269" LastActivityDate="2018-04-23T15:23:16.927" LastEditDate="2018-04-23T15:23:16.927" LastEditorUserId="2732" OwnerUserId="2732" ParentId="32268" PostTypeId="2" Score="27"/>
  <row AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;Someone commented to me that there is an ancient text talking about how everything has been said before. There are of course more recents thoughts along this line, but to me it was very impressive to think that this was said thousands of years ago, so I would be very thankful if someone knew about old quotes like that&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="11" CreationDate="2016-09-06T14:24:19.300" Id="32661" LastActivityDate="2019-01-07T19:24:18.667" OwnerUserId="21252" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;ancient-history&gt;&lt;philosophy&gt;" Title="Which ancient text claims that everything has been said before?" ViewCount="1146"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;After some searching, I cannot find an older succinct expression of the concept than that in the book Ecclesiastes from the Hebrew &lt;em&gt;Tanakh&lt;/em&gt;, which has become the Old Testament of the Christian Bible. Ecclesiastes (&lt;em&gt;Koheleth&lt;/em&gt; in Hebrew) is a piece of wisdom literature on the topic of futility, which dates to somewhere between 450-180 BCE. In Ecclesiastes 1:9 it is expressed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What has been will be again,
      what has been done will be done again;
      there is nothing new under the sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;(NIV)&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This concept is repeated throughout the book to reinforce the theme of the futility of human effort. The philosophy is not original. As has been pointed out in the comments, it bears resemblance to the notion of eternal return: the idea that in an infinite universe there must be a cycle of time in which the same events repeat over and over. This idea has been discussed in ancient cultures around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book of Ecclesiastes does not go as far as declaring a concept of eternal return, which would have gone directly against the traditional Jewish belief in a linear timeline with a defined beginning and end. Perhaps the idea is expressed so succinctly because it was a somewhat novel idea in Jewish culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The phrase has taken on a life of its own, and is often &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/there_is_nothing_new_under_the_sun&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;quoted&lt;/a&gt;. It is so common that it has been used as the title of &lt;a href=&quot;https://scholar.google.com/scholar?hl=en&amp;amp;q=nothing+new+under+the+sun&amp;amp;btnG=&amp;amp;as_sdt=1%2C44&amp;amp;as_sdtp=&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;numerous papers&lt;/a&gt; across various disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is, however, an iteration of this idea that more closely matches the wording of the question, from about the same depth of time. The Roman playwright Terence, in his 2nd century BC comedy &lt;em&gt;Eunuchus&lt;/em&gt;, wrote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[The author]...doesn't deny that in his Eunuch he has transported characters out of the Greek: but ... if the same characters will not be permitted, how is it more permissible to depict a servant on the run, or to make use of good old women, evil courtesans, a gluttonous parasite, a braggart soldier, a changeling, an old man duped by a servant, or even love, hate, and suspicion? &lt;strong&gt;In short, nothing is said that has not been said before.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;emphasis added&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Further reference:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ecclesiastes&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Ecclesiastes - Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eternal_return&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Eternal return - Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eunuchus&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Eunuchus - Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2016-09-07T13:44:42.460" Id="32670" LastActivityDate="2019-01-07T19:24:18.667" LastEditDate="2019-01-07T19:24:18.667" LastEditorUserId="2732" OwnerUserId="2732" ParentId="32661" PostTypeId="2" Score="6"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="34190" AnswerCount="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;The earliest example I have is Jose Antonio Bolcof of Russia, who became a Mexican about 1833. Who beat him?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cf. &lt;a href=&quot;https://history.stackexchange.com/questions/34078/who-was-the-first-foreigner-to-be-naturalized-as-a-mexican-citizen&quot;&gt;Who was the first foreigner to be naturalized as a Mexican citizen?&lt;/a&gt;: several Texans got in before Bolcof.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2016-11-29T18:31:28.607" Id="34097" LastActivityDate="2016-12-06T16:53:08.087" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:47:51.570" LastEditorUserId="-1" OwnerUserId="18968" PostTypeId="1" Score="5" Tags="&lt;immigration&gt;&lt;mexico&gt;&lt;california&gt;&lt;law&gt;&lt;identity-documents&gt;" Title="Who was the first foreigner to be naturalized as a Mexican citizen in Alta California?" ViewCount="196"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abel_Stearns&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Abel Stearns&lt;/a&gt; emigrated to Mexico in 1826 and naturalized in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jstor.org/stable/41167726?seq=1#page_scan_tab_contents&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;1828&lt;/a&gt;. In 1829 he moved out to Monterey, California, and he eventually settled in Pueblo de los Ángeles, which would become the Los Angeles that we know today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://wc.rootsweb.ancestry.com/cgi-bin/igm.cgi?op=GET&amp;amp;db=thedash1&amp;amp;id=I18537&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;RootsWeb biography&lt;/a&gt; says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;One year after his marriage, he purchased the 28,000-acre Rancho Los Alamitos, near present day Long Beach and Seal Beach, to use as a summer home. As a trader who settled in Los Angeles, Stearns had become one of the area's wealthiest citizens and the largest landowner in Southern California.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/c88k7c93/entire_text/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Online Archive of California&lt;/a&gt; says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Stearns was in Mexico City 1826-1829&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2016-12-02T14:16:25.767" Id="34129" LastActivityDate="2016-12-06T16:53:08.087" LastEditDate="2016-12-06T16:53:08.087" LastEditorUserId="2732" OwnerUserId="2732" ParentId="34097" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="34917" AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;I am currently reading John Williams' &quot;Augustus&quot;, or, to be precise, the German translation. I know the book is mostly fiction but there is one thing I'd like to know. The book dwells on Augustus' disease in 23BC, which was so serious that everyone believed he would die (see &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Augustus#Death_and_succession&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;). Then, the book says that his nephew &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marcus_Claudius_Marcellus_(Julio-Claudian_dynasty)&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Marcus Claudius Marcellus&lt;/a&gt; died soon after Augustus' unexpected recovery &quot;of the same fever&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know from the above article on Wikipedia that the cause of Marcellus' sudden death at the age of 19 is unknown. But is Augustus' disease known? What did he suffer from?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="5" CreationDate="2017-01-03T09:59:18.107" Id="34697" LastActivityDate="2018-06-06T15:28:15.033" LastEditDate="2017-01-03T15:00:54.630" LastEditorUserId="771" OwnerUserId="23027" PostTypeId="1" Score="10" Tags="&lt;rome&gt;" Title="What disease did Augustus recover from in 23 BC?" ViewCount="1901"/>
  <row AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;The Cat of Bubastes&lt;/em&gt;, Victorian era author G. A. Henty asserts that all of the gods of the Egyptian Pantheon originally described individual attributes of a single god.  Over time, common people came to worship these symbols as gods in their own right, but the high priesthood always maintained a belief in a single god who had all of the attributes represented by the various other &quot;gods&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realize that this book is historical fiction, but all of his other books (he was rather a prolific author) have been praised as well researched and historically accurate.  According to his contemporary (and modern) critics, his descriptions of major events, cultural practices, behaviors, and beliefs are considered accurate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there some basis for the belief that the high priesthood, at least, was monotheistic?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2017-01-10T19:52:49.230" Id="34867" LastActivityDate="2017-01-10T22:22:58.033" OwnerUserId="23156" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;religion&gt;&lt;ancient-egypt&gt;" Title="Were ancient Egyptians secretly monotheistic?" ViewCount="598"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordandsilence.com/2012/10/06/conceptions-of-god-in-ancient-egypt-the-one-and-the-many-by-erik-hornung-favorite-passages/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conceptions of God in Ancient Egypt: The One and the Many&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;* by Erik Hornung, this is a foreign idea that has been projected upon the ancient Egyptians, due to their frequent blending of gods:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[pp. 97-99, on the Egyptian ability to combine the names of deities, combine their attributes, and on mistaken notions that Egyptian religion originated with, or seemed to tend towards, monotheism:] Is the purpose of these combinations a clever priestly “equalization” of conflicting religious claims, as Bonnet, like his predecessors, assumed? Must gods be “equated” with one another until one finishes with a vague, solar-tinged pantheism? Such an interchange of attributes, which leads towards uniformity, is un-Egyptian; if anything it is Hellenistic. The Egyptians place the tensions and contradictions in the world beside one another and then live with them. Amon-Re is not the synthesis of Amun and Re but a new form that exists along with the older gods….&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It is clear that syncretism does not contain any “monotheistic tendency,” but rather forms a strong counter-current to monotheism–so long as it is kept within bounds. Syncretism softens henotheism, the concentration of worship on a single god, and stops it from turning into monotheism, for ultimately syncretism means that a single god is not isolated from the others: in Amun one apprehends and worships also Re, or in Harmachis other forms of the sun god. In this way the awareness is sharpened that the divine partner of humanity is not one but many….&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We shall find repeatedly that Egyptian deities do not present themselves to us with as clear and well defined a nature as that of the gods of Greece. The conception of god which we encounter here is fluid, unfinished, changeable. But we should not impute to the Egyptians confused conceptions of their gods… It is evidently unnatural for Egyptian gods to be strictly defined. Their being remains a fluid state to which we are not accustomed; it escapes every dogmatic, final definition and can always be extended or further differentiated. The combinations gods form with other gods are transitory in many respects and can be dissolved at any time. This fluidity leaves no room for monotheism, which bases itself on unambiguous definitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;* The link is to a blog which quotes the book. The above quote comes from that blog: &lt;em&gt;word and silence&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2017-01-10T22:22:58.033" Id="34869" LastActivityDate="2017-01-10T22:22:58.033" OwnerUserId="2732" ParentId="34867" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=HsrGEFpW80UC&amp;amp;pg=PA47&amp;amp;lpg=PA47&amp;amp;dq=augustus+influenza+23+bc&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=lZhst_nOrA&amp;amp;sig=l5H_ZUomasFnP5LTESYB_tC9h4g&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwiSu6LRpabRAhVHyFQKHY3UC3EQ6AEIOjAF#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=augustus%20influenza%2023%20bc&amp;amp;f=false&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Dictionary of the Roman Empire&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Matthew Bunson, in the section on Augustus, we learn that he suffered from health problems his whole life. While it does not mention specifically what he suffered from in 23 B.C., it is possible that it was a strain of influenza, which he might have been more susceptible too, being so sickly. He had previously suffered from influenza before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;His teeth were decayed, and his messily tended hair was yellow. Although he was only five feet, seven inches tall (perhaps less), he was elegantly proportioned. His health was always a concern. There was a weakness in his left hip and right forefinger, and ringworm was probably present. More importantly, Augustus fought terrible bouts of illness: abscessed liver, influenza and seasonal complaints. The worst came in 23 B.C., when it was generally believed that he would die. His private physician, Antonius Musa, managed to heal him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2017-01-12T14:54:09.940" Id="34917" LastActivityDate="2017-01-12T14:54:09.940" OwnerUserId="2732" ParentId="34697" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Clarke later apologized for misquoting Wooley on the subject of spaceflight. The passage in question came from a radio interview, so there isn't a solid paper trail, but there's no doubt that summing up Wooley's position as &quot;spaceflight is utter bilge&quot; is totally unfair. Wooley was talking about the popular idea that interplanetary flight would soon be widespread, and said (according to a 1995 letter to the New Scientist): &quot;All this talk about space travel is utter bilge, really. It would cost as much as a major war just to put a man on the moon.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clarke acknowledged that Wooley was right on the money if you substitute &quot;minor war&quot; for &quot;major war.&quot; In any case, he was far more correct than Clarke at the time, who thought that going to the Moon could be accomplished for a few million dollars.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2017-02-21T13:22:22.543" Id="35627" LastActivityDate="2017-02-21T13:22:22.543" OwnerUserId="23750" ParentId="28245" PostTypeId="2" Score="6"/>
  <row AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;There is news claiming that the Irish folk gods, the &lt;em&gt;Tuatha De Danann&lt;/em&gt;, were really Indian, and that their followers have similar practices to ancient Indians. Is that why the Celtic people are called the 'Bhramins of the West'?&lt;/p&gt;
" ClosedDate="2017-06-21T09:33:57.473" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2017-06-20T16:04:04.193" Id="38630" LastActivityDate="2017-06-20T18:32:18.067" LastEditDate="2017-06-20T18:20:32.183" LastEditorUserId="2732" OwnerUserId="25519" PostTypeId="1" Score="-2" Tags="&lt;ancient-history&gt;&lt;india&gt;&lt;celts&gt;" Title="Were the Tuatha De Danann really from India?" ViewCount="340"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The Irish (Gaelic) culture and Vedic culture are generally understood to have a common origin in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Proto-Indo-Europeans&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Proto-Indo-European culture&lt;/a&gt;. Gaelic and Sanskrit are both Indo-European languages. Some linguists have reconstructed &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Proto-Indo-European_religion&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Proto-Indo-European deities&lt;/a&gt;, from which some of the Irish and Hindu deities are believed to be derived, with varying levels of confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among these are &lt;em&gt;*Dehnu-&lt;/em&gt; (proposed origin of Vedic goddess Dānu and Irish goddess Danu) and &lt;em&gt;*Neptonos&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;*Hepom Nepōts&lt;/em&gt; (proposed origin of Vedic god Apám Nápát and Irish god Nechtain).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also similarities between the practices and beliefs of the Gaelic druids and the Hindu Brahmins, that may share a common origin as well. However, these are not understood to have come from India. The Proto-Indo-Europeans are generally understood to have come from an eastern European or central Asian location, their descendants having migrated to both the British Isles and the Indian subcontinent, among other locations.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2017-06-20T18:32:18.067" Id="38634" LastActivityDate="2017-06-20T18:32:18.067" OwnerUserId="2732" ParentId="38630" PostTypeId="2" Score="4"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="45489" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;Several years ago, I purchased a copy of A.W. Wheen's English translation of Erich Maria Remarque's &lt;em&gt;Three Comrades&lt;/em&gt; (published, as best as I can tell, sometime in 1937 by Hutchinson &amp;amp; Co. of London, England) at a second-hand bookstore in Canada (rather oddly, not in Toronto, but in Guelph). On the first (blank page), there are two things, one of which is of interest in the context of this question: a partially-torn sticker, seemingly applied by the bookseller, as seen below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/4XpPk.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bookplate&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I'm &lt;em&gt;assuming&lt;/em&gt; this indicates London, England, but it could just as easily be London, Ontario given where this particular copy has clearly spent the better part of its history. So, the real question is this: does anyone know anything about Smallman &amp;amp; &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;blank&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, Limited, proprietors of an unknown business in London?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonus points (i.e. a small bounty) will be awarded if you can tell me anything about the Keuroglouians of Toronto, in whose memory this book was donated.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2018-04-02T20:17:32.683" Id="45461" LastActivityDate="2019-09-19T20:43:03.317" LastEditDate="2018-04-02T20:28:22.743" LastEditorUserId="28122" OwnerUserId="28122" PostTypeId="1" Score="6" Tags="&lt;identification&gt;&lt;book&gt;&lt;canada&gt;&lt;london&gt;" Title="Who sold this book in London in the 1930s?" ViewCount="412"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="45472" AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;I'm working on a history of data visualization in which some works from the
1900 “Exhibit of American Negroes” at the Paris World Fair (the Exposition Universelle Internationale) are featured. A nice quote, attributed to him was
found at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brainyquote.com/quotes/w_e_b_du_bois_120759&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;https://www.brainyquote.com/quotes/w_e_b_du_bois_120759&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When you have mastered numbers, you will in fact no longer be reading
  numbers,  any more than you read words when reading books. You will be
  reading meaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a great quote for the purpose, but was challenged by an editor. Any hints for tracking down the source of this quote would be appreciated. &lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2018-04-03T15:57:59.537" FavoriteCount="4" Id="45470" LastActivityDate="2018-04-03T16:56:07.907" OwnerUserId="31127" PostTypeId="1" Score="36" Tags="&lt;historiography&gt;&lt;quotes&gt;" Title="Source of quote attributed to W.E.B. Du Bois: &quot;When you have mastered numbers...&quot;" ViewCount="6615"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The quote is by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harold_Geneen&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Harold Geneen&lt;/a&gt; from his 1984 book &lt;em&gt;Managing&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first found evidence of this from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Harold_Geneen&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Wikiquote&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When you have mastered the numbers, you will in fact no longer be reading numbers, any more than you read words when reading a book. You will be reading meanings.
  &lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Managing, Chapter Nine (The Numbers), p. 151.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To verify, I did a &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=61jFfehbLpUC&amp;amp;focus=searchwithinvolume&amp;amp;q=mastered&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Google Books search&lt;/a&gt;. It does appear to be original text and not a quote within that work.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2018-04-03T16:36:11.180" Id="45471" LastActivityDate="2018-04-03T16:36:11.180" OwnerUserId="2732" ParentId="45470" PostTypeId="2" Score="57"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The position of &quot;Limited&quot; in relation to &quot;Smallman &amp;amp;&quot; does resemble the &quot;Smallman and Ingram&quot; logo, for example on their &lt;a href=&quot;http://kickshawproductions.com/blog/?p=12927&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;catalog&lt;/a&gt;. While John Smallman and Lemuel Ingram started their retail store with a specialty in clothing, they quickly expanded to carry other dry goods, as both had experience working in the market. The business was based out of London, Ontario. The original location was at 147 Dundas Street in 1877. Smallman created Smallman &amp;amp; Ingram Limited in 1908, after the death of Ingram in 1901. He did bring Ingram's family into the business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1944, Simpson's of Toronto bought them out, but Gordon Ingram (son of Lemuel) remained as chairman. The store is now known as Market Tower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most I can tell you about the Keuroglouians is that the Armenian Catholic Church of Toronto was established in 1972. At the least we can say that they donated this book well after Smallman &amp;amp; Ingram Limited was bought out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updated 9/19/2019&lt;/strong&gt;: After a long time of searching, I was finally able to find what may be the &lt;a href=&quot;https://donohuefuneralhome.ca/tribute/details/2316/Assadour-Keuroghlouian/obituary.html&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;funeral home record&lt;/a&gt; of Mr. Keuroglouian. No obituary is provided, but the funeral home is Donohue Funeral Home in London, Ontario. If this is the right person, he lived from 1903-1996. Also, I may have found him in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ancestry.com/search/categories/35/?name=_Keuroglian&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Canadian voter records&lt;/a&gt;, along with a Mrs. Mabel Keuroglouian (possibly his wife's name?), but I don't have paid access to Ancestry.com to take a closer look at the record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.londonpubliclibrary.ca/research/local-history/local-historic-sites/smallman-and-ingram-limited&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Smallman and Ingram Limited - London Public Library&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.armeniancatholicchurchoftoronto.com/history.html&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;History - Armenian Catholic Church of Toronto&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2018-04-04T18:37:03.157" Id="45489" LastActivityDate="2019-09-19T20:43:03.317" LastEditDate="2019-09-19T20:43:03.317" LastEditorUserId="2732" OwnerUserId="2732" ParentId="45461" PostTypeId="2" Score="10"/>
  <row AnswerCount="4" Body="&lt;p&gt;Guns are very loud, even in an open field. In a trench or inside a city, I can only imagine they would be louder, and quite capable of causing hearing loss. How have armies ensured that their troops weren't all deaf by the end of the first battle or even bootcamp? I'd imagine cotton balls would help but I've never seen that mentioned in books or other media.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="5" CreationDate="2018-04-13T19:11:39.133" FavoriteCount="8" Id="45658" LastActivityDate="2018-07-15T16:53:02.877" OwnerUserId="31336" PostTypeId="1" Score="59" Tags="&lt;war&gt;&lt;technology&gt;&lt;health&gt;" Title="How has hearing loss been avoided in war?" ViewCount="8047"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Until the 1940s, it was believed that the cure to loud noises was developing a tolerance to them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The pervasive attitude of the early 1900s was that hearing loss could be prevented by developing a tolerance to noise. Consequently, any attempts to avoid loud sounds or to protect oneself from them were interpreted as weakness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between 1941 and 1944, the US Army finally put this theory to the test:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This “tolerance” theory was scientifically examined in 1941 when the US Army opened the Armored Medical Research Laboratory at Fort Knox, Kentucky. This laboratory completed a landmark study in 1944 resulting in the recommendation that gun crews, gunnery instructors, and others regularly exposed to gunfire blasts be provided hearing-protective devices. The hearing protector of choice was the V-51R, single-flange earplug. &lt;strong&gt;Although hearing protection was now being considered, it still was not deemed a requirement.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;emphasis added&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn't until the advent of the Air Force that hearing protection really became significant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Even though World War II was a major contributing factor in the evolution of hearing conservation, it was not until after the war that the most significant event occurred. The Army Air Corps became a separate branch of service from the US Army and was renamed the US Air Force. Concurrently, this new branch of service introduced the jet engine aircraft to the military. No sound of that volume and duration had ever before been experienced. It was immediately noted that exposure to jet engine noise caused permanent hearing loss in a brief time. It also made verbal communication impossible and caused a series of physical manifestations described as “ultrasonic sickness.” Symptoms included earache, headache, excessive fatigue, irritability, and feelings of fear. Initially, it was believed that these symptoms were caused by inaudible, ultra-high-frequency sounds being generated by the jet engines. These symptoms, widely reported by air force maintenance crews, triggered a medical study that revealed that the illness was real; however, research attributed it to high levels of audible frequencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the first regulation was established in 1948:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As a result, the US Air Force published the first military regulation on hearing conservation in 1948. AFR 160-3, “Precautionary Measures Against Noise Hazards,” is significant not only because it was the first enforceable regulation in the history of hearing conservation, but it also placed responsibility for the new program on the medical leadership at air force installations. Some of the preventive measures described in AFR 160-3 include limiting noise exposures in terms of overall sound levels and using cotton wads moistened with paraffin as hearing protection for exposures to hazardous noise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, for the United States at least, it wasn't until 1948 that preventative measures against the hearing loss of soldiers were really taken seriously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2636536/&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Heritage of Army Audiology and the Road Ahead: The Army Hearing Program - McIlwain, et al.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="6" CreationDate="2018-04-13T20:07:03.997" Id="45659" LastActivityDate="2018-04-13T20:07:03.997" OwnerUserId="2732" ParentId="45658" PostTypeId="2" Score="69"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="45876" AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;Do we have any record of the reaction of the average British person to the Boston Tea Party? Would the proverbial man on the street have been aware of the event? If so, what was their perception of it immediately following news of the event reaching Britain? I have found a lot of material about the state's reaction to the event, but not much about the average person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;T.E.D. says in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://history.stackexchange.com/questions/45805/what-was-the-perception-of-the-average-british-person-of-the-boston-tea-party#comment124093_45805&quot;&gt;comment&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As it was more of an affront to Parliament rather than Britain, Parliament is probably the better place to look for relevant reactions anyway. Its likely your typical farmer/factory worker didn't even hear about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I arrived at this type of conjecture myself, but I'm interested in evidence, if there is any.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to further comments questioning the newsworthiness of the Boston Tea Party at the time, here is a piece from the &quot;London Magazine&quot; in 1774:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.britishmuseum.org/collectionimages/AN00012/AN00012379_001_l.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The able Doctor or America Swallowing the Bitter Draught, a political illustration&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;The Able Doctor or America swallowing the Bitter Draught, 1774. BM sat 5226&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;© The Trustees of the British Museum&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt; Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International (CC BY-NC-SA 4.0) &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;Obtained from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.britishmuseum.org/research/collection_online/collection_object_details.aspx?objectId=1452655&amp;amp;partId=1&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;http://www.britishmuseum.org/research/collection_online/collection_object_details.aspx?objectId=1452655&amp;amp;partId=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="9" CreationDate="2018-04-23T13:43:13.483" Id="45805" LastActivityDate="2018-07-28T14:59:06.307" LastEditDate="2018-04-24T13:47:28.980" LastEditorUserId="2732" OwnerUserId="2732" PostTypeId="1" Score="15" Tags="&lt;social-history&gt;&lt;american-revolution&gt;&lt;great-britain&gt;" Title="What was the perception of the average British person of the Boston Tea Party?" ViewCount="2002"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;On the events of the 16th of December 1773 in Boston Harbor, the Boston Tea Party Historical Society article &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boston-tea-party.org/british-view-new.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;British View vs. American View&lt;/a&gt;, states that the incident was&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Scarcely noted in the British press at first&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;when the news reached London on the 20th of January 1774. Thus, the ‘average British person’ would probably not even have known about it when it was first reported. A copy of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.loc.gov/teachers/classroommaterials/presentationsandactivities/presentations/timeline/amrev/rebelln/tea.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;an article from the December 20th 1773 issu&lt;/a&gt;e of the  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boston_Gazette&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Boston Gazette&lt;/a&gt; was copied by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/London_Chronicle&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;London Chronicle&lt;/a&gt; dated &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rarenewspapers.com/view/121503&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;January 22nd 1774&lt;/a&gt;. In part, it reads:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A number of brave &amp;amp; resolute men, determined to do all in their power
  to save their country from the ruin which their enemies had plotted,
  in less than four hours, emptied every chest of tea on board the three
  ships commanded by the captains Hall, Bruce, and Coffin, amounting to
  342 chests, into the sea!! without the least damage done to the ships
  or any other property. The matters and owners are well pleas'd that
  their ships are thus clear'd; and the people are almost universally
  congratulating each other on this happy event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if the 'average British person' did see or hear about this report, the significance of the Boston Tea Party would not have been immediately evident to most people and would not have appeared to be as serious as the 1770 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ushistory.org/declaration/related/massacre.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Boston Massacre&lt;/a&gt; which involved loss of life, or perhaps even the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ushistory.org/declaration/related/gaspee.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Gaspee Affair&lt;/a&gt; of 1772 when a Royal Navy ship was looted and burned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, as already noted by the OP, was not the case with Parliament, where the majority of MPs’ reaction was to support stern measures against the Bostonians. Parliament, though, was concerned with protecting its own authority and was not elected by a representative cross-section of the British population, voters being males over 21 who met minimum property requirements. In the election of October – November 1774, even this limited electorate (unlike those they elected) had other priorities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The problem of colonial policy played little part in the elections (it
  was an issue in only ten of the 314 constituencies)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: B. Knollenberg, Growth of the American Revolution&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was, however, another group who were aware of the Boston Tea Party – merchants. Their concern was, of course, self-interest; any disruption to trade would cost them dearly, but it is difficult to separate reactions to the Boston Tea Party from other events (such as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intolerable_Acts&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Intolerable Acts&lt;/a&gt;) in the wake of December 1773. Nonetheless, in &lt;em&gt;British Supporters of the American Revolution, 1775 - 1783&lt;/em&gt;, Sheldon A. Cohen notes that,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;After the Boston Tea Party in 1773, several London merchants held out
  the vain hope that some form of reconciliation could be reached with
  the North American colonists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;London merchants were not the only ones who were both aware and concerned. Cohen again:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Portsmouth was not oblivious to the crucial developments in the North
  American settlements. The town regularly received London newspapers
  and other publications featuring stories about American unrest. In
  addition, since it was a seaport, Portsmouth’s merchants were well
  aware of colonial boycotts of British goods and of the destruction of
  East India tea in Boston Harbor in 1773.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the cartoons and prints relating to the Boston Tea party is this British one &lt;a href=&quot;http://common-place.org/book/impressions-of-tar-and-feathers-the-new-american-suit-in-mezzotint-1774-84/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Published by Sayer &amp;amp; Bennett (London, October 31, 1774)&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Sayer&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Robert Sayer&lt;/a&gt; and John Bennett were Fleet St. publishers):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/lg7EE.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/lg7EE.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;enter image description here&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“A British view in 1774 of how authority was being challenged in Massachusetts. Before a “liberty tree” on which the Stamp Act placard is tacked upside down, a tarred-and-feathered Tory is being forced to drink taxed tea while in the harbour the Boston Tea Party goes on. A gibbet hangs from the liberty tree.”&lt;/em&gt; Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com.mm/books?id=KgMeh_9uWVEC&amp;amp;printsec=copyright&amp;amp;source=gbs_pub_info_r#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=tea%20party&amp;amp;f=false&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Stanley Weintraub, Iron Tears&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above image also illustrates how the Boston Tea Party was commented on along with other issues happening around the time, rather than in isolation. The tarring refers to the aftermath of an altercation involving a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gilderlehrman.org/content/british-view-rebellious-boston-1774&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;British customs officer, John Malcolm, in January 1774&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This next British print makes no direct mention of the Tea Party but is clearly a result of it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/dZvXC.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/dZvXC.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;enter image description here&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Print shows Bostonians held captive in a cage suspended from the &quot;Liberty Tree.&quot; Three British sailors standing in a boat feed them fish from a basket labeled &quot;To -- from the Committee of --&quot; in return for a bundle of papers labeled &quot;Promises&quot;; around the tree and in the background are cannons and British troops. The paper in the hand of one jailed Bostonian says &quot;They tried with the Lord in their Troubl &amp;amp; he saved them out of their Distress. CVIL 13.&quot;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.loc.gov/pictures/item/2004673305/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;London : Printed for R. Sayer and J. Bennett, Map &amp;amp; Printsellers, No. 53 Fleet Street, as the Act directs, 1774 Novr. 19.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notable individuals outside of Parliament also had something to say on the general &lt;a href=&quot;http://foreignpolicy.com/2012/07/03/how-did-the-british-press-cover-the-american-revolution/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;situation in America&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Taxation No Tyranny&lt;/em&gt;, published in 1774, Samuel Johnson, the
  compiler of the first modern English dictionary and an influential
  British writer, set the tone, asking readers how it was “that we hear
  the loudest yelps for liberty among the drivers of negroes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, it should not be forgotten that not all Americans approved of what happened in Boston. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bostonteapartyship.com/tea-blog/benjamin-franklins-views-on-the-boston-tea-party&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Benjamin Franklin&lt;/a&gt;, who was in London at the time, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.history.com/news/10-things-you-may-not-know-about-the-boston-tea-party&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;George Washington&lt;/a&gt; both condemned the destruction of property and wrote that all the destroyed tea should be paid for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note on the term '&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bostonmagazine.com/news/2017/12/14/boston-tea-party/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Boston Tea Party&lt;/a&gt;'&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The event wasn’t even labeled as the Boston Tea Party until 1826, and
  at this time the term “party” was used to refer to the men involved,
  not the event itself (they were “of the Tea Party,” not “at the Tea
  Party”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Other sources:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Electoral System and Parliamentary Reform&lt;/em&gt; (PowerPoint)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://foreignpolicy.com/2012/07/03/how-did-the-british-press-cover-the-american-revolution/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;How Did the British Press Cover the American Revolution?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com.ph/books?redir_esc=y&amp;amp;id=Taw7DVGrbRcC&amp;amp;q=boston#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=boston%20tea%20party&amp;amp;f=false&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Lewis Namier, John Brooke, The House of Commons 1754-1790&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2018-04-28T15:04:32.703" Id="45876" LastActivityDate="2018-07-28T14:59:06.307" LastEditDate="2018-07-28T14:59:06.307" LastEditorUserId="26454" OwnerUserId="26454" ParentId="45805" PostTypeId="2" Score="10"/>
  <row Body="&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question:&lt;/strong&gt; What was the perception of the average British Person of the Boston Tea Party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;General Answer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Boston Tea party was a reaction against Royal Monopoly supported by the Tea Act of 1773, not new taxes.  The Tea Act of 1773 &lt;strong&gt;reduced&lt;/strong&gt; the cost of tea &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bostonteapartyship.com/samuel-adams&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;below the price colonial tea smugglers could compete with&lt;/a&gt;.   The British were trying to re-assert their long standing Tea Monopoly for the East India Company which was nearly bankrupt due to all the smuggling both in the British Colonies and domestically in Britain itself.   By reforming their tax policy, making their disbursement more efficient, and undercutting the price of the dominant black market tea which controlled 90% of the colonial market, the British Parliament hoped to increase it's control over the colonies.  Further the Tea Act shifted the use of the existing Tea Tax, which now was substantially reduced, to fund expenses in the Colonies which the British thought was both reasonable and would not draw down the protests which defined the earlier Stamp Act of 1765.  The Tea act both halved the existing tax and transferred that revenue to pay for Royal appointed colonial governmental officials like the governors.  These governors salaries were traditionally paid for by the colonial legislatures.  By paying these appointed local officials directly from the crown, although still with colonial money, the Sons of Liberty believed the local legislatures were weakened as now their governorships were more loyal to London than their Colonies.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The response from the Son's of Liberty, funded by tea smugglers, was to threaten and physically intimidate colonial merchants not to accept the cheap tea.  This was very effective and no colonial merchants would risk taking delivery of this legal very inexpensive tea.  The tea could not even be offloaded from the ships which brought it to the colonies. This lead to the British tea being consolidated in ships in Boston Harbor for weeks unable to be offloaded.  Being thus consolidated it was a target for the Son's of Liberty and resulted in the Boston Tea Party.  If the East India Company's legal tea was permitted to reach the Colonies market, it would undercut the lucrative black market enterprise of the Son's of Liberty's primary benefactor, John Hancock.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boston-tea-party.org/smuggling/John-Hancock.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;John Hancock&lt;/a&gt; made his fortune selling smuggled goods, especially tea, would become the first and most prominent signer of the Declaration of Independence just under 3 years removed from the Boston Tea Party.  It would have also strengthened the crown's control over the Colonies at the expense of Colonial legislatures and Colonial merchants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Boston itself the reaction to the Tea Party was pretty reserved.  The ships which were targeted by the Son's of Liberty were proximal to Royal Navy ships moored in the harbor and the harbor was patrolled by Royal Soldiers, yet neither had any reaction to the night time raid.  Now you can say this is because it was in the middle of the night. However, the day after the Boston Tea Party the Son's of liberty discovered that much of the tea thrown into Boston Harbor was still floating on the surface of the water in it's water tight containers; this prompted the Son's of Liberty to return in broad daylight, with the crews of the Royal Navy ships watching... and sink the containers in broad daylight.  Still no reaction from the British military which was all over the Boston Harbor and it's docks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When news from Boston of the destruction of private property arrived back in Britain, it was not covered by the British Press, and thus the average Britain would have been unaware of the event.  Britain was the larger market for smuggled Dutch tea, much larger than were the colonies so the average Britain's sympathies might have been mixed.  However since the Tea Act only reduced the costs of tea in the Colonies and did not effect the price in Britain, such a Britain might have been unaware of the Tea Act altogether and its role in inspiring the Boston Tea Party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the average Britain who was taxed at a higher rate than his colonial brothers was generally unsympathetic to the Colonial demonstrations over taxation from the Stamp Act which occurred almost 8 years before the Tea Act.  The Stamp Act was passed to modestly contribute to the expense of the Seven Years War or French and Indian War.  A war started in the Colonies by future American President George Washington.  A war which protected the Colonies and severely impacted the British purse.           &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more pertinent reaction was not from the average Britain but from the British Parliament.  The reaction from Parliament would transform the Boston Tea Party into the historical event most Americans remember.  Parliament in reaction would reconsider their long policy of appeasement to the Colonies mob eruptions, and respond with the Coercive Acts(Dec 1773).  The Colonies would call them the &quot;Intolerable Acts&quot;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Closed Boston Harbor until the Boston Tea Party destroyed goods were paid for&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modified Massachusetts charter of 1691 to end local participation in government.  Put Massachusetts under Military rule, and outlawed town meetings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Administration of Justice Act&lt;/strong&gt;, Allowed British Official charged with capital crimes in the Colonies to be tried for these crimes back in Britain and not answerable to Colonial Courts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quartering Act&lt;/strong&gt;,  Allowed the British Military confiscate occupied buildings in the colonies for their use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Quebec Act&lt;/strong&gt;, removed all the territory and fur trade between the Ohio and Mississippi rivers from possible colonial jurisdiction and awarded it to the province of Quebec.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reaction to these acts would magnify the Boston Tea Party into the spark for the Colonies to organize their own underground government (Continental Congress first conviened 1774), The Declaration of Independence(July 4th, 1776) and ultimately the Revolutionary War.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Detailed Answer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Important Dates.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;1763                    Seven Years War(French and Indian War) ends
1765                    British Parliament Passes the Stamp Act Tax
1766                    British Parliament repeals the Stamp Act.
1767                    Parliament passes Indemnity Act, 
Mar 5th, 1770           Boston Massacre
1773                    British Parliament passes the Tea Act 
Dec 16th, 1773          Boston Tea Party
1774                    Parliament passes the Intolerable Acts, 
                           a series of acts designed to punish Boston
                           and the Colonies for the Boston Tea Party.
Sept 1774               The Continental Congress's first meeting, 
                           calls upon the British Parliament to
                           repeal the Intolerable Acts.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Important Facts.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.history.com/topics/american-revolution/tea-act&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;The Stamp Act(1765 - 1766)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; was the first direct, internal tax that Parliament had ever levied on the colonists.  It was repealed after British officials trying to enforce it were subject to physical intimidation and mob violence, making it's enforcement impossible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.revolutionary-war-and-beyond.com/indemnity-act-of-1767-text.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;The Indemnity Act&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; was the first attempt by Parliament to save the British East India Company which was one of England's largest companies, but was on the verge of collapse due to much cheaper smuggled Dutch tea. Part of the purpose of the entire series of Townshend Acts was to save the company from imploding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boston_Tea_Party&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;The biggest market for illicit tea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; was England—by the 1760s the East India Company was losing £400,000 per year to smugglers in Great Britain[&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At the time of the Boston Tea Party American colonists consumed, on average, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.history.com/topics/american-revolution/tea-act&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;2 to 3 cups of tea each day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. This equaled approximately two million pounds of tea among 3 million colonists each year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was estimated that &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.history.com/topics/american-revolution/tea-act&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;approximately 90%&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of the tea being drank by American colonists was smuggled. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.history.com/topics/american-revolution/tea-act&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;The Tea Act(1773)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; eight years after the failed Stamp Act, was not a tax.  Tea sold in the colonies prior to the Tea Act was required to travel to Britain first for export, where it was taxed.  Then shipped to the colonies were it was taxed again.  The Tea Act allowed the tea most of which came from China or India to be shipped directly to the US,  thus cutting the effective tax in half and lowering overall the consumer cost significantly.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shipping companies who purchased tea from the East Company for distribution to Colonial Merchants had tons of rotting tea in colonial warehouses which they could not sell due to colonial hostilities over taxes.  &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bostonteapartyship.com/samuel-adams&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;The Tea act&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; allowed the East India Company to dump this tea onto the market at rock bottom prices, undercutting all illegal competition. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bostonteapartyship.com/samuel-adams&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;The Tea Act&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; so reduced the cost of British tea within the colonial marketplace that it made British tea cheaper than smuggled tea.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Boston Tea Party(Dec 16th, 1773)&lt;/strong&gt; was in reaction to &lt;strong&gt;The Tea Act(1773)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Son's of Liberties Leader who organized the Boston Tea Party was &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bostonteapartyship.com/samuel-adams&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Samuel Adams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; cousin of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Adams&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;John Adams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; the second President of the United States.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bostonteapartyship.com/samuel-adams&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Samuel Adams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; was strongly associated with the another founding father and tea smuggler, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boston-tea-party.org/smuggling/John-Hancock.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;John Hancock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.   A joke at the time was the two were so close that when Samuel Adams wrote a letter, John Hancock licked the stamps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boston-tea-party.org/smuggling/John-Hancock.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;John Hancock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; was a wealthy shipping magnate, who made the bulk of his money illegally by smuggling tea, and almost single handedly financed all of the early protests against Britain in Boston.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When news of the Boston Tea Party arrived back in London, the event was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boston-tea-party.org/british-view-new.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;barely mentioned in the British Press&lt;/a&gt;.  The people on the streets of Britain were were not initially overly concerned with the destruction of property which occurred in Boston Harbor.  What magnified the event was the perception of Parliament.  From Parliament's perspective they had originally mishandled the colonies and that is what resulted in this further dispute.  Parliament had originally asked the Colonies to contribute modestly for the war Britain undertook on their behalf with the Stamp Act.  Parliament had reacted to the Colonies negative and volatile response by repealing the Stamp Act in it's first year.  This time Parliament decided to take a different tact.   This time Parliament's reaction would come to be known in the Colonies as the Intolerable Acts.  The Colonists reaction to these series of five acts designed to punish the colonies, lead directly to the meeting of the first Continental Congress in 1774, and ultimately the Revolutionary War.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bostonteapartyship.com/the-aftermath&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;News Reaches London of the Boston Tea Party&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  The news of the Boston Tea Party reached London, England on January 20, 1774, and as a result the British shut down Boston Harbor until all of the 340 chests of British East India Company tea were paid for. This was implemented under the 1774 Intolerable Acts and known as the Boston Port Act. In addition to the Boston Port Act, the Intolerable Acts also implemented the Massachusetts Government Act, the Administration of Justice Act, the Quartering Act, and the Quebec Act. American colonists responded with protests and coordinated resistance by convening the First Continental Congress in September and October of 1774 to petition Britain to repeal the Intolerable Acts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sources:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.softschools.com/facts/history/boston_tea_party_facts/1026/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Boston Tea Party Facts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.history.com/topics/american-revolution/tea-act&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Tea Act&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bostonteapartyship.com/samuel-adams&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Samuel Adams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boston_Tea_Party&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Boston Tea Party&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boston-tea-party.org/smuggling/John-Hancock.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;John Hancock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Adams&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;John Adams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.revolutionary-war-and-beyond.com/indemnity-act-of-1767-text.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Indemnity Act&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bostonteapartyship.com/sons-of-liberty&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Sons of Liberty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bostonteapartyship.com/the-aftermath&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;The Boston Tea Party :Aftermath&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boston-tea-party.org/british-view-new.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Boston Tea Party Historical Society&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2018-04-29T20:18:13.437" Id="45899" LastActivityDate="2018-07-18T16:56:51.190" LastEditDate="2018-07-18T16:56:51.190" LastEditorUserId="27618" OwnerUserId="27618" ParentId="45805" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="48204" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;It's common for seats to contain springs. Cushions have been part of seats as long as there has been upholstery. In vehicle seats, springs absorb unwanted forces perpendicular to the direction of the vehicle's travel. This job is identical to that of the vehicle's suspension (if any). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In vehicle suspensions, suspended carriages preceded sprung carriages. If the same thing happened for vehicle seats, then U.S. Patent 104,714 of 1870, for seats suspended from &quot;bars&quot;, might precede the use of springs in seats. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When did elastic, solid springs first appear in or below vehicle seats?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2018-09-10T06:34:13.910" Id="48038" LastActivityDate="2018-10-03T16:35:01.997" LastEditDate="2018-09-10T15:56:44.927" LastEditorUserId="18968" OwnerUserId="18968" PostTypeId="1" Score="4" Tags="&lt;technology&gt;&lt;transportation&gt;" Title="When did springs first appear in or below vehicle seats?" ViewCount="187"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;At first, the earliest reference I could find to a spring seat in a vehicle was in William Felton's &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/atreatiseoncarr00feltgoog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Treatise on Carriages&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (published 1794), in which he describes (on page 144):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;it [the coach-box] is fixed on to the top iron-work with bolts, having a cradle, the same as the others, for the seat; they sometimes hang upon springs, and are made with a head and knee-flap the same as to a one-horse chaise; their use is to make the situation of the servant more comfortable, and more secure from danger, by travelling on bad roads&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This source seems to take the existence of the spring seat for granted, so it seems to already be implemented at this time, meaning the spring seat may have been around for longer. However, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gold_State_Coach&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Gold State Coach&lt;/a&gt; (commissioned in 1760) does not seem to have a sprung seat, so the innovation probably occurred at some point between 1760 and 1794.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I found an early patent that coins the word &quot;spring seat&quot;. It is dated &quot;A.D. 1792, May 25&quot; by John March.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Certain springs and rollers are set forth as being placed below the body of the carriage, apparently for the purpose of preventing such body from swinging improperly from side to side owing to its &quot;centrical suspension,&quot; and both the coachman's seat and the footman's standing board are also mounted on springs, there being also a &quot;spring seat&quot; for the inside of the vehicle which is supported by hooks and straps, as well as other seats or stools inside the vehicle which turn upon hinges so as to be raised or lowered at pleasure, and likewise a &quot;drop table.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This patent is described in &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=MXVUAAAAYAAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA68&amp;amp;lpg=PA68&amp;amp;dq=%22spring+seat%22+%22carriage%22+%221792%22+-machine+-warehouse&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=0Q_oKYaibB&amp;amp;sig=nmqOsD5izPtUgfufR6ICXQob11A&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwiFoMq6yOrdAhWD_YMKHRoSDcQQ6AEwCHoECAgQAQ#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=%22spring%20seat%22%20%22carriage%22%20%221792%22%20-machine%20-warehouse&amp;amp;f=false&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Patents for Inventions. Abridgements of Specifications Relating to Carriages and Other Vehicles for Common Roads. A.D. 1625-1866. London&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2018-09-19T16:34:03.430" Id="48204" LastActivityDate="2018-10-03T16:35:01.997" LastEditDate="2018-10-03T16:35:01.997" LastEditorUserId="2732" OwnerUserId="2732" ParentId="48038" PostTypeId="2" Score="4"/>
  <row AnswerCount="0" Body="&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eunuchus&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eunuchus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by the Roman playwright &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Terence&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Terence&lt;/a&gt;, there is a prologue penned for the explicit purpose of justifying the author's reuse of existing characters. In a section, the author identifies some common literary tropes of his time and defends his reuse on those grounds:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When the officials were present, a run-through began. He cried out that it was a thief, not an author,
  who had put the play on, but that he hadn’t put one over on him all
  the same. He said that there was a play called The Toady by Naevius
  and Plautus, an old play, and that the characters of the parasite and
  the soldier had been lifted from it.
  If that wrong has been done, it was done through the author’s
  ignorance, not because he was keen to commit a theft. That this is so,
  you will now be able to judge. There’s a play called The Toady by
  Menander; in it there’s a parasite (the Toady) and a boastful soldier. 
  The author does not deny that he has transferred those characters to
  his Eunuch, from the Greek play; but he does utterly deny that he
  knew those plays had been written previously in Latin. And if he’s not
  allowed to use the same characters as someone else has used, how is
  it more allowable to show a running slave, to make his mothers
  good and his prostitutes bad, [a parasite gluttonous and a soldier
  boastful,] to write about a supposititious baby, the deception of an
   old man by a slave, love, hate, suspicion? In short, there’s nothing
  said today that has not been said before. So it’s right that you should
  acknowledge and allow it, if new writers do what old ones used to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;From the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amherst.edu/system/files/.../terence_eunuch_translation_brown_0.PDF&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Peter Brown translation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seems very similar to the justification behind the modern legal doctrine of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fair_use&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;fair use&lt;/a&gt;. Is this the earliest example of such a defense, or is there an earlier instance of defending recycling intellectual property in a literary context?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2019-01-07T19:54:36.167" Id="50512" LastActivityDate="2019-01-07T19:54:36.167" OwnerUserId="2732" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;ancient-history&gt;&lt;law&gt;&lt;literature&gt;" Title="Is the Prologue to Eunuchus the earliest recorded defense of literary fair use?" ViewCount="69"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="50928" AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;I've been researching African ethnography recently, and this path has led me to looking for early accounts of Sub-Saharan Africa. That they come from non-residents likely goes without saying, but I specify this as to not be Eurocentric.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've done a bit of research to try to find out what and where these accounts may be, but I'm coming up empty-handed. So if I were to visit an academic library for the earliest, surviving written accounts of Sub-Saharan Africa, what would the title/author of these books be?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2019-01-31T17:53:14.957" Id="50913" LastActivityDate="2019-02-02T09:29:11.620" LastEditDate="2019-02-01T20:00:20.907" LastEditorUserId="771" OwnerUserId="4886" PostTypeId="1" Score="5" Tags="&lt;africa&gt;&lt;resource&gt;" Title="What are the earliest written accounts of Sub-Saharan Africa from the outside?" ViewCount="268"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Originally, the question asked for a non-African source, which I interpreted as an account from someone who originally lived outside Africa. The question has now been refined to include any accounts outside of sub-Saharan Africa, which would include early Egyptian accounts and others such as the Egypt-dwelling Greek/Roman sources in Lars's answer. I won't attempt to capture those, so what follows focuses on the earliest accounts from sources located entirely outside Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The earliest account of Sub-Saharan Africa by a non-African that I can find is &lt;em&gt;Kitab al-Budan&lt;/em&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ya%27qubi&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Ya'qubi&lt;/a&gt; in 872 CE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the English translations you might look for is &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=LnxTDwAAQBAJ&amp;amp;q=africa#v=snippet&amp;amp;q=766&amp;amp;f=false&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Works of Ibn Wāḍiḥ al-Yaʿqūbī&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Here is an excerpt:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Whoever travels south by road from Sijilmasa toward the land of the Blacks,&lt;sup&gt;766&lt;/sup&gt; (inhabited by) various black tribes, travels through wasteland and desert for a distance of fifty days' journey. One then encounters a group of Sanhaja called the Anbiya in the desert; they have no fixed dwelling.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;766 Arabic &lt;em&gt;ard al-sudan&lt;/em&gt;: for Arabic geographers the term covers all of sub-Saharan Africa, not merely the modern Sudan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=6ug7DwAAQBAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA83&amp;amp;lpg=PA83&amp;amp;dq=Ya%27qubi+sub-saharan+africa&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=hzvg5k-tOD&amp;amp;sig=ACfU3U28pf5yelb7pf08uvHUm3HahJmJBg&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwjxy92W1pjgAhURY6wKHTCyDdwQ6AEwAXoECAkQAQ#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=Ya&amp;#39;qubi%20sub-saharan%20africa&amp;amp;f=false&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Trade in the Ancient Sahara and Beyond&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; claims that the first accounts to the outside world of sub-Saharan West Africa came from Muslim traders. It mentions Ya'qubi as a source, so he may be as early as it gets.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2019-01-31T18:59:42.057" Id="50914" LastActivityDate="2019-02-01T20:07:13.153" LastEditDate="2019-02-01T20:07:13.153" LastEditorUserId="2732" OwnerUserId="2732" ParentId="50913" PostTypeId="2" Score="4"/>
  <row AnswerCount="4" Body="&lt;p&gt;I just saw the film &lt;em&gt;Dora and the Lost City of Gold&lt;/em&gt;, in which there is a somewhat meta running commentary over whether so-called &quot;jungle puzzles&quot;, intellectual challenges typically requiring explorers to push the right buttons, pull the right levers, step on the right tiles, make the correct offering to an idol, etc., and that stereotypically guard large caches of treasure in treasure hunting films, actually exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did ancient peoples ever actually guard their treasure behind intellectual puzzles? To be clear, it seems to have been &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; common for treasure to be guarded by &lt;em&gt;security through obscurity&lt;/em&gt; solutions, with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nationalgeographic.com/news/2018/02/king-tut-tomb-hidden-chamber-scan-egypt/&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;passages hidden behind fake walls&lt;/a&gt;, stuff buried in the middle of nowhere, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Southern_South_Saqqara_pyramid&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;decoy artifacts and rooms&lt;/a&gt;, but I'm having trouble finding any instances of actual &lt;em&gt;puzzles&lt;/em&gt; of the kind that appear in H. Rider Haggard novels, &lt;em&gt;Indiana Jones&lt;/em&gt; films, and &lt;em&gt;Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons&lt;/em&gt; adventures, where the original designers seem to have &lt;em&gt;intended&lt;/em&gt; that the puzzle be &lt;em&gt;solved&lt;/em&gt; at some future time by persons deemed worthy enough &lt;em&gt;by possession of the correct skills or knowledge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The critical difference between a &quot;puzzle&quot; and ordinary hidden or buried treasure is the apparent &lt;em&gt;intent&lt;/em&gt; that a future quest for the items would involve significant &lt;em&gt;intellectual&lt;/em&gt; efforts, such as applying knowledge of traditional lore, recognizing obscure grammatical quirks, solving math problems, using lateral thinking skills, applying steganographic analysis, recognizing out-of-place elements (e.g. all these symbols are of animals that lay eggs except this one, so this is the correct lever to pull and none other), and otherwise performing cognitively significant tasks beyond bare memorization. Cases where a treasure was apparently hidden or secured &lt;em&gt;without&lt;/em&gt; eye to a puzzle but where the effort was concentrated on making it hard to find and/or especially difficult to penetrate (secured against brute force solutions) don't count. Drilling through 10 meters of rock or searching every tree in a forest for the one that has a symbol carved into it is not a puzzle, but a chore. Having to recognize that a &quot;star chart&quot; is actually a map of a forest with a rectangular-&gt;polar coordinate transform and that the tree with the symbol is the one corresponding to the center of the galaxy on the map &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a puzzle was &lt;em&gt;actually solved&lt;/em&gt; in modern times by chance or brute force, but significant evidence exists that it was originally &lt;em&gt;intended&lt;/em&gt; to be solved via a puzzle process, that can count. For example, if an ancient tomb on the side of a mountain was accidentally rediscovered when a World War One fighter pilot was shot down near it, but a later generation discovered that a 3000 year-old painting in a nearby downtown temple steganographically encodes hiking directions to the entrance, that counts. Similarly, if 18th century scurvy pirates (arr) encountered an Ancient Greek &quot;push the button that doesn't trigger a trap&quot; wall but decided to bypass it with explosives because they were all illiterate and had minimal knowledge of Greek lore, that would also count as long as sufficient evidence exists to reconstruct what the original puzzle configuration probably was.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="7" CreationDate="2019-08-27T11:47:30.680" FavoriteCount="10" Id="54355" LastActivityDate="2019-09-05T12:54:43.240" LastEditDate="2019-08-28T03:14:42.463" LastEditorUserId="21290" OwnerUserId="21290" PostTypeId="1" Score="67" Tags="&lt;ancient-history&gt;&lt;science&gt;&lt;gold&gt;&lt;engineering&gt;&lt;secrecy&gt;" Title="Did ancient peoples ever hide their treasure behind puzzles?" ViewCount="12256"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;One man's &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Combination_lock&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;lock&lt;/a&gt; is another man's puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combination locks have been used since at least ancient Rome. Whether the lock uses numbers or letters (or other symbols), the combination to be entered may be set based on a riddle or some other piece of knowledge as a mnemonic. The lock is meant to be solved at some future time by someone who has the correct knowledge. The intention of the one who put the lock on was most likely that it only be &quot;solved&quot; by authorized persons, but to a thief it is a puzzle to crack. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slate.com/blogs/the_eye/2015/04/15/a_history_of_lockpicking_from_99_percent_invisible_and_roman_mars.html&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Lockpicking&lt;/a&gt; is as old as locks themselves, and while mechanical solutions are probable--it is likely the codes were sometimes cracked as well. &lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="12" CreationDate="2019-08-27T12:20:31.753" Id="54356" LastActivityDate="2019-08-27T12:20:31.753" OwnerUserId="2732" ParentId="54355" PostTypeId="2" Score="43"/>
  <row Body="Questions relating to the Roman politician and general Gaius Julius Caesar" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2019-08-30T15:51:53.087" Id="54414" LastActivityDate="2019-08-30T16:03:55.930" LastEditDate="2019-08-30T16:03:55.930" LastEditorUserId="2732" OwnerUserId="2732" PostTypeId="4" Score="0"/>
  <row AnswerCount="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/River_Oaks,_Houston&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;River Oaks, Houston, TX&lt;/a&gt;, attorney recently purchased and parked outside his home  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wtsp.com/article/news/local/hoa-fight-over-world-war-ii-tank-in-river-oaks/67-479874785&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;a fully functional World War Two tank&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: The original newspaper article claimed the tank was &quot;fully functional&quot; - but the main gun was disabled by drilling a hole through it prior to departing France.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To my untrained eye it appears to be a Sherman, but I am looking for a more expert opinion. Can anyone definitely determine the type and model of this tank, along with any other interesting specifications?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&quot;The problem is there is no action [the Homeowners' Association] can take,&quot; said Buzbee. &quot;They can ticket it or they can try to tow it, but the truth is unless I decide to move it, it's not going anywhere.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/1l3sM.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/1l3sM.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;enter image description here&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presumably this is a serial number of some sort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/GTZ14.png&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/GTZ14.png&quot; alt=&quot;enter image description here&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not sure what these numbers represent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/hQMbR.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/hQMbR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;enter image description here&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More details, with thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://history.stackexchange.com/users/2732/called2voyage&quot;&gt;called2voyage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.texasmonthly.com/the-daily-post/complete-story-river-oaks-tank/&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;https://www.texasmonthly.com/the-daily-post/complete-story-river-oaks-tank/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="13" CreationDate="2019-09-18T14:34:46.840" FavoriteCount="4" Id="54663" LastActivityDate="2019-09-19T17:26:05.120" LastEditDate="2019-09-19T16:38:31.127" LastEditorUserId="2283" OwnerUserId="2283" PostTypeId="1" Score="19" Tags="&lt;world-war-two&gt;&lt;tanks&gt;" Title="Is this a Sherman, and if so what model?" ViewCount="4917"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;It appears from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.artcurial.com/en/lot-1944-chrysler-m4a4-sherman-3114-46&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;auction details&lt;/a&gt;, that the serial number of the tank is 18688.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The serial number does appear on &lt;a href=&quot;http://the.shadock.free.fr/sherman_minutia/data/known_sherman_SNs.html&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;this list&lt;/a&gt; of known Sherman serial numbers compiled by Pierre-Olivier Buan (who has been cited as an expert on tanks of this era) and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entry identifies the tank's type as M4A4(75), which was manufactured by Chrysler. The registration number entry varies from what's on the tank, but it is marked red, which means unconfirmed and possibly wrong. Randolph Duke, in the Texas Monthly article linked in the question, claims the original registration number was painted over. The notes say:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Comes from the range target, Salisbury Plain. Previously located at Coleraine, NI, UK and then in Normandy, France&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The website with the list of Shermans has more information on &lt;a href=&quot;http://the.shadock.free.fr/sherman_minutia/sherman_types/m4a4/m4a4.html&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;this variant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The M4A4 Shermans were equipped with a Chrysler Multibank engine; they have a lengthened welded hull. Only the 75mm version were built in the USA, but the M4A4 was also widely used as a basis for 17pdr Firefly tank by the British Army. The users were : Britain, France, China (Source : Wikipedia).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This variant was only manufactured by Chrysler (7499 units produced).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This tank has a 75mm gun, small hatches (protruding hoods), a 57° glacis and dry ammunition stowage bins. The M4A4s were only produced with the 3-piece differential housing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a little bit more information at that link along with pictures.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2019-09-18T15:26:14.290" Id="54664" LastActivityDate="2019-09-18T15:37:35.043" LastEditDate="2019-09-18T15:37:35.043" LastEditorUserId="2732" OwnerUserId="2732" ParentId="54663" PostTypeId="2" Score="27"/>
</posts>