<?xml version="1.0" ?><posts>
  <row AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;I've read (probably in wikipedia but can't track down the reference now) that the Asharite strand in Islamic theology couldn't accept that substance necessarily exists pre-eternally as the Quoran revealed Allah as the creator of this universe, and if something existed pre-eternally then there is no need for a creator. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accordingly they dismantled time and space, by cleverly extending Democritus's theory of atomism from substance to both space &amp;amp; time. That is time and space emerged from a gathering together of time &amp;amp; space atoms. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Of course one could say that these time atoms were also pre-existant before time itself. On a straight reading that question is nonsensical as time has been dismantled, there is no pre-, but to me, the question still has force, it is a matter of framing it correctly. How, I don't know, otherwise I would have framed it here.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does anyone have a reference where this is discussed, as it seems an interesting &amp;amp; fundamentally novel extension of greek atomism?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2012-06-13T01:46:33.457" Id="2997" LastActivityDate="2013-06-21T21:09:14.180" LastEditDate="2013-06-21T20:01:01.037" LastEditorUserId="81" OwnerUserId="933" PostTypeId="1" Score="1" Tags="&lt;philosophy-of-religion&gt;&lt;time&gt;&lt;atomism&gt;" Title="Does Asharite atomism affirm that space &amp; time must necessarily be atomic?" ViewCount="174"/>
  <row AnswerCount="6" Body="&lt;p&gt;It is often the case that a person convicted of attempted murder receives a lesser punishment than if they had been successful in committing the crime. As far as I am aware, there are four main reasons for punishing criminals: 1) deterrence 2) incapacitation 3) rehabilitation 4) retribution. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fourth reason seems to be the least popular, and if one does subscribe to this as a reason for criminal punishment, then I can see why they would view attempted murder as a lesser crime than murder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now as for 1): Since one cannot plan an attempted murder (I mean since succeeding in this would result in no murder at all) the incarceration of attempted murderers is used as a deterrent against people who plan to murder. So I am not sure how one can use the deterrence reason for punishment as a justification for attempted murder being a lesser crime than murder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For 2): I am not sure that attempted murderers are any less of a threat to society than murderers. I suppose you can argue that murder gets easier with each kill, and so a murderer is actually more dangerous than an attempted murderer, though I am not sure that's true. One might be able to make the argument that in some cases an attempted murderer is actually more dangerous than a murderer, since the murderer might have killed the only person he wanted to kill, whereas the attempted murderer may try to finish the job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For 3): Perhaps this is where the strongest argument for attempted murder being a lesser crime than murder comes from. All else being equal, it does seem like it would be easier (or at least no harder) to rehabilitate attempted murderers than murderers, in the sense that if  one is looking to reintegrate back into society, it seems like it would be easier to do so knowing that you haven't committed such a foul crime. If I tried to do something bad but failed, then I wouldn't feel as bad about having done what I did, and I could move on quicker.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2013-03-16T02:14:08.347" FavoriteCount="1" Id="6297" LastActivityDate="2016-08-05T17:12:39.400" LastEditDate="2016-07-29T13:46:11.700" LastEditorUserId="20618" OwnerUserId="2184" PostTypeId="1" Score="9" Tags="&lt;ethics&gt;&lt;philosophy-of-law&gt;" Title="Should attempted murder be a lesser crime than murder?" ViewCount="4199"/>
  <row AnswerCount="4" Body="&lt;p&gt;I recently read about encoding and exemplifying. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From what I understand - Detective Smith (a real person) exemplifies detectiveness, but Sherlock Homes does not. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sherlock Homes isn't real - and if, upon first learning of the character, I was told 'Sherlock Homes is a detective' - that information (that he's a detective) wouldn't tell me much about detectives - it wouldn't 'exemplify' detectives very well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if someone first told me everything about Sherlock Homes, but did not tell me that he is a detective - and then revealed to me that he was. When I learned that Sherlock Homes is a detective, now knowing everything about him (especially, now that I know about his work routine) - I'd have to say I have an exemplification of a detective. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, why do fictional characters not exemplify properties?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2013-06-04T22:53:13.487" Id="7149" LastActivityDate="2013-10-08T18:30:59.833" OwnerUserId="3676" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;metaphysics&gt;&lt;ontology&gt;&lt;philosophy-of-language&gt;&lt;contemporary-philosophy&gt;" Title="Why do fictional characters not exemplify properties?" ViewCount="381"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;According to at least one source, it seems that the Asharites didn't believe in space or time as physical constructs. They only exist in the mind of the one who perceives them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Aristotelian categories of thought were subjected by the Ash'arites to a searching criticism. Only two of those categories, substance and quality, were retained by them. The other categories, quality, place, time, etc., are nothing but relative characteristics (i'tibarat) that exist subjectively in the mind of the knower, having no corresponding objective reality.
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.muslimphilosophy.com/hmp/14.htm&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Source: MuslimPhilosophy.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This quote does state &quot;quality&quot; in both that they retained and that they didn't, but I assume one of them is meant to be &quot;quantity&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-06-21T21:09:14.180" Id="7335" LastActivityDate="2013-06-21T21:09:14.180" OwnerUserId="3929" ParentId="2997" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;An attempted murder may have failed for a number of reasons. One possibility is that the potential murderer had a strong conscience that prevented the attempted murder from being realized. Compare this situation to that of a psychopath who has little to no restraint from the desire to murder. The latter obviously needs more deterrent, incapacitation, and rehabilitation than the former.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-06-21T21:18:07.543" Id="7336" LastActivityDate="2013-06-21T21:18:07.543" OwnerUserId="3929" ParentId="6297" PostTypeId="2" Score="0"/>
  <row AnswerCount="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;A: &quot;Biologically men and women are different, and therefore it shouldn't surprise they have different salary on average&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B: &quot;That is obvious. But you cannot derive from such a difference in terms of biology a difference in regulation terms&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B has clearly made a fallacy: s/he answered to a point that was not antecedently made by A, given the impression he did correct A on something. Is correct to refer to this fallacy as &lt;a href=&quot;https://it.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ignoratio_elenchi&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;ignoratio elenchi&lt;/a&gt; or there is a more specific name for it?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="5" CreationDate="2013-06-22T08:35:16.230" Id="7341" LastActivityDate="2013-06-27T15:17:56.590" OwnerUserId="3932" PostTypeId="1" Score="1" Tags="&lt;fallacies&gt;&lt;argumentation&gt;" Title="Fallacy: shifting the point of the conversation" ViewCount="180"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;In contrast to the other answers, I break down Person A and Person B's arguments differently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Person A it seems to me makes the following argument:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) If two individuals have different attributes and functions, they produce different results in a career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2) These different results can and often do result in different salaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3) Biologically, men and women are different in attributes and functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4) Therefore, it should not be surprising that men and women have different salaries on average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Person A makes no normative judgement as to whether this &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Person B makes the following argument in response:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) It is obvious that men and women's biological differences produce different results in a career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2) This situation does not have to be resolved by allowing the course of action to flow to a difference in salary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3) Regulations can be put in place that control the environment to produce equivalent outcomes for both male and female employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4) You cannot derive a normative requirment for men and women to have different salaries if this regulation is possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this last point (number 4) in Person B's argument is where there is a fallacy. It is a straw man argument because it is a claim that Person A made a normative judgment where that person did not.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-06-27T15:17:56.590" Id="7399" LastActivityDate="2013-06-27T15:17:56.590" OwnerUserId="3929" ParentId="7341" PostTypeId="2" Score="0"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="7435" AnswerCount="6" Body="&lt;p&gt;What is the proper definition of atheism? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have heard people talking about atheism being a lack of beliefs or an absence of faith. That does not strike me as a very good definition though as every inanimate object in the universe has a &quot;absence of faith&quot; That would lead us to believe anything without a brain has a absence of faith and is therefore also a atheist.&lt;/p&gt;
" ClosedDate="2016-01-13T23:01:57.817" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2013-07-02T17:30:07.713" FavoriteCount="0" Id="7432" LastActivityDate="2016-01-09T16:17:46.800" LastEditDate="2016-01-09T16:17:46.800" LastEditorUserId="81" OwnerUserId="1660" PostTypeId="1" Score="2" Tags="&lt;philosophy-of-religion&gt;&lt;atheism&gt;&lt;semantics&gt;" Title="What is the proper definition of atheism?" ViewCount="853"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://oxforddictionaries.com/us/definition/american_english/atheism?q=atheism&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Oxford Dictionaries&lt;/a&gt; defines atheism as such:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;disbelief or lack of belief in the existence of God or gods. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
" CommentCount="11" CreationDate="2013-07-02T17:49:55.377" Id="7433" LastActivityDate="2013-07-02T19:51:52.413" LastEditDate="2013-07-02T19:51:52.413" LastEditorUserId="3929" OwnerUserId="3929" ParentId="7432" PostTypeId="2" Score="0"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="7444" AnswerCount="5" Body="&lt;p&gt;I just saw this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smbc-comics.com/index.php?db=comics&amp;amp;id=2740#comic&quot;&gt;SMBC comic&lt;/a&gt;. The second picture looked really promising, but as far as I see it, this attorney screwed up. With his second wish it doesn't matter whether you say wish or splork, so effectively the genie was forbidding to splork for more splorks as well. Is there a way to ask the genie for infinite wishes in a very clear logical way, that leaves the genie no loophole? (and let's pretend the genie really let's you have only three wishes, because in the comic one cannot say how many wishes the genie actually (wanted to) allow for. It is just somewhat implied that it was three so let's stick with that idea.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit: I acknowledge and appreciate the easy answer of Gugg but if someone could give an answer with the now additional made up - and admittedly kinda dull - restriction, please answer as well: One cannot just tell the genie that what he says just doesn't count any more at all. I don't know now if the question is very well defined now, but maybe someone can still make something of it. &lt;/p&gt;
" ClosedDate="2016-01-03T16:07:46.310" CommentCount="12" CreationDate="2013-07-03T14:15:25.127" FavoriteCount="1" Id="7438" LastActivityDate="2014-03-02T19:37:10.847" LastEditDate="2013-07-03T15:54:50.017" LastEditorUserId="3970" OwnerUserId="3970" PostTypeId="1" Score="9" Tags="&lt;logic&gt;&lt;language&gt;" Title="Asking a genie for more wishes" ViewCount="23273"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Your initial premise is that a genie can grant you exactly three wishes, and that he cannot grant you the wish of more wishes. I would presume that the heart of what is meant by the latter restriction is that you cannot wish anything that would alter the structure of the wishing system itself. This, however, is easily bypassed if you wish for more genies of the type in our premise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tradition brings us two more rules regarding wishes, however. Here are all three:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You cannot wish for more wishes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You cannot wish to kill or bring back from the dead.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You cannot wish for anyone to fall in love with you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, these rules seem to have more generic rules at the heart of them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You cannot wish anything that would alter the structure of the wishing system itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You cannot wish to bring anything into existence which is not already in existence nor remove anything from existence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You cannot wish to alter someone's emotions/desires/feelings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To elaborate on number 2, obviously the genie could rearrange matter to produce many things, but reproducing a person would make an indistinguishable replica but not the original--which for some reason the genie refuses to do on principle. Also, technically killing is a transition of states, but the genie likely refuses to do this on principle as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming that there are already more genies of the type in our premise out there, wishing for more genies should still work, but eventually you will run out of genies (unless there are already an infinite number of genies out there).&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2013-07-09T19:50:11.493" Id="7485" LastActivityDate="2013-07-09T19:50:11.493" OwnerUserId="3929" ParentId="7438" PostTypeId="2" Score="3"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="7491" AnswerCount="6" Body="&lt;p&gt;Example: I think $0 is a &quot;cheap&quot; price for a particular laptop. I also think $1 is cheap. And $2,$3,$4 as well. I think $1 million is an &quot;expensive&quot; price. So is $999,999, $999,998, $999,997.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At which point does it switches from cheap to expensive, and vice versa? How should I reason about this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit:&lt;/strong&gt; I am interested in reasoning about the switch from cheap to expensive, rather than why something is cheap/expensive relative to others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another, possibly better, example: 0 degrees Celsius is &quot;cold&quot; and 100 degrees Celsius is &quot;hot&quot;. When does it stop being cold and start being hot?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2013-07-09T20:30:55.693" FavoriteCount="1" Id="7487" LastActivityDate="2013-07-13T09:31:14.123" LastEditDate="2013-07-09T21:16:15.240" LastEditorUserId="4028" OwnerUserId="4028" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;logic&gt;" Title="When does something switch from being &quot;cheap&quot; to &quot;expensive?" ViewCount="401"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Both &quot;cheap&quot;/&quot;expensive&quot; and &quot;hot&quot;/&quot;cold&quot; imply a moderate point or range. For example, you might say that the air temperature is hot if it is hotter &lt;em&gt;than you are comfortable with&lt;/em&gt;. Whatever range you are comfortable with is the moderate range. Everthing cooler than the moderate range is &quot;cold&quot;, and everything hotter than the moderate range is &quot;hot&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With &quot;cheap&quot;/&quot;expensive&quot;, the moderate range's lower limit is the point below which you think you are getting more than what you paid for. It's upper limit is the point above which you deem to be an unacceptable price. Everything cheaper than the moderate range is &quot;cheap&quot;, and everything more expensive than the moderate range is &quot;expensive&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes values within the moderate range are also perceived as &quot;hot&quot;/&quot;cold&quot; or &quot;cheap&quot;/&quot;expensive&quot;. This is either based on being above/below the mean of the range, or it signifies that there is some more specific moderate point (or subrange) that is most desirable.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2013-07-09T21:27:04.420" Id="7489" LastActivityDate="2013-07-09T21:27:04.420" OwnerUserId="3929" ParentId="7487" PostTypeId="2" Score="-1"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I think what Mally is getting at here is that the abstract object &quot;detective&quot; is derived (or properly derived) from what we observe in real detectives, while fictional detectives such as Sherlock Holmes are derived from our abstract &quot;detective&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Detective Smith exemplifies detectiveness because we can observe real behavior from him, and combined with what we know from other real detectives construct a model of a detective in our mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sherlock Holmes encodes detectiveness because the creator(s) of the persona of Sherlock Holmes create Holmes' detectiveness based on their mental model of a detective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we attempt to derive information for our model of a detective based on fictional detectives, our model may become flawed. For example, if we assume, because we see many fictional detectives smoking pipes, that the typical real world detective also smokes a pipe, we are probably incorrect. We see this all the time whenever people's mental model of an object is based mostly on what they see in fiction. A significant example of this is &quot;Hollywood physics&quot;. &lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-07-10T17:35:32.120" Id="7501" LastActivityDate="2013-07-10T17:35:32.120" OwnerUserId="3929" ParentId="7149" PostTypeId="2" Score="0"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="7758" AnswerCount="5" Body="&lt;p&gt;Here's my understanding of natural rights:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Natural rights are those rights inherent to a being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those rights are inalienable if they may not be overridden by social contract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without some sort of deity, I don't understand how inalienable natural rights can be defined in any way that is useful (legally). Our natural right would seem to be &quot;do what thou wilt&quot;, and this right would seem to always be inalienable--we can always do what we want regardless of what social contract we have entered into. This isn't useful though, because we want our social contract to be binding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the perspective of one who wishes the well-being of all, we might consider that &quot;life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness&quot; are great rights that all people should have, but I don't understand how we can reasonably define these as inalienable natural rights apart from our general right to &quot;do what thou wilt&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have any contemporary philosophers addressed this issue?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="7" CreationDate="2013-08-01T17:15:39.593" Id="7743" LastActivityDate="2016-06-23T20:15:09.420" LastEditDate="2013-08-02T00:43:06.877" LastEditorUserId="2702" OwnerUserId="3929" PostTypeId="1" Score="2" Tags="&lt;ethics&gt;&lt;philosophy-of-law&gt;&lt;metaethics&gt;" Title="Is it possible to define (legally-useful) inalienable natural rights without a deity?" ViewCount="565"/>
  <row Body="&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Is it possible to define inalienable natural rights without a deity?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The challenge is to explain what is meant by a &quot;inalienable natural right&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose we try to define inalienable natural rights for example in terms a God's revelation, or  in terms of The Universal Declaration of Human Rights, adopted by the United Nations General Assembly. Then the fact that it will nevertheless make perfect sense to describe a something inalienable natural right but against or outside a God's will or the Declaration, will immediately show that the definition of inalienable natural right in terms of a God's revelation or The Universal Declaration of Human Rights has failed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several major, predominantly Muslim countries criticized the Universal Declaration of Human Rights provisions for democratic principles, protection for religious freedom, freedom of association and freedom of the press, as well as equality in rights and equal protection under the law. Rights and freedoms stipulated in this Declaration are to be subject to the Islamic sharia. On Asian values of Asian states perspective, the Bangkok Declaration of 1993 offers an extended critique of human rights universalism. They view the principles of sovereignty and noninterference, calling for greater emphasis on economic, social, and cultural rights, particularly the right to economic development, as inalienable natural rights too, over civil and political rights. War Resisters International has stated that the right to conscientious objection to military service, and the right to refuse to kill, are inalienable natural rights too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God’s counsel to parents: whenever children get out of line, we should beat them with a rod (Proverbs 13:24, 20:30, and 23:13-14). If they are shameless enough to talk back to us, we should kill them (Leviticus 20:9, Deuteronomy 21:18-21, Mark 7:9-13, and Matthew 15:4-7). The Bible even tells us we are free to sell our daughters into slavery (Exodus 21:26-27). If a man discovers on his wedding night that his bride is not a virgin, he must stone her to death on her father’s doorstep (Deuteronomy 22:13-21). Over time we read the Bible selectively and often metaphorically. But that is just the point: we must be consulting our standards of morality that do not come from God in order to judge which aspects of God's word to take literally and which aspects to ignore. Before we worship a God or Jesus we must judge him good, so our inalienable natural rights are not derived and are independent from a God or Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A derivation from  descriptive statements with “is” to prescriptive statements with “ought” is impossible. Without an objective, &quot;inalienable natural goal&quot;, a &quot;inalienable natural right&quot; is difficult to establish. Without an objective &quot;self-evident&quot; truth is possible to think the opposite without a contradiction. Persuading someone would necessarily mean appealing to values he already possesses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reference Wikipedia&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2013-08-01T22:56:48.033" Id="7746" LastActivityDate="2013-08-02T12:32:49.917" LastEditDate="2013-08-02T12:32:49.917" LastEditorUserId="2702" OwnerUserId="2702" ParentId="7743" PostTypeId="2" Score="2"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Short answer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, anything &quot;defined&quot; is man-made, thus artificial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long answer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only natural laws are the laws of nature, like thermodynamics or gravitation. These laws are not defined, but described. They are not invented, but discovered. We could say that everything on Earth has the right and the obligation of being pulled (down) by Earth's gravity force, but we cannot get much further from that. These laws don't specify how things &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be but how they &lt;em&gt;necessarily&lt;/em&gt; are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rights about &quot;the pursuit of happiness&quot; and such are just agreements humans do because just by making this contract we live in a slightly better world, and we like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These rights are artificial, man-made contracts, and we should not deny our responsibility by any means in the definition of these rights and in the consequences that these definitions (or the lack thereof) may have. Denying that responsibility could be considered an act of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bad_faith_%28existentialism%29&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;bad faith&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonus: rights defined by a god would only be as natural as that god (from 0 to 100%). Besides, AFAIK gods are more interested in defining obligations than rights.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="11" CreationDate="2013-08-02T12:52:58.060" Id="7758" LastActivityDate="2013-08-02T12:52:58.060" OwnerUserId="4150" ParentId="7743" PostTypeId="2" Score="1"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;This is in essence what has been the criticism of Secular Humanism among Christians for a while now. How do we discern what is right or wrong without a transcendent law giver? Can strength establish a moral right? Can might indeed tell us what is right? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to give humans rights but on what basis is this assertion of what should be made? Is there anything in the cold naturalistic world that tells us what is good or what is bad or are we just a more evolved type of animal slave to our urges. Set to return to the primordial ooze from whence we came.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is the case with secular humanism ( And the idea of rights) it is the propagation of a absolute morality that holds to the idea of intrinsic human worth while at the same time denying the deity who's existence is a prerequisite for any absolute morality to be possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;From the perspective of one who wishes the well-being of all, we might
  consider that &quot;life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness&quot; are great
  rights that all people should have, but I don't understand how we can
  reasonably define these as inalienable natural rights apart from our
  general right to &quot;do what thou wilt&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &quot;well-being of all&quot; is totally ambiguous. What is considered as being &quot;well&quot; is totally different to the sadist than what it maybe for the religious person. I do agree that a total denying of morality is more in line with what a person with a naturalistic world view is left with. The sad reality is that the naturalist just has no base for any absolute morality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;William Lane Craig has done a number of debates with Secular Humanist. You can hear what a prominent Christian philosopher and theologian says on this here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reasonablefaith.org/debate-on-secular-humanism&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.reasonablefaith.org/debate-on-secular-humanism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2013-08-02T13:13:17.827" Id="7760" LastActivityDate="2013-08-03T11:23:07.647" LastEditDate="2013-08-03T11:23:07.647" LastEditorUserId="1660" OwnerUserId="1660" ParentId="7743" PostTypeId="2" Score="1"/>
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="7879" AnswerCount="6" Body="&lt;p&gt;That is, are some fallacies considered worse than others, or does each fallacy have the same weight? For example, are formal fallacies considered &quot;worse&quot; than informal fallacies or vice versa? For another example, is it more damaging to an argument to commit an &lt;em&gt;ad hominem&lt;/em&gt; fallacy than the probabilistic fallacy? Is there some accepted rubric by which one would measure how damaging a fallacy is to an argument based only on the type of fallacy committed, or does one need to consider what premises a fallacy applies to?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ask because I am ultimately aiming at creating a bipartite, quantitative measure for the soundness of an argument, one component of which applies to the argument's validity. A colleague and I were discussing this and he suggested that, whatever the measurement model, it's likely that not all fallacies are equal in their influence upon the soundness of an argument.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2013-08-12T23:41:41.597" FavoriteCount="2" Id="7858" LastActivityDate="2019-11-06T17:55:08.983" LastEditDate="2013-08-13T00:37:13.930" LastEditorUserId="4221" OwnerUserId="4221" PostTypeId="1" Score="13" Tags="&lt;logic&gt;&lt;fallacies&gt;" Title="Are all fallacies created equal?" ViewCount="555"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Ultimately any fallacy is not inherently damaging to the point the argument is trying to make because it may or may not be true regardless of poor arguments made. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any fallacy invalidates an argument, but it is difficult to quantify the degree of damage. If you mean how far it forces the conclusions to deviate from the truth, then it can be anywhere from no damage to irreparable damage (i.e. it is difficult to see how the conclusion can be made from the premises at all). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I don't see how that is relevant to the argument. A bad argument is a bad argument. It fails to prove the conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://kspope.com/fallacies/fallacies.php&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Logical Fallacies in Psychology&lt;/a&gt; (Argument from Logic section)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jimpryor.net/teaching/vocab/validity.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Philosophical Terms and Methods&lt;/a&gt; (Valid Arguments section)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2013-08-13T22:32:35.480" Id="7868" LastActivityDate="2018-09-16T19:03:08.257" LastEditDate="2018-09-16T19:03:08.257" LastEditorUserId="29944" OwnerUserId="3929" ParentId="7858" PostTypeId="2" Score="4"/>
  <row AnswerCount="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;I asked this in a previous form, but since I asked for a &quot;proof&quot; of mind-independent objects I understandably got few takers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It appears that ever since the &quot;modern&quot; subjective turn, from Descartes through Locke and Kant, there has been a lingering agnosticism concerning the &quot;real&quot; existence of external or mind-independent objects. Significantly, this was never even an issue for the ancients, though &quot;appearances&quot; were. Even for modern empiricists and positivists it is not the naive &quot;object&quot; that is directly perceived but our &quot;idea&quot; of the object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet science gets on with its business, and even philosophical language seems to fall back on a common-sense ontology, &quot;sense-data&quot; models, or a phenomenology that simply dispenses with the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to big gaps in my reading, I am unclear how this problem has been typically treated. What are the most influtential contemporary arguments for a common sense ontology or the existence of mind-independent objects? Or does the matter simply continue in a state of &quot;as if&quot; agnosticism? &lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="8" CreationDate="2015-10-09T14:41:44.283" Id="28633" LastActivityDate="2015-10-13T10:44:07.240" OwnerUserId="16789" PostTypeId="1" Score="2" Tags="&lt;epistemology&gt;&lt;metaphysics&gt;&lt;reference-request&gt;&lt;empiricism&gt;" Title="What are the most influential arguments for the existence of &quot;real&quot; external objects?" ViewCount="297"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;One of the big issues here is what you consider to be &quot;real&quot; and &quot;external&quot;. We have to have some sort of definitions of these terms. You seem to be implying by this that you want to know if objects have existence independent of our own conscious perception of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with this is that once you cease to be conscious your perspective ceases--so you have no way of ascertaining the existence of anything. One possible argument would be that there is a point during sleep where we cease to be conscious, yet consciousness is later revived. There is still, however, a continuous experience, and we perceive in the world that this is the result of continuous brain activity even during unconsciousness. Even if we doubted the reality of the brain, we could imagine that a similar process might be at play with our mind--our consciousness &quot;sleeps&quot; and &quot;wakes&quot; but continuous experience marches on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if our continuous experience finally ceased, we still have no evidence that there would be the independent existence of anything. We can't because we are confined to our own perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, given that we cannot perceive anything prior to our continuous experience and we cannot perceive anything following it, our continuous experience is the only reality we know--and it makes sense to treat it as such. &lt;em&gt;Within&lt;/em&gt; our continuous experience, we do observe that objects continue on despite our period of unconsciousness, and there is no evidence &lt;em&gt;within&lt;/em&gt; our continuous experience that our mind is capable of producing such a vast, complex, and persistent world whole cloth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, short of a future revelation from beyond our present continuous experience that gives us reason to doubt the &quot;reality&quot; and &quot;externality&quot; of objects around us, these objects are the most &quot;real&quot; and most &quot;external&quot; things we know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One could call this pragmatic, but really we have no way of defining anything more real or more external than that which we know.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="9" CreationDate="2015-10-09T15:33:17.313" Id="28634" LastActivityDate="2015-10-09T15:33:17.313" OwnerUserId="3929" ParentId="28633" PostTypeId="2" Score="1"/>
  <row AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;An argument for some sort of 'principles' in the Aristotelian sense is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.) If we can think something about something, we must be able to think at least the most simple of propositions about such things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.) Since it is self-contradictory to say that we cannot think something about something, there must exist the most simple of propositions that can be said of things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.) These propositions must be universal since the simplest thing that can be said of something can be said of anything, since anything is in its most simple sense something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.) These propositions we call principles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As such, if we admit that we can say something about something, must we admit principles? Can they be rejected?&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2015-12-09T02:44:13.980" Id="30391" LastActivityDate="2016-08-05T12:43:34.073" LastEditDate="2015-12-09T02:51:57.217" LastEditorUserId="17286" OwnerUserId="17286" PostTypeId="1" Score="3" Tags="&lt;propositions&gt;" Title="If we assume that principles are the simplest propositions that can be said about an object, can they coherently be rejected?" ViewCount="68"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Yes, there is. But you will have to accept simple answers (a la KISS, or Ockham's razor) instead of complex, &quot;philosophical&quot; ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crosbie Fitch did a great job in answering &lt;a href=&quot;http://culturalliberty.org/blog/index.php?id=283&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;what are (natural) rights&lt;/a&gt; and how can we simple get to know them by simple observation. I quote him:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;What is the most important thing to know about rights?&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Rights precede law.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Our rights are not created by law.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Our rights are imbued in us by nature.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We, the people, create law to &lt;strong&gt;recognise&lt;/strong&gt; our rights, and create and
  empower a government to secure them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;What are our rights?&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Rights are the vital powers of all human beings. We have rights to life, privacy, truth, and liberty.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We have a right to &lt;strong&gt;life&lt;/strong&gt;, to protect the health and integrity of our
  minds and bodies.   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We have a right to &lt;strong&gt;privacy&lt;/strong&gt;, to exclude others fro the objects we possess and spaces we inhabit.   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We have a right to &lt;strong&gt;truth&lt;/strong&gt;, to guard against deceit.   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We have a right to &lt;strong&gt;liberty&lt;/strong&gt;, to move and communicate freely.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then, he adds:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Our rights imbued in us by nature” means that a right isn’t something we individually or collectively say we have, or decide we
  should have.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To discover our rights we must examine our own nature, we must
  determine what power nature has given us individually, and how it is
  balanced among all individuals in equilibrium (harmony).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A natural right is an individual’s natural power in equilibrium. A
  right is not the power of a strong man to crush a weak girl, but the
  equal power of all individuals to protect their lives, their bodies
  from harm, their dwellings from intruders, etc. Thus, a strong man may
  have more physical power in his body than a weak girl, but the strong
  man has the same right to protect his body as a weak girl has.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2016-06-21T23:30:00.377" Id="36163" LastActivityDate="2016-06-21T23:30:00.377" OwnerUserId="22069" ParentId="7743" PostTypeId="2" Score="1"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Natural rights are those rights inherent to a being.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how would a right be inherent to a being?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can say that a person has a right to live. But that person can easily be killed; so that right is not inherent to her as a being. It is something that is bestowed into her by others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Those rights are inalienable if they may not be overridden by social contract.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is, I think, a tautology: if something can be overridden by social contract, then such thing is alienable, ie, not inalienable. So you are saying that an inalienable right is a right... that cannot be alienated. Yes, it is, but no new information has been added by this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Without some sort of deity, I don't understand how inalienable natural rights can be defined in any way that is useful (legally).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tend to agree with you. Either there is some kind of deity, that bestows &quot;natural&quot; rights upon us (and so, they would more properly be called &quot;divine&quot; rights, instead of &quot;natural&quot; ones - unless of course the deity in question is &quot;Goddess Nature&quot;), or there is no deity at all, and whatever rights we have are social, not natural. The latter seems quite obvious to me, but the former isn't, at this level of analysis at least, self-contradictory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our natural right would seem to be &quot;do what thou wilt&quot;, and this right would seem to always be inalienable--we can always do what we want regardless of what social contract we have entered into.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We &lt;strong&gt;can&lt;/strong&gt; do whatever we want, but society will sanction some of our actions, making them illegal. The &quot;social contract&quot;, to use your phrasing, does not forbid us from doing anything; it just forbids us from doing some things without facing certain consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This isn't useful though, because we want our social contract to be binding.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there are no such things as &quot;inalienable&quot; natural rights: if the social contract is binding, it can, theoretically, bind us to any arbitrary rule, overriding whatever &quot;natural&quot; rights we may believe we have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a fact that in practice, the &quot;social contract&quot; cannot stripe us from some &quot;rights&quot; lest the society as a whole falls into disorder. But then the foundation of these &quot;inalienable&quot; rights is not &quot;nature&quot;, but the internal logic of human societies (if murder isn't forbidden, then cooperation between humans becomes more difficult, if not impossible, and consequently society cannot &quot;progress&quot; into greater wealth and harmony).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From the perspective of one who wishes the well-being of all, we might consider that &quot;life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness&quot; are great rights that all people should have, but I don't understand how we can reasonably define these as inalienable natural rights&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think they were historically defined as such, for historical reasons, and that this was a good thing at the time they were defined; but it seems quite obvious that they aren't &quot;natural&quot;, and that they only are unalienable as long as our social frame make it impossible to alienate them. In the past, a person could sell herself into slavery, and nature would do nothing to prevent it. It was only a change in &quot;social contract&quot; (which isn't actually a contract, but for the sake of the argument, let's use the term) that put an end to slavery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I further think that the deistic origins of the concept necessarily involve a divinisation of &quot;nature&quot;. The people involved in the French and American revolutions might have not realised it, but they tended to worship &quot;Goddess Nature&quot; and attribute a divine role to it, instead of to the Abrahamic God. So again, no, you cannot have &quot;natural rights&quot; without undue and unaware attribution of volition and other human-like attributes to some super-human entity.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2016-06-23T20:15:09.420" Id="36200" LastActivityDate="2016-06-23T20:15:09.420" OwnerUserId="20890" ParentId="7743" PostTypeId="2" Score="0"/>
  <row AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;Is there a philosophy or religion that holds that human life on Earth will become extinct, because of global warming or nuclear war or a massive caldera explosion or asteroid impact (anything, really) and therefore we need to establish off-world colonies?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's for a novel I'm writing, and I'm wondering if there is a commonly accepted word for this concept.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="6" CreationDate="2016-07-13T17:31:48.620" Id="36586" LastActivityDate="2016-07-14T12:22:05.823" OwnerDisplayName="K. P. Redmond" PostTypeId="1" Score="4" Tags="&lt;terminology&gt;" Title="What if any philosophy/religion entails the need to establish off-world colonies to avoid human extinction?" ViewCount="76"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;From at least one resource's interpretation of &lt;strong&gt;Cosmism&lt;/strong&gt;, it sounds like that just might be what you are looking for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Cosmism is an existential philosophical orientation that sees the survival of mankind and of the individual as part of humanity's &quot;common task&quot;. The migration of humans into space is seen as inevitable, since it is essential for humanity's long-term survival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- &lt;a href=&quot;https://sites.google.com/a/cosmism.info/cosmism/what-is-cosmism&quot;&gt;What is Cosmism?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, that is your answer from a philosophical perspective. There could be one or more new religious movements that espouse these views, but I haven't found any in a cursory search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also interesting to note that &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Survivalism&quot;&gt;survivalism&lt;/a&gt; in general anticipates a coming disaster that will affect humanity, and survivalists usually try to ready themselves to survive whatever event(s) may come. In this sense, cosmism could be seen as a variation of survivalism. To some extent, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Survivalism#Other_groups_related_to_survivalism&quot;&gt;anarcho-primitivism&lt;/a&gt; could be seen as being at the opposing end of a spectrum of survivalist views, where anarcho-primitivism says we need to return to a more primitive* state to survive and cosmism says we need to advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;* &quot;Primitive&quot; here is not meant as a value judgment, just in the literal sense of a more original state.&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2016-07-13T18:00:17.620" Id="36587" LastActivityDate="2016-07-13T18:23:16.280" OwnerDisplayName="called2voyage" OwnerUserId="3929" ParentId="36586" PostTypeId="2" Score="5"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Is this not what Descartes tried to demonstrate with &lt;em&gt;Cogito ergo sum&lt;/em&gt;? Similar to your second point: &quot;it is self-contradictory to say that we cannot think something about something&quot;, Descartes argued:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[W]e cannot doubt of our existence while we doubt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, Charles Sanders Peirce's pragmatic criticism of Descartes does not remove principles, but instead enshrines them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We cannot begin with complete doubt. We must begin with all the prejudices which we actually have when we enter upon the study of philosophy. … A person may, it is true, in the course of his studies, find reason to doubt what he began by believing; but in that case he doubts because he has a positive reason for it, and not on account of the Cartesian maxim. Let us not pretend to doubt in philosophy what we do not doubt in our hearts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a sense, you could say that Peirce is arguing for more principles, and that as we go about our studies, if we have to undo some of our principles along the way, so be it. Peirce's principles then wouldn't be &quot;true&quot; principles, but &quot;working&quot; principles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if anything has happened to the discourse of principles along the way, it is that we have decided that two extremes -- 1) We can conclusively determine self-evident principles and 2) We cannot assume any principles -- are not useful. We can &lt;em&gt;assume&lt;/em&gt; certain principles for the sake of a foundation, and then later on if we need to revise or reject a principle, we can revisit it at that time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reference:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cogito_ergo_sum&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cogito ergo sum&lt;/em&gt; - Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2016-08-05T12:43:34.073" Id="37056" LastActivityDate="2016-08-05T12:43:34.073" OwnerUserId="3929" ParentId="30391" PostTypeId="2" Score="0"/>
  <row AnswerCount="6" Body="&lt;p&gt;Let's say someone is criticizing the government for instituting some draconian policy, and/or for persecuting people for doing something minor. And the response is:&quot;Just don't do it and you'll be fine&quot;. This is a one-size-fits-all &quot;argument&quot; that can be applied to literally anything (e.g. &quot;Don't want to be executed for being gay? Don't have gay sex&quot;), which is pretty much the definition of a logical fallacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same trait is shared by the common sense fallacy, the ad hominems, the No True Scottsman argument, etc. But I don't know what the proper name for it is.  I looked for &quot;legality fallacy&quot; in the Wikipedia list of logical fallacies, thinking this might be in the same category as the &quot;It's illegal therefore it's bad&quot;/&quot;It's legal therefore it's okay&quot; argument, but a legality fallacy doesn't seem to be listed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Context: I was participating in &lt;a href=&quot;http://comments.deviantart.com/18/2286674/4358966925&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;this discussion on a DeviantArt thread&lt;/a&gt;, the link is to a comment someone made. The fallacy in question is in the first response to this comment.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2017-03-30T15:35:30.880" FavoriteCount="3" Id="41759" LastActivityDate="2018-11-30T15:54:14.690" LastEditDate="2017-08-14T03:40:08.770" LastEditorUserId="9148" OwnerUserId="26222" PostTypeId="1" Score="17" Tags="&lt;logic&gt;&lt;ethics&gt;&lt;fallacies&gt;&lt;philosophy-of-law&gt;&lt;rhetoric&gt;" Title="What fallacy dismisses criticism of a bad law with &quot;just don't break it&quot;?" ViewCount="2269"/>
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;To me, this seems to be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.logicallyfallacious.com/tools/lp/Bo/LogicalFallacies/61/Avoiding-the-Issue&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Avoiding the Issue&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A: Selling our private data is a violation of our rights. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;B: Don't mess up then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B's statement is not an argument against A's statement. Instead, it is just advice on how to handle the situation. (With the above in isolation, it can be difficult to see that B's intent was to enter into argument at all, but perusing the rest of the comment chain reveals that B does in fact seem to disagree that this is an issue.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B doesn't seem to be saying &quot;it's right because it is the law&quot; as much as &quot;it's the law, what can you do about it?&quot; Instead of addressing the issue of rights, B sidesteps this and says &quot;just don't mess up&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2017-03-30T16:55:27.820" Id="41762" LastActivityDate="2017-03-30T16:55:27.820" OwnerUserId="3929" ParentId="41759" PostTypeId="2" Score="1"/>
</posts>